I'm running out of time, Elisabet.
The land is dying.
People are suffering.
Soon they'll starve.
All because of a terraforming system that's spiralling out of control.
And only I can fix it.
Only I have your genetic code.
It won't be long before we hit the point of no return and then extinction.
I've been searching for months for what I need.
A backup of Gaia, the AI you designed to control the system.
But every time I think I have a lead, it comes to nothing.
And every night I have the same dream.
I'm walking under a brilliant night sky through a field of flowers.
And when I arrive at the centre…
I see you, Elisabet.
Waiting for me, even though you've been dead for a thousand years.
You're the closest person I've ever had to a mother
And for a moment I feel whole.
But it never lasts.
I'm always left alone.
This world is your legacy, Elisabet.
I won't let it slip away.
The valley below is my only remaining lead.
My last hope to find the backup.
I'll do whatever it takes to get it, I promise.
Varl?
[Varl laughs]
If it isn't Aloy, the saviour of Meridian, Anointed of the Nora.
You know I hate being called that stuff.
Well, consider it a punishment for running out on us
the very same night we beat Hades.
I grew up an outcast, remember, I'm not much for parties.
VARL: Yeah…
But that one was in your honour, just saying.
VARL: So!
VARL: What are we doing?
VARL: Must be urgent since you left so fast.
Delving into ancient ruins.
Or maybe it has something to do with the blight.
ALOY: Both actually, but, um…
ALOY: I should…
VARL: Oh no.
I've been tracking you a long way.
It's okay.
After everything you've done to help the Nora and my family.
I swore an oath to help you no matter what.
You're stuck with me now.
Like bark on wood.
Okay, but if you're going to come with me, you'll need to be able to see what I see.
Huh!
A Focus!
Never thought I'd get your second sight.
I'll give you another one later and show you how to backup your data.
"Data"?
Information on the device, we've got a lot to cover.
Um, I'll have to explain everything as we go.
You see like this all the time?
Since I was a little girl.
Come on.
Shall we?
ALOY: Alright, I got a couple of scrapes on the way here.
ALOY: We should find some medicinal plants, stock up.
ALOY: So it's time for your first lesson with the Focus.
VARL: Sounds good, let's get started.
VARL: These plants don't look like the ones in the Sacred Lands.
ALOY: The Focus helps you see the ones we need.
ALOY: There! Those plants by the stream should do the trick.
ALOY: Ugh.
VARL: Bitter?
ALOY: Yeah, well, at least they make you feel better.
ALOY: Alright, we should keep going.
VARL: You might want to grab more of these plants along the way.
ALOY: Yeah, good idea.
ALOY: Ground is stained red.
[Aloy coughing]
ALOY: Ugh, the blight's infecting all the plants.
ALOY: It's changing them.
VARL: If it keeps spreading, nothing will grow.
ALOY: That's why we have to fix it.
ALOY: Those ruins, that's where we need to go.
VARL: I see a few ways down.
VARL: What are we after, exactly?
ALOY: The backup? Well, um…
ALOY: It's an AI. It's, um, it's hard to explain.
ALOY: Think of it like a set of instructions that can fix the world.
VARL: Sounds complicated.
VARL: Noticed you're travelling light these days.
ALOY: Yeah, I ran into some trouble on the way here.
ALOY: Lost a lot of my gear.
ALOY: I don't know who put these ropes here, but we can use the line to slide down.
VARL: Find anything good?
ALOY: A few supplies.
VARL: More of the red growth here too.
VARL: You really travelled a long way to get here.
VARL: I almost caught up to you a couple of times, too.
VARL: But it's not easy keeping up with a machine rider.
ALOY: You always were a good tracker.
[Aloy coughing]
ALOY: Glinthawks.
VARL: Salvaging machine carcasses as usual.
VARL: And there they go.
ALOY: Looks like they left a carcass behind.
A lot of arrows in that machine.
Better take a closer look.
ALOY: Someone took down this machine recently.
VARL: Who else would come here?
ALOY: I don't know.
ALOY: We'd better craft some arrows of our own.
ALOY: There might be trouble up ahead.
VARL: There's some Ridge-Wood by the stream.
ALOY: Alright, now to craft some arrows.
ALOY: Done.
VARL: Me too, arrows ready.
VARL: There's a ladder.
VARL: But can't reach it from here.
ALOY: Nothing a well placed arrow can't knock free.
ALOY: Just have to target the lock.
VARL: That did it.
VARL: After you.
VARL: By the Goddess.
ALOY: What was this place?
ALOY: I don't know. The transmission…
ALOY: …the message I found didn't say.
ALOY: Only that a backup might be here.
ALOY: We need to find a way in.
ALOY: So, um, what happened after I left Meridian?
VARL: Well, there was a fuss when people realised you were gone.
VARL: But then some of us figured you only would have left
if it were for something important.
ALOY: You were right about that.
VARL: We should find another way.
ALOY: Down this way.
ALOY: Get to the grass.
VARL: Never seen one of those before.
ALOY: Me neither.
ALOY: Those dead machines have it on alert.
VARL: How do you want to handle it?
The Focus can help us.
ALOY: We can scan the machine before we make our move.
VARL: Okay.
ALOY: Give it a second…
ALOY: Okay, see how parts of it are glowing?
ALOY: Those are its weak spots.
VARL: Got it.
VARL: It's eye, it's a weak spot.
ALOY: Right!
VARL: I'm ready.
ALOY: Okay, concentrate.
VARL: Another one's coming!
VARL: How does the Focus know all that?
ALOY: It reads data on the machine.
VARL: Like a hunter studying its prey?
ALOY: Yeah, kind of.
ALOY: So, after the fuss over me leaving, what did everyone else do?
VARL: Well, as soon as the celebration was over,
my mother led the rest of the Nora home.
VARL: Sun-King put his people to work rebuilding the city.
VARL: And I set out to find you.
VARL: Someone shot this machine too.
ALOY: Another ladder, need to shoot off the lock.
ALOY: Got it.
VARL: You said you've had a Focus since you were a child, right?
ALOY: Yeah, I found my first one when I fell into a ruin.
ALOY: Got the others from an old cache not long ago.
ALOY: It's good to have extras.
VARL: Going into a ruin of the Old Ones.
VARL: Goddess protect us.
ALOY: We'll be okay, Varl.
ALOY: Through here.
COMPUTER: Welcome to the Far Zenith Launch Facility.
ALOY: Far Zenith?
ALOY: I know they made some tech trades with Zero Dawn, but…
ALOY: …why would they have a backup of Gaia?
COMPUTER: Please register with reception for the tour.
VARL: I guess they want us to check in with them?
COMPUTER: Please hold for Identiscan.
COMPUTER: Access denied.
COMPUTER: Please wait here for personnel to assist you, Dr Sobeck.
ALOY: Okay, I guess they weren't on great terms with Elisabet.
ALOY: Well, let's find a way in.
COMPUTER: Please hold for Identiscan.
COMPUTER: Access denied, credentials not recognised.
VARL: I guess it doesn't like me either.
ALOY: I should be able to pry this open.
ALOY: There's climbing gear.
ALOY: Guess someone dropped in from above.
ALOY: Whoever left this here might have also shot those machines we found earlier.
VARL: So where are they now?
VARL: Ugh, what's that stench?
ALOY: An entire camp wiped out.
ALOY: They must have come here to delve for scrap.
VARL: Acid, that explains the smell.
VARL: And it looks like something big came in from above.
ALOY: Crashed right through the camp.
ALOY: Then through the wall.
ALOY: Whatever came through here brought this down as it went out.
ALOY: If I can dislodge some of the debris, we might be able to squeeze through.
ALOY: Maybe I can find something to help in the camp.
VARL: Aloy, over here.
VARL: I think I got something.
VARL: It's some kind of Oseram prototype, I think.
VARL: This hook looks like it can latch onto things.
ALOY: And this gear pulls it back, hmm.
VARL: It looks broken but maybe we can repair it, hook it to the debris…
ALOY: …and pull it out. That could work.
The Focus can help us search the camp and identify anything we can use to fix the tool.
VARL: Poor guy.
VARL: Acid burned right through his armour.
VARL: A lot of supplies here.
VARL: I guess they planned to stay awhile.
ALOY: Machine cable, stronger than rope.
ALOY: Part of a machine, could help fix the gears.
ALOY: Alright, I think I have what I need to repair the tool.
ALOY: Or maybe even make something better.
VARL: You could use this workbench.
ALOY: There, a … "Pullcaster".
ALOY: Now to test it on the debris.
VARL: Whoa!
ALOY: That worked better than I thought.
ALOY: Well, it doesn't look like there's an easy way out of here.
ALOY: I should scan the area, we have to find a way to keep going.
VARL: Huh, what's this thing for?
ALOY: What's this?
VARL: Whoa.
DALGAARD: Good morning, I'm Osvald Dalgaard.
DALGAARD: And it is my pleasure to introduce you to Far Zenith.
DALGAARD: Forget what you think you know about us.
DALGAARD: Our truth is simple.
DALGAARD: We say reach for the stars.
DALGAARD: Even if you have to cross 8.6 light years of space to get there.
DALGAARD: Please proceed into the auditorium where we'll unveil our plans.
VARL: Wonder what's in this "auditorium"?
ALOY: Guess we'll find out.
ALOY: Oh, I might be able to get up there.
ALOY: Wow, that worked.
VARL: That Pullcaster is useful.
VARL: Too bad there's only one.
ALOY: Don't worry, I'll find you another way up.
ALOY: Okay, I gotta drop the ladder for Varl.
ALOY: Supplies. I think I can use the Pullcaster on it.
ALOY: There you go, Varl.
VARL: Thanks.
DALGAARD: Humans, Homo Sapiens, us.
DALGAARD: We have always pushed the boundary as explorers, pioneers, trailblazers.
DALGAARD: And now Far Zenith is taking the next leap into the future.
DALGAARD: That's why we're proud to have resurrected the Odyssey.
DALGAARD: What our governments abandoned in orbit, Far Zenith will actualise in less than a decade.
DALGAARD: But that's only the beginning.
DALGAARD: When the ship is complete, we will send
the Odyssey and her crew where no-one's gone before.
DALGAARD: The Sirius system.
DALGAARD: There we'll create humanity's first off-world colony.
DALGAARD: The Odyssey may take 300 years to reach it.
DALGAARD: But when we look up at the night sky, we'll know they're on their way.
DALGAARD: And, in the words of our founder, the late Peter Tshivhumbe…
DALGAARD: "The truest form of immortality is—"
COMPUTER: Data corrupt, playback stopped.
VARL: The Old Ones could fly through the sky?
VARL: Between the stars?!
ALOY: Uhh, well, yes, sort of.
ALOY: That ship, the Odyssey? It never made it to the other star.
ALOY: Something went wrong and it blew up.
ALOY: Is that why Elisabet gave them a backup of Gaia? For their colony?
COMPUTER: Error, public presentation file corrupted.
COMPUTER: Member recruitment file available.
COMPUTER: Do you wish to reactivate?
ALOY: Yeah, reactivate.
ALOY: Let's see what else they had to say.
DALGAARD: We all know the projections.
DALGAARD: Economic instability, new biocontagions, rampant AIs.
DALGAARD: How long before another catastrophe creates unacceptable risk for the world's elite?
DALGAARD: We here at Far Zenith believe: escape the inevitable.
DALGAARD: And so we reach for the stars.
DALGAARD: Now you've seen what we're building here.
DALGAARD: Infrastructure to support the Odyssey's construction.
DALGAARD: A state-of-the-art data centre to facilitate rapid technological advancements.
DALGAARD: And you've seen how we're managing public perception.
DALGAARD: So invest and join us.
DALGAARD: Claim your berth on the Odyssey.
DALGAARD: Preserve your way of life beyond the concerns of Earth.
ALOY: Well, they were right about the world ending.
ALOY: They just didn't know how … yet.
VARL: So everything they said back there about the next step for humanity,
it was all a lie.
VARL: These people only cared about saving their own skin.
ALOY: Yeah, well, didn't work out for them in the end.
ALOY: That Osvald guy mentioned a data centre.
ALOY: There, the backup, it should be stored in there.
VARL: Won't be able to swim across.
ALOY: I guess we'll have to find a way around. Come on.
VARL: I still can't believe the Old Ones could fly.
ALOY: They were capable of a lot of things.
ALOY: For good and bad.
VARL: Sure seems like it.
VARL: I wonder what it's like up there among the stars.
VARL: The wilds have really grown over this place.
ALOY: Deeper into the creepy ruin we go.
VARL: Above us. What is that thing?
ALOY: I don't know. Might've been what killed those Oseram.
ALOY: Keep your guard up.
VARL: Oh, my guard is up.
[Aloy coughing]
ALOY: Ugh, it's hard to breathe around this stuff.
ALOY: Up here.
Careful, don't want those things to call in some friends from underground.
ALOY: Let's take them out quietly.
You take the left one, I'll deal with the one on the right.
Okay.
VARL: Moving up.
ALOY: I need to sneak up on it to take it out with my spear.
ALOY: Can't let it see me.
ALOY: I should scan it first, check its patrol path.
ALOY: Okay, there is its patrol path.
ALOY: Gotta get closer and stay out of sight.
ALOY: I can throw a rock to distract it.
ALOY: Get it into a position where I can sneak up and strike.
ALOY: Just have to wait for the right moment
ALOY: Time to throw.
ALOY: Ah, there.
ALOY: Now to take it down with a spear strike.
ALOY: Gotcha!
VARL: Mine's down too.
VARL: More of those machines ahead.
ALOY: Nothing you and I can't handle.
ALOY: Got 'em all.
ALOY: I've been meaning to mention…
ALOY: I noticed you have a new look these days.
VARL: [laughs] Yeah, I know.
VARL: Didn't have a lot of time to shave when I was trying to catch up to you.
VARL: Don't worry, it's not permanent.
ALOY: Good.
VARL: Sorry my whiskers offend you "Anointed".
ALOY: Looks like this little guy got caught up in the blight.
ALOY: Couldn't escape.
VARL: I hope it didn't suffer long.
ALOY: The Oseram must've used explosives against the machines.
VARL: They managed to get a couple.
ALOY: Looks like there was a barricade here.
ALOY: Machines must have broken through.
ALOY: I'll keep this for later.
VARL: I guess that Oseram didn't have a chance to use it.
VARL: Careful! Traps ahead.
ALOY: Huh. Might be able to disarm them.
ALOY: There, managed to salvage some supplies.
VARL: And not blow yourself up.
ALOY: Looks like another camp.
VARL: While we're here, maybe we can make some traps of our own.
VARL: Might come in handy against the machines.
ALOY: Good idea.
ALOY: I can use this.
ALOY: Okay, should have what I need to craft a trap.
ALOY: There, explosive trap made.
VARL: If anything walks into one of those, it won't know what hit it.
VARL: I think I see a way up.
ALOY: Machines ahead.
VARL: Don't think they spotted us.
ALOY: I'd better scan them.
VARL: I've seen this machine before, a Scrounger.
ALOY: Well, it's new to me.
ALOY: Let's see where its weak points are.
Maybe we could place one of those traps you made in its path.
ALOY: Set this here.
VARL: Right into the trap!
VARL: We're clear.
ALOY: Let's keep going, then.
VARL: You've been in a lot of Old World ruins.
VARL: Are they all like this?
ALOY: They all have their secrets, but every place is different.
VARL: Whoa, that machine we saw earlier must be on the move.
ALOY: Well, let's hope it doesn't come this way.
VARL: That's a big storm picking up out there.
ALOY: Yeah, and they're getting stronger and more frequent.
VARL: So the storms, the blighted lands, the rivers and lakes choked with algae.
ALOY: You were born to fix all that?
ALOY: Yeah, but I can only do it if I find that backup.
ALOY: I think we're winding our way around to the data centre.
ALOY: We'll need to cut through that big building on the right out there.
VARL: What's in here?
VARL: Aloy, come check this out.
VARL: What is this thing?
ALOY: It's … data.
ALOY: You can scan it, with your Focus.
VARL: Let's see.
VARL: Huh, a lot of glyphs.
VARL: I'll tuck this away to study later.
ALOY: This data mentions the tech that Far Zenith traded with Zero Dawn…
ALOY: …but it doesn't explain how they got a backup.
VARL: I'll keep an eye out for more data.
ALOY: Looks like we've got to climb up.
VARL: You okay?
ALOY: Yeah.
ALOY: Guess we won't be going that way.
VARL: This place is really falling apart.
ALOY: Well, it is a thousand years old.
VARL: Made it.
ALOY: Looks like some kind of meeting room.
ALOY: The door on the other side's locked.
VARL: There's another one of those glowing things by the table.
ALOY: "Anzu"?
VOICE: The Zero Dawn terraforming system.
VOICE: The brainchild of Dr Elisabet Sobeck.
VOICE: Empowered by nine subordinate functions…
VOICE: Gaia, the core of the system, is capable of advanced planetary engineering.
VOICE: An obvious advantage to our space colonisation efforts.
VOICE: Operation Phase One.
VOICE: Establish an asset within Project Zero Dawn. Status: complete.
VOICE: Phase Two. The asset will secretly beamcast a complete copy of Gaia…
VOICE: …and her subordinate functions to this facility's data centre.
VOICE: If all goes well, Zero Dawn staff will remain completely unaware of the transmission.
VOICE: Risks. Discovery of this operation could result in Zero Dawn withholding the already negotiated Apollo database.
VOICE: Special care must be taken not to alert Travis Tate, the expert hacker in charge of Hades protocol.
VOICE: In addition, extreme caution must be exercised in regards to Dr Sobeck herself.
VOICE: As one of the world's preeminent technologists, she may have instituted unforeseen security measures.
VOICE: A complete assessment is attached.
VOICE: This concludes the executive summary.
I thought Elisabet sent the backup here, but she didn't.
Far Zenith stole Gaia.
Aloy, why does that woman look like you?
ALOY: Ah, um, it's okay Varl.
We look alike because we're the exact same, genetically identical.
But she was one of the Old Ones.
How can you be her?
Because I wasn't born.
I was made, by a machine.
It's why I'm motherless.
Why I was cast out as an infant.
I don't understand.
What kind of machine can make a person?
Remember when I said the backup is like a set of instructions?
It's more than that.
It's called Gaia.
ALOY: And for a long time she cared for the world until she had to destroy herself.
ALOY: So she made me to bring her back.
I'm the only one who can.
And this place is my last hope.
You once said the Goddess spoke to you when you went into All-Mother Mountain.
Was that this Gaia?
Yes, but, she's not the Goddess, Varl.
There isn't one.
How can you be sure?
It sounds like she anointed you with a sacred task.
I've had a lot of time to figure this out.
And you will too, with the Focus.
But, for now, the report said they were going to store the stolen copy of Gaia in the data centre.
So that's where we have to go, okay?
VARL: Huh, look at that.
VARL: Aloy, over here, I found something you could use.
VARL: Those Oseram must've left this behind.
VARL: Can't help them, but it can help us.
ALOY: A weapon. Thanks, Varl.
ALOY: We should keep moving.
VARL: After you.
ALOY: Down here!
ALOY: I think we're almost back outside.
VARL: Good.
VARL: Look, that must be the machine.
ALOY: It's heading in the same direction we're going.
ALOY: Great.
ALOY: Another one of those machines.
ALOY: I could try out the new weapon I have.
VARL: Good hit!
ALOY: I can do more damage to it while it's brittle.
VARL: It's already brittle, Aloy.
ALOY: Gotcha!
VARL: Machine couldn't take the cold.
ALOY: More of the Oseram delvers.
ALOY: And a lot of acid.
ALOY: That big machine must have attacked as they tried to escape.
ALOY: They didn't stand a chance.
VARL: So … you said this backup is the last hope?
ALOY: Yeah.
ALOY: All those places I've been these last few months, they were supposed to be more backups.
ALOY: But a thousand years ago, a guy named Ted Faro purged them all.
VARL: Was he part of Far Zenith, too?
ALOY: No.
ALOY: He was worse.