VOICE: Operation Phase One.
VOICE: Establish an asset within Project Zero Dawn. Status: complete.
VOICE: Phase Two. The asset will secretly beamcast
a complete copy of Gaia…
VOICE: …and her subordinate functions to this facility's data centre.
VOICE: If all goes well, Zero Dawn staff will remain
completely unaware of the transmission.
I thought Elisabet sent the backup here, but she didn't.
Far Zenith stole Gaia.
VARL: So … you said this backup is the last hope?
ALOY: Yeah.
ALOY: All those places I've been these last few months,
they were supposed to be more backups.
ALOY: But a thousand years ago, a guy named Ted Faro purged them all.
VARL: Was he part of Far Zenith, too?
ALOY: No, he was worse.
ALOY: Looks like we can cross over here.
VARL: Wow.
VARL: That big metal thing looks like the ship
we saw back in the auditorium.
VARL: Imagine going up to the stars in that!
ALOY: More Oseram.
ALOY: Machines tore right through them.
VARL: These guys couldn't catch a break.
VARL: Machines patrolling ahead.
ALOY: We can tag them in the Focus to keep track of them.
ALOY: Sneaky one.
ALOY: Okay, now how to get out of here?
VARL: Machine ripped right through the wall.
VARL: There's a ladder in the back.
ALOY: So tell me something.
ALOY: Sona was really okay with you
not going back to the Sacred Lands?
VARL: As the Nora War-Chief she understood
why I was obligated to follow you.
VARL: But as my mother, she wasn't pleased.
ALOY: Is she ever pleased? I don't think I've seen her smile.
VARL: Me neither.
VARL: Three of those things?!
VARL: If they slaughtered all those Oseram,
we'll never get through to the data centre.
There's no way to slip past them.
They're too tough to fight head on.
We could find a settlement, convince some hunters to help us.
That would take weeks, and we don't have that kind of time.
ALOY: Maybe all we need is that shuttle to fall.
VARL: That thing? How?
ALOY: We'll figure it out. Just wait here.
VARL: Aloy!
ALOY: Trust me.
ALOY: Just need to get over to the shuttle to figure out
how to make it fall into the basin.
And there she goes.
If I can make it to that tower,
I should be able to find a way across to the shuttle.
Maybe I should stick to my spear for now, saves some ammo.
There, that ladder can get me up to the tower.
Okay, there's a rail up there.
I think I can reach it if I launch myself off that grapple point.
Got it!
[groaning metal]
Well, that sounds good.
The storm is getting bad.
Hah, made it!
Easy.
There is a cable here, maybe I can ride it to the other side.
Uhhh…
AAH! Oof!
Well, nowhere to go but up!
This place is barely holding together.
Whoa.
Looks like there are massive clamps holding the shuttle in place.
I'll bet there's a control console nearby.
If I can release the clamps, the shuttle should fall…
…right into the basin!
Ah, great. More machines in my way.
Okay. Got this place to myself now.
Control console might be in there.
Okay, time to crush those machines down below.
The shuttle's caught up in those cables.
I'm going to have to climb the tower to find a way to disconnect them.
Scanning with my Focus could help here.
Gotta climb closer to the shuttle to detach the cables.
Okay, that doesn't sound good. Better detach those cables quick!
This should be the right spot.
There!
That connector's holding the cables together.
It should break if I shoot it.
One down.
Now I just need to climb higher to detach the second set of cables.
Scaling an ancient rickety tower
with killer machines waiting down below.
Oh, maybe Varl was right.
No turning back now.
Almost there!
There's the other connector.
Umm…
No, no!
Oh shit! Shit! Shit!
Not going anywhere, are you?
Finishing this the hard way.
I need to take this thing down to get the data centre!
I'll scan for weak spots.
Okay, where's that weak spot?!
That sac's full of acid. I should target it first.
Watch out for that acid!
Whoa! Still got some fight left in you!
Hah! Try spitting at me now!
There! Those canisters are exposed now, I should aim for them.
Damn it, it broke free!
Got to take this thing down, fast!
Trap, maybe? Frost ammo?
Or my Focus might find something I can use around here.
How do you like that?!
It's dead. Finally!
The data centre should be straight ahead.
I guess Varl's gonna have to find another way there.
Once I get the backup, I can reboot Gaia.
Fix the system, heal the blight.
Restore Elisabet's dream.
But is it still there?
Okay, I should find the server room.
I'm close, I have to be.
Please be here!
It's here!
GAIA: Gaia version 6.9 initialising.
GAIA: Hello.
ALOY: Hi!
ALOY: Elisabet?
ALOY: Travis Tate.
TATE: Now, what's this we got here?
A Far Zenith conspiracy to steal a copy of Gaia,
and her subordinate functions?
Naughty, naughty!
You want me to handle this, Liz?
Blasphemers! Brood of vipers!
With a mighty hand I smite and pour troubles upon you.
[pew pew pew]
This ain't no copy of Gaia you stole, you losers.
But it's the mother of all logic bombs!
So good luck repairing your data.
And next time you start thinking you can outsmart a Tate?
Remember my salute!
VARL: Aloy?
The Goddess!
ALOY: There is no Goddess!
ALOY: I told you that already.
That's not Gaia.
ALOY: It's not what I'm looking for.
ALOY: It's nothing but a fake!
I got it.
ALOY: Varl…
I'm sorry.
VARL: You have a sharp bite sometimes, you know.
But it was pretty amazing to see you
fly off that tower and blow up the entire basin.
ALOY: The thing is, um, there's going to be more of that.
ALOY: I'm out of leads, Varl.
ALOY: But I have to keep searching and fast.
ALOY: And whatever risks I have to take, I will.
ALOY: And it doesn't make sense to have someone with me.
ALOY: Someone who might get hurt.
ALOY: This is on me Varl, nobody else.
VARL: Hold on!
VARL: Before, in Meridian, you said there was a man who helped you.
VARL: Sylens.
VARL: You said you used to talk to him a lot,
about things you discovered from the Old World.
VARL: Things no-one else understands.
VARL: And he gave you the lance you used to defeat Hades.
ALOY: He's gone, Varl.
ALOY: I haven't heard from him since the battle against Hades.
VARL: Sure, but spymaster Marad back in Meridian,
he's good at finding people, isn't he?
ALOY: Varl, I…
VARL: Come on, it might work.
VARL: Plus you'll get to see some friendly faces again.
ALOY: Okay, I…
ALOY: I guess it's worth a shot.
VARL: We've got a long walk ahead.
ALOY: Actually…
ALOY: I've got a better idea.
BYSTANDER: By the Sun, it's true. She's come back!
CARJA NOBLE: Bless us! The Saviour of Meridian has returned!
You earned this welcome.
You saved them.
ALOY: Not yet.
MARAD: In the name of the Sun-King Avad,
a royal welcome for the Champion!
MARAD: Make way.
VARL: Marad, Aloy has an urgent matter to discuss.
Does she? That makes two of us.
I've sent forth hunters for weeks.
MARAD: To Sunfall, all the way to the Sacred Land, searching for you.
Something happened at the Spire.
MARAD: Come, I'll show you.
MARAD: Watch your step.
MARAD: You saved us all, to be sure,
but we're still cleaning up the mess.
MARAD: It happened right after the solstice.
MARAD: We were able to explain it away, thank the Sun.
Otherwise it might have caused a panic.
One night, for less than half a minute, it glowed an angry red.
From Meridian, it looked like a trick of the light.
MARAD: But those who were closer, atop the Alight,
said it could not have been a reflection.
MARAD: Much to my dismay, they said the light
rose up from the tower's base.
MARAD: From that!
MARAD: We left everything just as it was.
VARL: What do you think happened?
ALOY: I don't know.
ALOY: The Spire is supposed to send out
signals — messages — for the terraforming system.
VARL: But Hades tried to use it to wake up ancient war machines.
ALOY: I was sure I cut the connection to that thing.
ALOY: Wait here while I check it out.
VARL: Let us know what you find.
ALOY: I've got a bad feeling about this.
ALOY: I don't know, looks the same as before.
Never could pull this thing out of the—
What?!
"Transmission"?
No, he wouldn't…
…he couldn't.
Something was transmitted from the top of the spire.
I guess I have to find a way up there.
There we go.
Now, how to cross over to the Spire?
Should be able to get up there now.
I thought Sylens was helping me when he gave me his lance.
Looks like he tricked me.
Transmitted something through the Spire.
Did he save Hades?
Why would he do that?
If I can figure out where he sent it, I can track him down.
Hopefully the transmission node at the top will tell me.
Looks like this panel's ajar.
Can I go up through the inside?
An elevator? Let's see.
COMPUTER: Access lift activated.
My lucky day.
COMPUTER: Engaging maintenance configuration.
The whole thing is opening up.
Wonder what the Carja will make of this.
There's the node.
Somewhere to the far West.
Bastard.
SYLENS: Well, Aloy…
SYLENS: I see you finally figured it out.
SYLENS: To be honest, I'm surprised
it took you so long to discover my ruse.
You rigged the lance to steal Hades.
How could you be so reckless?
SYLENS: Reckless?
You're the one who tried to purge Hades
before its precious knowledge could be … extracted.
The mysterious signal that woke it, for example.
SYLENS: Or where to obtain one of those Gaia backups
you've been having such a hard time finding.
ALOY: If you knew why didn't you just tell me?
SYLENS: I've been having problems of my own
these past six months, Aloy.
SYLENS: The difference is I've made progress.
SYLENS: So once your anger
at my entirely necessary deception has faded…
SYLENS: …well, why don't you come out here
and find me in the Forbidden West…
SYLENS: …and learn all that I have discovered.
ALOY: Oh, I'll come find you, alright.
SYLENS: Yes, well, the coordinates should make it simple enough…
SYLENS: …even for you.
GAH!
[sighs]
There's no other choice.