MARAD: Something happened at the Spire.
MARAD: Come, I'll show you.
ALOY: The Spire is supposed to send out
signals — messages — for the terraforming system.
VARL: But Hades tried to use it to wake up ancient war machines.
ALOY: I was sure I cut the connection to that thing.
Somewhere to the far West.
SYLENS: I see you finally figured it out.
SYLENS: To be honest, I'm surprised it took you so long to discover my ruse.
You rigged the lance to steal Hades.
I've made progress.
SYLENS: So once your anger
at my entirely necessary deception has faded…
SYLENS: …well, why don't you come out here
and find me in the Forbidden West…
SYLENS: …and learn all that I have discovered.
ALOY: Oh, I'll come find you, alright.
VARL: You went inside it and it transformed,
almost like the day of the battle.
MARAD: I can only be grateful that it's a stormy day.
Few will have seen the tower change from Meridian.
What did you discover?
ALOY: Hades.
ALOY: The danger didn't end here.
ALOY: It went into the Forbidden West.
ALOY: And I have to follow.
MARAD: I see. That can be difficult.
The West is called forbidden for a reason.
A tribe of ferocious warriors controls much of it, the Tenakth.
MARAD: And they allow no trespassers past its border.
MARAD: That said, under the Sun-King Avad,
a fragile peace has been negotiated.
MARAD: And indeed, the next Embassy will take place
in a day or two on the edge of the frontier.
MARAD: Were you to attend the gathering under his auspices,
MARAD: the Tenakth might grant right of passage,
MARAD: instead of hunting you and attacking on sight.
Great, just what I need — more killers.
MARAD: Ah, the Sun-King.
AVAD: Aloy, it's good to see you.
You left in such haste we never had a chance to properly thank you.
ITAMEN: Can— can we show the Champion the spear now? Please?
NASADI: Itamen, quiet.
AVAD: It's true, we bear gifts.
AVAD: Decorum usually calls for a ceremony of offering at the palace.
AVAD: But I thought you would prefer a less formal occasion.
AVAD: Bring them, please!
ALOY: Avad, this is all very kind, but I —
VANASHA: Quick, better hand them over before she runs off again.
UTHID: Really? Must you?
VARL: Try it on.
ALOY: It's beautiful.
AVAD: On behalf of all the citizens of the Sundom…
AVAD: …may these tokens remind you of our eternal gratitude.
MARAD: Perhaps you'd like to spend more time with your friends.
MARAD: Come speak to me when you're ready to depart.
I need to attach the Master Override to my new spear.
Should be a workbench around here I can use.
NASADI: Manners, Itamen. Now come and stand beside me.
Dowager Queen Nasadi.
NASADI: Blessed Champion. Itamen, what do you say?
My humblest thanks to you, great Champion.
For delivering my mother and me from Sunfall.
ITAMEN: And for defending our holy city against the forces of shadow.
Did I say it right?
You said it fine, Itamen.
And you're welcome.
Champion, will you teach me how to shoot like a real machine hunter?
Itamen!
I have to go on an important mission, Prince.
To save the world?
Something like that.
But when I come back, I could give you a few tips.
It would be an honour.
NASADI: We owe you our lives, Champion, and we will not forget.
NASADI: May the Sun light your way.
ITAMEN: Watch out for Thunderjaws, Champion!
ITAMEN: Is it true you and Talanah killed Redmaw? Marad said it's true.
NASADI: Hush child! Marad should know better
than to fill your head with such stories.
ITAMEN: But his stories are the only ones that aren't boring.
ADVISER: Shipments continue to arrive weekly through Cut-Cliffs.
ADVISER: And another band of Oseram labourers
have been hired to speed up reconstruction.
AVAD: Very good.
ALOY: Is that a statue of me?
AVAD: The sculptor wanted something even bigger.
AVAD: Twice the size, covered in gold and jewels.
AVAD: But I was quite certain you wouldn't appreciate that.
ALOY: You were right.
ALOY: I'm sorry, Avad.
AVAD: It's good to see you, but I can't stay long.
AVAD: I see.
AVAD: I'd hoped you'd remain in the city for a time.
AVAD: Perhaps at the palace.
ALOY: Meridian's still in danger, but it's bigger than that.
ALOY: To put things right, I have to go west.
ALOY: Tenakth territory.
AVAD: By the Sun! The Tenakth?
AVAD: Well, perhaps Marad already told you, but…
AVAD: After years of hostility, we've negotiated a truce.
AVAD: And hopes of a lasting peace.
AVAD: Another Embassy will be held in just a day or two.
"Years of hostility" — I assume you mean the Red Raids?
Ah, yes, my favourite subject.
I wouldn't ask if I didn't need to know.
As you know, my father raided all the border tribes.
The Oseram, Banuk, and Nora suffered greatly,
resisting as best they could.
But none fought back like the Tenakth.
They rose up and assaulted our western front of Barren Light.
Sweeping us from their lands.
AVAD: Getting them to talk to us again after that was … tricky.
How did you get the Tenakth to talk again?
The same way I got you to talk.
By giving gifts.
The Tenakth like tiaras?
More like metals, spices, and relics looted during the fighting.
We've met with them on several occasions,
and the gifts seem to have eased the tension.
But this coming Embassy is the most important yet.
The best sign we've had so far that the Tenakth want lasting peace.
What makes this coming Embassy so special?
Well, just like today, it is special because of the guest.
Our delegation will meet with the Tenakth just outside Barren Light.
We'll give them treasure and they'll return a prisoner.
Fashav, one of our finest soldiers.
Soldier? Don't you mean Raider?
No, not in this case.
Fashav is my cousin.
Nothing like Helis and his ilk.
He joined the Western Expedition with the hopes
of reining in certain excesses.
AVAD: But he was captured during a heroic defence
of our forward base at Cinnabar Sands.
And has been held ever since.
How long has he been a Tenakth captive?
Five years.
Tenakth emissaries swear he is well.
But I wonder.
That tribe is renowned for its brutality.
How did he survive?
Well, I'll know soon enough.
If you see him before I do…
Tell him that I await him in Meridian, where he belongs.
Itamen looks happy.
AVAD: You got him out of Sunfall.
AVAD: Any happiness he has, he owes to you.
He's turning into a fine young man.
Which he'll need to be if he is to inherit the crown.
Wouldn't the crown go to a son of yours first?
Yes, well.
I'd have to get married for that to happen.
Marad keeps throwing noble matches at me.
But I find I'm always…
…trying to make them into someone they're not.
AVAD: At any rate, I never aspired to the throne.
And I don't wish to sit there forever.
When Itamen comes of age, I hope to step aside.
Free of the crown.
I might finally be able to travel the world.
Who knows, perhaps even accompany you on one of your adventures?
I need to get going.
AVAD: Ah, one moment Aloy!
There's something I must ask you.
Since you left, I've thought of little else.
This isn't really the time.
But it has to be.
The way you left before, there's no way to know when I'll see you again.
I'm not trying to stop you or hold you back.
But I need to know.
When your mission is over.
Will you return to Meridian, and stay?
Long enough for us to … spend time to …
… get to know each other properly, perhaps?
Avad, the situation calls for … a higher perspective.
The threat I'm facing endangers not just Meridian,
but a lot of other places too.
A lot of innocent people.
What happens between us … it's not important.
At least not yet.
You're right.
I'm acting like a fool.
It's supposed to be the king who calls for a higher perspective.
I do hope to see Meridian again, Avad.
And you.
But, this mission, it's my life.
It's all I can think about.
I have to stay focused.
What happens after?
I can't imagine that.
I wouldn't know where to begin.
If that place were to end up being Meridian…
…know that you will always receive a boundless welcome here.
Tend to your mission, Aloy.
I will hope for your success.
As always, our hopes ride with you.
There, the workbench.
Okay, Master Override installed.
Plus something new to store up and release energy.
A "resonator". Should help in a fight.
ALOY: Uthid. Vanasha.
Thanks for being here.
VANASHA: Wouldn't miss it.
Even if you did leave us hanging after the big battle.
UTHID: Vanasha, stop.
She's here now, isn't she?
VANASHA: For the moment.
But I see that look on her face.
She's got business to attend to.
And it isn't in Meridian.
You know, I didn't vanish before because I wanted to, I had—
Little huntress, please.
You don't have to justify yourself to us.
You saved our butts.
If you've got to go, go.
With our blessing.
UTHID: Always.
You both look like you're doing well.
VANASHA: Mr Shiny Pants here is now
the Sun-King's senior military adviser.
That means people actually have to listen to him talk.
May the Sun bless their sorry souls.
UTHID: At least I say something of substance every once in a while.
What was that?
I just fell asleep while you were talking.
ALOY: And how about you, Vanasha?
I've been looking after Nasadi and Itamen.
Two parts bodyguard, one part—
UTHID: Bad influence.
VANAHSA: Ha! I was going to say nanny, but I like your version better.
ALOY: I never pictured you as a nanny.
Itamen must be special.
VANASHA: Hold on now!
I'm not entirely domesticated.
Nasadi was the Mad Sun-King's wife, she has enemies.
I've had to foil a plot or two.
UTHID: Right. You can try to hide it,
but inside you're as soft as a silk pillow.
VANASHA: Oh, you have no idea.
UTHID: Uh, oh dear.
ALOY: Uhhh, we were talking about Itamen?
VANASHA: Okay, I admit it.
Itamen's cute, he's fun, and he looks up to me.
I like him.
Except when he forgets to wash his hands after hooking worms
in that muddy garden behind his solarium.
Bleech!
It's been months since I was in Sunfall.
What's become of the Shadow Carja?
VANASHA: After you wiped out the Eclipse, there were
hardly any priests or officers left to terrorise the little people.
UTHID: Avad offered amnesty to all
who were forced to serve the Shadow.
So the commoners cleaned out the citadel and handed it back to him.
The Sundom was unified.
VANASHA: Avad wanted Uthid to take command of the garrison there…
VANASHA: …but Captain cuddly here refused.
Rumour has it that he wanted to stay close to me here in Meridian.
UTHID: He he, that's nonsense of course.
ALOY: Well—
VANASHA: I know, I know, you're out.
Go! Away with you!
UTHID: Always an honour, Champion.
VANASHA: Always a pleasure.
But please, little huntress, come back someday?
And tell us about your adventures?
If I can't get in trouble, at least I can hear about yours.
GUARD: Saviour, welcome back to the Alight.
Well, that's everyone.
I guess it was nice to catch up.
For a little while.
Machine carcasses, remnants from the battle of the Alight.
"Honouring those who fell in the battle of the Alight."
Lots of brave people defended this place from Hades.
I guess I should be flattered by the statue.
It feels wrong.
Especially when my job is only half done.
I'd better get going.
And if I'm headed west, it sounds like I'll need
right of passage from the Tenakth as you said.
Where exactly is this Embassy going to be held?
MARAD: Past The Daunt, the canyon that marks
the western border of the Sundom.
You'll find the fortress of Barren Light at its farthest edge.
MARAD: The Embassy will take place just beyond its gates.
It's a long march, fortnight on foot.
VARL: A couple of day's hard riding should get us there.
ALOY: Actually, it might be better to rest here tonight.
Head out in the morning.
Of course. I'll arrange it.
[Song: In The Flood, by Oleksa Lozowchuk, feat. Ariana Gillis]
Am I the one to hold
This crown of ash and salt
Their kindness calls to me
I have to block it out
My voice has grown so somber
These words don't seem like mine
But the iron won't subside
No matter, no matter what I try
Am I rain drops in the flood?
In this emptiness, in the storm
If I falter, if I fall
The wave inside my soul carries all I know
Who can take my hand in the flood?
Her voice calls me forth
Through darkness unknown
My heart with silence burns
Through solemness and bone
The edge beyond the shore
This weight of root and rot
I long to reach the other
To find, to find the path we lost
Am I rain drops in the flood?
In this emptiness, in the storm
If I'm broken, if I'm torn
The wave inside my soul carries all I know
Who can take my hand in the flood?
Sparks to steel!
Ha! Never seen anyone use one of those to get around.
Is that how I get to Barren Light?
Uh yes, I mean usually, but not today.
Not yet.
And why is that?
Well, The Daunt, the whole valley, it's infested with machines.
ALOY: I can handle machines.
Oh I'm sure you can, but…
I'm under strict orders not to operate until the whistle
down at Chainscrape sounds the all-clear.
Look, I didn't come all this way just to stand around and wait.
I'll crank that car down myself if I have to.
Well, but then who would crank it back up?
KARHN: Fine, fine.
Though, should anyone ask, it might be best to say you forced me.
ALOY: I see smoke, but not a lot of activity.
KARHN: Smoke's probably coming
from something the machines wrecked.
KARHN: As for the quiet, well,
there's a work stoppage in effect because of all the fuss.
ALOY: What sort of machines are causing the trouble?
KARHN: Nasty ones and lots of them. Bristlebacks, they're called.
KARHN: Strangeness is they're not native to The Daunt.
KARHN: Just showed up all of a sudden.
ALOY: No hunters to kill them?
KARHN: Well, we've got hunters.
KARHN: Just none that want to cross Ulvund.
KARHN: Boss of Chainscrape, he is self-appointed.
KARHN: Work stoppage was his idea.
ALOY: Yeah, well, I'm just passing through.
ALOY: Got an embassy to attend.
KARHN: You should have said!
KARHN: That ain't gonna happen no time soon.
ALOY: What are you talking about?
KARHN: You hear that? That's your answer.
[distant raised voice] Not this time!
ALOY: Who is that?
KARHN: Carja Sun-Priest, cranked him down yesterday
about an hour before the machine trouble started.
KARHN: He's a very important man.
KARHN: Or so he says.
KARHN: That Embassy at Barren Light?
KARHN: He's the one supposed to run it! Hah!
ALOY: Great.
VUADIS: If you don't do as I say immediately,
the Sun-King himself shall hear of your insolence.
VUADIS: Thanks to you, I was forced to spend the night
shivering in the tent.
VUADIS:  Exposed to attack! I might have died.
VUADIS: Oh, me you refuse to transport, but not this …
VUADIS: This … what? This Nora girl? This savage?!
VUADIS: Aside, scallywag.
JORUF: Vuadis, that's Aloy.
VUADIS: Studious Vuadis.
JORUF: Aloy, you know, Saviour of Meridian.
VUADIS: Really?
VUADIS: Well, that lessens the insult, I suppose.
I came here for the Embassy at Barren Light.
Way I hear it, so did you.
VUADIS: Well, not with the valley infested.
"And so did Araman proclaim the Sun-Priests
most precious and worthy of safekeeping."
See? Scripture.
I shall head to Barren Light when the captain of the Vanguard
tells me the way is clear.
And not a moment sooner.
Fine.
Captain's a friend of mine, you know.
ALOY: Where is Erend?
Wouldn't mind speaking to someone a little more action, a little less …
… scroll.
JARUF: Vuadis—
VUADIS: Studious Vuadis.
Studious Vuadis sent Erend and another Vanguard
out at daybreak to clear the way.
VUADIS: "And so at daybreak—"
ALOY: Hey!
ALOY: Shh!
ALOY: Down the valley, then?
Yeah, said they'd check the ruins on the left bank for tracks.
Take it from there.
Okay. I hear there's a work stoppage.
Any way to upgrade my gear?
JORUF: I'll bet the smith in Chainscrape
would let you use his workbench.
As for the Bristlebacks, you might want to craft some acid arrows.
Hitting their canisters with those will take 'em down quick.
ALOY: Thanks. I'll find Erend and I'll bring him back.
ALOY: Where do you think you're going?
VUADIS: Why, to the top of the ridge to wait in safety.
ALOY: Sorry, operator's under strict orders!
ALOY: No passengers till the whistle blows, right?
That's right. Best start cranking.
VUADIS: Why? Why?
ALOY: Joruf, would you kindly escort
Studious to Chainscrape and wait for me there?
JORUF: You got it.
I will find Erend and I will help clear a path.
But after that, no more excuses.
Barren Light. Embassy.
VUADIS: If such be the will of the Sun.
It will be, trust me.
I gotta find Erend, but it might be good
to hit Chainscrape first and upgrade my bow.
A gemstone. It's green like blaze, but it's hard and shiny.
Wonder if merchants would be interested?
It's a dead machine.
It must be a Bristleback.
Maybe Erend took it down?
Ground's soaked with acid.
Did the Bristlebacks do this?
That must be Chainscrape.
Joruf said I could get my bow upgraded in there.
Might be able to tinker with my other gear too.
OSERAM GUARD: Outlander approaching. Is that the Saviour?
OSERAM GUARD: Wanna come in Saviour?
Welcome to Chainscrape, Saviour.
Open up guys, Joruf's orders.
Good enough for me.
VOICE: By. The. Forge!
Petra?
Aloy! What are you doing here?
ALOY: Uhh…
PETRA: 'Bout time there was something worth looking at in this dump.
ALOY: It's nice to see you too.
PETRA: And not a moment too soon.
PETRA: Come on!
ALOY: I…
PETRA: Damn brewery's only thing I can count on in this place.
ALOY: Yeah, I heard. Machines. Work stoppage?
PETRA: Oh, those are just the latest malfunctions.
Chainscrape's always been a few tools short of a kit.
And right there is the biggest tool of all.
ULVUND: Not our land, not our problem.
JAVAD: The Bristlebacks are everybody's problem.
ALOY: Ulvund?
PETRA: You've heard of him?
ALOY: Yeah.
PETRA: But he's a story best told over a cold beer.
ALOY: Uh Petra! Petra!
I'm just passing through.
I'm headed west.
Oh.
There's an Embassy at Barren Light I need to make happen.
And then I… keep moving.
Ah, of course.
Bigger gears to grind.
Well, flamehair, good to see you.
If you gotta move on…
Petra.
But if you want a cold beer and a few laughs with an old friend?
Come find me at the brewery, your choice.
Well this Ulvund guy sounds like trouble.
Maybe Petra could use some support.
But first things first I need to find that workbench and upgrade my bow.
HAKUND: Until Ulvund blows that whistle, no-one's working here.
ALOY: Shop looks closed?
HAKUND: Yep.
ALOY: Can I still use the workbench?
HAKUND: I ain't gonna stop you.
HAKUND: Workbench is good for all kinds of tinkering.
This should be useful.
Now I just need to find Erend and help him clear the Bristlebacks.
Can't override that now. Need to get data
from a cauldron, if I can find one,.
Pain's subsiding.
I'll gather these while I can.
Acid won't make much of a dent.
Is that a tripwire?
This whole area is rigged with tripwires.
THURLIS: Hey! You! Make it worth your while
if you kill these Scroungers!
ALOY: It's always something.
ALOY: Hold tight! I'll see what I can do.
THURLIS: Try luring them into the tripwires.
THURLIS: That's fancy wire-work!
ALOY: That's the last one.
THURLIS: Hello, Red. What a day. What a day.
THURLIS: Thank the Forge you showed up.
THURLIS: Tripwires are handy, but machine hunting's a young-uns game.
THURLIS: Come on over, let me give thanks proper like.
THURLIS: I see you're a practised hunter.
Took you less time to kill those Scroungers
than Vanguards to kill one Bristleback.
ALOY: So the Vanguards came through here?
THURLIS: Yeah, just a bit ago.
THURLIS: Downed that Bristleback, headed south.
THURLIS: But then those Scroungers showed up
to carve the carcass, as they do.
THURLIS: Then another Bristleback ran through.
I'm telling you, it's crazy around here.
So the Vanguard went south.
Probably. This whole valley is swarming with them.
THURLIS: The Vanguard seemed dead set on getting rid of them.
ALOY: I see.
Hold on there, Red.
If you're gonna go chasing across The Daunt,
you're gonna want a Tripcaster.
Not just any Tripcaster, one of my make, free of charge.
Workmanship looks solid enough.
THURLIS: Yup.
Been tweaking the design since I left Chainscrape.
More room to tinker out here and less chance of, well, accidents.
Did something happen in Chainscrape?
More like someone.
I don't follow.
There's this sack of wet dirt, Ulvund.
Thinks he's the Ealdorman of Chainscrape.
Got half the town treating him as such.
Back when I had a place in town, he took a real interest in my wares.
THURLIS: Kept pressing for the "Ulvund discount".
THURLIS: I said no, he didn't like that so much.
THURLIS: I can't prove it, but that chuffbucket set my workshop on fire.
Felt it best to put some distance between us after that.
ALOY: Cable car operator told me
the Bristlebacks just appeared yesterday.
Do you know anything about them?
How is old Karhn?
Back in the day, me and him got into all sorts of trouble.
There was this one time tha—
ALOY: Anything about the Bristlebacks?
Nope, Karhn said true.
Just showed up and ran amok.
Lucky for me, I've got you and the Vanguard
swooping in time to time to save my backside.
ALOY: I should get going.
Thanks for the Tripcaster.
While you're blasting Bristlebacks,
I think I'll head down to the hunting grounds.
Did you know they have a Tripcaster trial?
Come by later, if you want to try it out.
ALOY: Maybe, after I get things under control.
ALOY: So Erend headed south.
Should be able to pick up his tracks with my Focus.
Tracks. Maybe Erend's and the Vanguards'.
It's a ruin from the Old World.
Bet I could find something interesting inside.
FENDUR: Hey you! Mind giving me a hand?
TELGA: Is that the Saviour of Meridian?
FENDUR: Welcome to the party!
ALOY: Glad I can help.
TELGA: Big guy's fast!
TELGA: Try pushing it off.
Mighty thankful to you, Saviour.
Just Aloy is fine.
Erend mentioned you're not one for fancy titles.
You're Vanguard.
FENDUR: We're here to escort Vuadis' delicate behind to the Embassy.
TELGA: If we can get rid of these Bristlebacks.
FENDUR: Captain said to keep an eye on Chainscrape.
Then these ugly lugs showed up.
TELGA: Gave the first one a good beating.
FENDUR: But didn't quite have time to roll out of the way when it fell.
Told you it wasn't a good idea to eat that much before heading out.
ALOY: I should probably get going.
FENDUR: Now, if you see any more of these Bristlebacks…
ALOY: I'll make sure to roll out of their way.
TELGA: Might want to take some of these with you as well.
They're handy in a pinch.
Thanks.
TELGA: Stay safe, Aloy.