VUADIS: I shall head to Barren Light when
the captain of the Vanguard tells me the way is clear.
And not a moment sooner.
Fine.
Captain's a friend of mine, you know.
ALOY: Where is Erend?
Wouldn't mind speaking to someone a little more action, a little less …
… scroll.
Vuadis sent Erend and another vanguard
out at daybreak to clear the way.
VUADIS: "And so at daybreak—"
ALOY: Hey!
ALOY: Shh!
ALOY: Down the valley, then?
Yeah, said they'd check the ruins on the left bank for tracks.
Take it from there.
Okay.
ALOY: So the Vanguards came through here?
THURLIS: Yeah, just a bit ago.
THURLIS: Downed that Bristleback, headed south.
THURLIS: But then those Scroungers showed up
to carve the carcass, as they do.
THURLIS: Then another Bristleback ran through.
I'm telling you, it's crazy around here.
So the Vanguard went south.
Probably. This whole valley is swarming with them.
THURLIS: The Vanguard seemed dead set on getting rid of them.
ALOY: Thanks
TELGA: Stay safe, Aloy.
Sounds like someone's putting up a fight.
ALDUR: Another one down!
EREND: Now this? This is what I was forged for!
EREND: No ledgers to fill.
EREND: No boring mid-afternoon patrols.
Just the hammer. Just the fight!
Aloy?!
Erend!
ALOY: Stay where you are, I'll handle the rest!
EREND: Dammit, I should be down there.
ALDUR: Not with those ribs.
ALOY: Those Bristlebacks have acid canisters on their backs.
It should trigger a chain reaction if I hit them with acid arrows.
EREND: Turn 'em to scrap, Aloy!
Machine's weak against Frost.
EREND: Look at that thing fizzing away!
EREND: Smashed 'em good!
EREND: Ha, ha! Oh, that one hurt.
EREND: Unh! Like hammer to metal!
EREND: Smashed 'em good!
That could help.
EREND: Aloy, you know you might have to — OOF —
EREND: — meet me half-way here — AAAH!
EREND: Aloy! Uhh, oh that's gonna hurt tomorrow.
EREND: Caught me at my best, as usual.
You did the hard part, I just took care of the stragglers.
How bad is it?
Oh this? Ah, who needs ribs, eh?
EREND: Ow!
EREND: Oh, I'm good, I'm good.
EREND: Okay, well, I …
I know you didn't come all the way to The Daunt
just to watch me get wrecked.
What's the story?
I need the Embassy to happen so I can head west.
ALOY: Erend, what I did at the Spire…
ALOY: …what WE did…
…it didn't end the threat.
It just slowed it down.
There's still more to do.
EREND: Really?
Well, that's great!
I mean, not the "threat's not over" part, that's not so great.
But hey, whatever you're up against, your spear, my hammer!
Just like old times!
ALOY: Erend, I need the Embassy now.
I can't wait for you to heal.
A couple of days rest, if that.
ALOY: Actually, even if you weren't hurt, what I have to do it's …
… it's better if I do it alone.
EREND: Alone.
EREND: Now that figures.
ALDUR: Erend!
ALDUR: I hate to interrupt the romance, but I'm pretty banged up here.
EREND: Don't blow your blaze, I'm coming.
EREND: Ugh, this just keeps getting better.
Listen,
I'll go to Barren Light, get patched up.
If you want this Embassy to happen …
… we're going to need this Sun-Priest, Studious Vuadis.
I know him.
I'll clear the valley of Bristlebacks, then send Vuadis to Barren Light.
I'll catch up with you there.
Well, I guess that's sort of like a goodbye.
I'm sorry?
You? Sorry? Hah.
That'd be a first.
ALOY: Where is this coming from?
EREND: Hey, just, you know, forget it, yeah?
EREND: It's nothing.
ALOY: It sounds like something.
Alright, fine.
Now, after the battle at the Spire, you took off.
You left without so much as a handshake.
EREND: I mean, people like me, we fought and bled at your side, Aloy.
EREND: You just, what, you just disappear?
EREND: What kind of person does that?
How about someone who thinks saving the world
is more important than whether your feelings get hurt?
Saving the world?
That's what I've been doing, Erend.
ALOY: What I'm still doing.
So, sorry if I've been in a hurry.
Erend, I left when I did, how I did for a reason.
A good one.
Oh, thanks for sharing.
Listen to me.
Life on Earth is in danger and only I can save it.
What're you talking about?
Everything dies unless I succeed.
EREND: Well, then let me help!
ALOY: You can't.
There's no machine to fight, no bad guy to kill.
What I've gotta do, I …
I can't even explain it.
Not even to people I care about.
Yeah, I guess that's a reason alright.
As usual, I shouldn't've said anything.
ALDUR: Erend! By the Forge!
I guess that's my cue.
Maybe I should go with you to Barren Light.
No, no, hey, no, you're you needed elsewhere, obviously.
We'll make it without you.
ALOY: That doesn't sound good.
EREND: You'll have to handle that one on your own.
EREND: We'll only slow you down.
What are those Oseram doing out here?
OSERAM: Quick! Gotta scrap 'em before the Scroungers get 'em!
ALOY: That Bristleback's charging right at them!
OSERAM: Haha! Another one for the scrap pile.
OSERAM: Your help was timely, Nora.
ALOY: Just get back to Chainscrape before you get yourselves killed.
OSERAM: Not with all this salvage lying about!
OSERAM: C'mon crew, back to it!
Quarry's full of Bristlebacks.
BELNA: Break those acid chuckers!
ALOY: Getting there.
BELNA: One down!
ALOY: One less machine.
BELNA: Look out! We got a different machine out here.
BELNA: That's it! Smash 'em to scrap!
ALOY: Another one down.
ALOY: This one can spit fire instead of acid.
BELNA: Good hit, now do it again.
ALOY: One less machine.
BELNA: One more down.
ALOY: Another one down!
BELNA: That's it, smash 'em to scrap!
ALOY: There, quarry's safe.
BELNA: Stranger, come on over here, we gotta talk.
Yeah, Yeah.
BELNA: Come here kid, I wanna talk to you.
I don't know what a Nora is doing out here, but consider yourself owed.
We tried to hold off and wait for the Vanguard,
but one of them Bristlebacks charged us.
Next thing you know it was a full-fledged fracas.
Is everyone OK?
BELNA: We lost some good people.
But we would have lost the whole quarry without you.
Well, at least it's quiet now.
Your ears ought to be ringing with a quarry at work.
But Chainscrape's whistle ain't blowin',
so we're stuck picking up the pieces.
You need the whistle to get back to work?
Me and my crew we're just little cogs out here.
Can't lift a hammer 'til Ulvund blows that thing.
Because if we work without his say so, he'll ban us.
And my people have been through enough.
Ulvund holds that much power?
He's got the money and connections to snuff our fires for good.
Almost feels like we stood a better chance with the Bristlebacks.
ALOY: What are you and your crew working on?
We're supposed to be working Ulvund's claim.
Digging out stone to shore up Barren Light.
But the work stoppage and the Bristlebacks cut us short.
Never seen those blasted things in The Daunt before.
Where in forgefire did they come from?
I'm not sure.
At least not yet.
I need to get going.
Stay safe.
Thanks to you, that might actually be possible today.
Valley should be safe enough to travel.
I'll go give Vuadis the good news.
Then maybe this Embassy can finally happen.
Come on!
GUARD: Be welcome, Outlander.
Time to get Vuadis to Barren Light.
ALOY: The way to Barren Light is clear, get moving.
VUADIS: You're not Erend Vanguardsmen.
VUADIS: I will move only when the captain—
ALOY: When I've cleared out all the Bristlebacks, which I have.
ALOY: Captain's orders.
JORUF: So they're okay?
ALOY: Banged up but breathing, and waiting up ahead for you.
VUADIS: Well, I shall not be moving anywhere
until the whistle has sounded.
VUADIS: If it is not safe for them, then it is not safe for me.
ALOY: Ugh, fine.
ALOY: I'll make sure the whistle gets blown and then I'll be back.
VUADIS: Hear that? We're not leaving yet. Unpack the cart!
ALOY: No, I'll be right back, don't get comfortable.
VUADIS: As if that were possible here.
Petra mentioned Ulvund is supposed to be in charge around here.
Guess I should talk to him to get the whistle blown.
JAVAD: We are on the same side here, Ulvund.
JAVAD: The Bristlebacks threaten us all.
ULVUND: Oh drop the act.
ULVUND: We all know it was the Carja
who let the Bristlebacks into the valley.
ULVUND: Sent them straight through the gates of Barren Light.
JAVAD: That is preposterous.
JAVAD: Why would we let dangerous machines into our own land?
ULVUND: You mean the land that honest Oseram labourers
work tirelessly with no say in its governance?
ULVUND: The land that should you sign the decree—
JAVAD: Oh! You and that damned concession decree!
ULVUND: —would be managed by the people
who actually live and work on it.
JAVAD: What do you want, Ulvund?
JAVAD: Some kind of payment?
ULVUND: My dear magistrate, you think I can be bought?
If you want that whistle blown, all you have to do
is have your soldiers remove the Bristlebacks…
ULVUND: …and sign the concession decree.
Face it, what other choice do you have?
ALOY: [clears throat] Hi.
JAVAD: Saviour! What auspicious timing!
Might we discuss a matter of importance to the Sundom?
ALOY: We might, later.
JAVAD: Very well, I shall be waiting.
ULVUND: So the Saviour herself.
Walloper of Dervahl, gutter of Helis.
ALOY: [sighs] Maybe.
I've heard many tales of your beauty and heroics, my fierce lady warrior.
Ulvund Freeholder, at your service.
ULVUND: So what could have dragged you away
from the fine silks and wine of Meridian…
…to this smudge of a settlement?
Your Saviourly attention must be needed elsewhere.
I'm here for the Embassy and—
ULVUND: The Embassy?
Why, by the Forge.
Ah.
Greater gears for greater matters.
Guess that means you'll be moving on.
ALOY: Once I've dealt with any problems
around here that need my "Saviourly attention".
ULVUND: Ah, the Bristlebacks, of course.
Got to get rid of them if you want that Embassy to take place.
Well, best get to it, hey? And off you go!
ALOY: Not so fast.
You don't seem to have a high opinion of the magistrate.
Well, I refuse to play nice to some fancy robed parchment pusher.
When my fellow labourers are being bullied,
intimidated, and taken advantage of.
ALOY: How noble of you.
ULVUND: Noble, hah!
ULVUND: Born with a hammer in hand, I was.
ULVUND: Nobody handed me anything
or dropped opportunity into my lap.
Everything I've achieved, I've done on my own.
ALOY: And where is this hammer now?
The …uh… burden of leadership forced me to set it aside.
ULVUND: The Carja risk nothing.
ULVUND: While demanding that good Oseram
gamble with their lives out there.
Someone had to step up and say "no more!"
You ordered the work stoppage?
ULVUND: Indeed I did.
We're labourers, not soldiers.
Until the Carja clean up their mess and give us the fair deal we deserve…
I'm not risking Oseram lives!
"Fair deal"? You mean your concession decree?
ULVUND: It's not my decree.
ULVUND: It's on behalf of all the good Oseram labourers
of this land who do all the backbreaking work.
While only the Carja reap the rewards.
All we're asking for is the ability to share in this prosperity.
For a land worked by the people, for the people!
ALOY: Right. And just how much would be your share?
Only an amount appropriate to my contributions
to this community, of course.
If Chainscrape is on Carja land, shouldn't a Carja be in charge?
Who appointed you?
The sensibilities of good Oseram folk, of course.
You think a Carja can head this whole venture?
Ha!
The Magistrate can barely make the trek
from Barren Light without losing a few screws.
So you have no real authority, then?
People only follow you because you say so … loudly.
Anyone who has followers has authority.
I've been with Chainscrape from the beginning.
I mean, I'm practically its founder.
And its honest folk know I'm indispensable to its success.
You said you founded Chainscrape.
Somehow I doubt that.
Practically founded, I said.
I alone saw its potential when it was just
a smattering of tents in Barren Light's shadow.
ULVUND: I invested in the mine,
convinced some friends back home to do the same.
And here we are.
You could say Chainscrape is what it is thanks to me.
Oh, so you're not just standing around and profiting off everyone else?
Not at all.
Sure, I make a little return on my investment here and there.
But my main priority, as it was from the beginning,
is to look after the well being of these honest, working Oseram.
I cleared out all the Bristlebacks.
Oh, you did?
Now that you've recovered from your shock, time to blow the whistle.
Whoa there, not so fast.
I'll have to send someone out to confirm the kills.
Make sure the valley is safe again.
Shouldn't take more than a day.
ULVUND: Or two.
ALOY: No, you blow the whistle now.
These are innocent Oseram lives we're talking about here.
Surely the delay—
ALOY: Either you do it now or I will.
I knew you could do it!
ULVUND: Friends! Gather around.
ULVUND: The Saviour of Meridian has done it again.
ULVUND: The Bristlebacks are defeated.
Uhhh … you.
OSERAM: What?
ULVUND: Sound the whistle! Chainscrape is open for business.
OSERAM: Terrific.
OSERAM: Great.
OSERAM: Yay.
ALOY: And Ulvund has agreed
to personally pay every worker their lost wages.
Yeah!
That's more like it!
Whoo! Haha! Yeah!
[Chainscrape whistle blows]
ULVUND: Don't you have an Embassy to get to?
ALOY: Yeah, I guess I do.
Now that Chainscrape's back to work,
merchants should be open to trade.
I should see if they have anything useful
before I send Vuadis off to Barren Light.
Better see what that Carja magistrate wanted.
I bet he's in the tavern.
Hey, Milduf. Milduf!
Took some of your stew last time I went into the wild.
Kept me going for a week.
Felt like I could have put a Strider in a sleeper hold.
Enjoy it while it lasts.
ALOY: Sounds like you're serving up some impressive provisions here.
MILDUF: Ohh, not again.
MILDUF: You can have the discount too,
but you'll have to come back later.
ALOY: I think you have me confused with someone else.
MILDUF: Ulvund didn't send you?
ALOY: No.
MILDUF: Oh, my apologies.
It's just that his minions won't stop pestering me.
Huh, now I've even worn out my special griddle.
Since I'm in the midst of a crisis,
perhaps you could skip to what it is you wanted?
ALOY: Some of your food?
Of course.
Are Ulvund's people causing you problems?
Oh yeah, they constantly demand my best.
But the equipment I need to make
my signature dishes isn't built for batch cooking.
And don't get me started on the
"Ulvund discount" they feel so entitled to.
ALOY: And if you refuse?
MILDUF: I make meals, not trouble.
How did you end up in Chainscrape?
Heard about a new and upcoming town at the edge of the frontier.
Where there's a town, there's a tavern.
I was in need of work.
So I got myself out here and started cooking.
Some of these people had never tasted proper
boars'n'berries stew before.
Anyway, next thing I knew, people kept coming back.
Guess they like my food … more than ale.
Your last customer mentioned your cooking
really kept him going out in the wild.
Where I'm headed I could use some of that.
I would be happy to oblige,
especially since you have the decency to ask pleasantly.
ALOY: But…?
But my special grooved griddle is no more.
Without it I can't cook any of my signature dishes.
I hate to think what'll happen when
I'm forced to refuse Ulvund or his goons.
Even if I already had the right ingredients, there's nothing I could do.
Unless you can source me a temporary replacement?
What do you need?
For the ingredients? A few pieces of decent wild meat.
And, let's see, a big handful of bitter leaf stems, that'll do.
As for the griddle, a corrugated metal panel might suffice.
Until I can have a new one forged.
You'd likely find one in a Scrounger pile,
if you follow the river to the north-east.
Don't worry, I'll clean it first.
You'll have no issue finding boars and bitter leaf on your way.
Assuming you're as much a hunter-gatherer as your clothing suggests.
Thanks, Milduf. I'll keep an eye out.
MILDUF: So that's what gratitude sounds like.
ALOY: And don't let anyone push you around, okay?
If you say so.
Saviour, thank you for taking the time.
My condolences that you had to endure Ulvund's bloviating.
ALOY: I've dealt with worse.
It sounds like he's really trying to put you over the barrel.
JAVAD: The idea that the Carja
purposely let Bristlebacks into The Daunt, it's…
It's completely absurd.
But the louder and longer he says it,
the more support he'll get for his damned concession decree.
How did the Bristlebacks get into The Daunt?
No-one knows for sure.
The first report of them came from west of the quarry.
According to one terrified labourer,
said the ground trembled before they came charging down the hillside.
He took off and ran all the way here.
But unless they have wings I don't know about,
I don't see how they could have come over the mountains.
ALOY: No other way in?
JAVAD: The only way I know about is Barren Light.
If you can get to the bottom of this,
I can offer a considerable bounty in return.
Help me shut Ulvund up!
If you learn the truth, maybe Ulvund will stop
blaming the Carja for every problem under the Sun.
And maybe then he'll actually focus on rebuilding Barren Light instead.
What is this concession decree that Ulvund wants?
He wants the Sundom to designate
portions of The Daunt as Oseram holdings.
Only the portions, mind you, that produce any value.
Let me guess: because he stands to profit somehow?
Exactly.
With The Daunt under Oseram law,
he could secure more investment for their numerous ventures.
He can't get those investments without the concession?
JAVAD: No, not while there's a chance
the Sundom could revoke their access.
JAVAD: Hence why the concession is so important to him.
And why blaming the Carja for the Bristlebacks,
no matter how absurd, works in his favour.
How does blaming the Carja for the Bristlebacks
help Ulvund get his concession?
Look around.
This may be the Sundom, but Chainscrape is
all gears and rust and … bad ale.
Claiming that the Carja loosed the Bristlebacks in order
to intimidate Oseram labourers into obedience…
Well, let's just say no-one here has forgotten
the atrocities of the Mad Sun-King.
Even with the valley working again, Ulvund hopes
he can stir up enough resentment against the Carja to call for a strike.
And if the Oseram refuse to work unless
the concession is signed, you won't have a choice.
Correct.
The reconstruction of Barren Light must continue.
How did you get stuck out here?
I asked for the posting, believe it or not.
Overseeing the entire valley on behalf of the Sun-King?!
It was an honour … is an honour, I mean.
But your job would be a lot easier without
someone like Ulvund blasting hot air all the time?
Ulvund's not going anywhere.
He's been around longer than I have.
Even fancies himself the "Founder of Chainscrape".
No, I'll find a way to live with him.
I have to.
ALOY: You heard the whistle, time to go.
VUADIS: But I–I was supposed to have three escorts.
JORUF: I'm off to Barren Light, Vuadis.
Like Aloy said, Captain's orders. You can stay here.
Abandoned to the riff-raff? I think not!
JORUF: Guess you're coming with me then. See you there, Aloy!
Well, now that that's done, the Embassy can finally get underway.
If I can get through it, I'll be able to
track down Sylens, Hades, maybe even a Gaia backup.
Guess I could head straight for Barren Light,
or a poke around The Daunt some more first.
And maybe take Petra up on that drink.
What happened to you?
ARNUF: That damn mine is what happened to me.
It won't be the last injury if Ulvund keeps
shoving his tongs into those tunnels.
What mine?
Northeast of Chainscrape, where the river ends.
I told Korvend we should stop when the first cave-in happened, but…
…Ulvund probably threatened to cut off our pay. Or worse.
ALOY: How about you slow down and take me through it?
Korvend and the others were opening a new vein,
while I was checking on an older one.
Soon as their blast hit, tunnel I was in collapsed.
Might have dodged it if I wasn't running on barely a spark of sleep.
We're pushing too hard and too fast.
And you're afraid Korvend and the others
might not be as lucky if it happens again.
Mmm-hmm, hit the nail right on the head.
How come Ulvund's in charge? Don't these mines belong to the Carja?
Try telling Ulvund that!
He brought in all the backing to get 'em open, might as well own them.
He he, fire and spit, you ask him … he owns us as well.
Who's Korvend?
He's the foreman and a damn good one.
The kind of knows how to deal with management
when it gets unreasonable.
But Ulvund? Huh. His demands go beyond unreasonable.
Korvend's been doing his best to appease him.
He even blamed himself for my injury,
when it was Ulvund who ordered the extra shifts.
Sounds like a good guy.
That's why we all put up with the long hours and lousy conditions.
But if the whole mine becomes unstable?
I'd rather suffer Ulvund's wrath than die buried in rubble.
I could check in on your crew?
I would appreciate that.
Thank you.