VOICE: By. The. Forge!
ALOY: Petra?
PETRA: Aloy! What are you doing here?
ALOY: Uhh…
PETRA: 'Bout time there was something worth looking at in this dump.
ALOY: It's nice to see you too.
PETRA: And not a moment too soon.
ALOY: Uh Petra! Petra!
I'm just passing through.
I'm headed west.
Oh.
There's an Embassy at Barren Light I need to make happen.
And then I… keep moving.
Ah, of course.
Bigger gears to grind.
Well, flamehair, good to see you.
If you gotta move on…
Petra.
But if you want a cold beer and a few laughs with an old friend?
Come find me at the brewery, your choice.
But if the whole mine becomes unstable?
I'd rather suffer Ulvund's wrath than die buried in rubble.
I could check in on your crew?
I would appreciate that.
Thank you.
It seems like bitter leaf likes to grow on rocky terrain.
Okay, I think I have enough bitter leaf.
Hold onto this for later.
There, that should be enough wild meat for Milduf.
Can't override that machine,
but I could learn if there's a cauldron out here.
Frost'll make it brittle.
Huh, hunter becoming the hunted.
Scroungers.
Milduf said I could find a metal panel in one of their scrap piles.
No metal panel, better check another scrap pile.
Acid ammo could help here.
I'll save the extra stock for later.
DELVER: Does your All-Mother hear your prayers out here?
I think I have everything I need for Milduf.
Good thing too, I could use a decent meal.
This metal panel should work for Milduf.
Spotted!
Smoke, coming from where Arnuf said I'd find his crew.
This must be the mine Arnuf told me about.
It looks like the miners are in trouble!
[panting]
KORVEND: You good?
VALGEND: I–I'm okay. Thank you, Korvend.
ALOY: Korvend?
KORVEND: Not now. Aah!
ALOY: Arnuf sent me. What happened?
Explosion in the mine.
Water flooded the whole place.
KORVEND: Some of my guys are still…
KORVEND: They're still down there, I can't–can't stop…
You've done enough.
ALOY: Are you hurt?
KORVEND: I'm…
KORVEND: I'll live.
KORVEND: I can't…
I have to go.
How many are still down there?
KORVEND! How many?
KORVEND: Uhh…
KORVEND: Two, I think. Two more.
Take care of him, I'll check on the others.
Gotta find those two miners, quick.
Hello? Can anyone hear me?
DISTANT VOICE: Over here!
LOKUF: I think I'm starting to see things — is that a Nora?
Are you okay?
Who are you?
Korvend sent me. Are you hurt?
LOKUF: My leg.
LOKUF: I… I was a little too close to the blast.
ALOY: What happened?
THORDEN: We were blasting in the farthest tunnel,
but the scaffolding didn't hold, it collapsed.
THORDEN: I think it blocked the drainage shaft.
THORDEN: Water started flooding the place as quick as I drink ale.
THORDEN: I barely managed to drag us here.
ALOY: So something is keeping the water inside the tunnels.
LORUF: What are you thinking?
ALOY: I've got an idea. Are there more explosives?
Are you crazy?
Yeah, should still be some up top, but…
You'll need these fuses.
Are you crazy?
You can't move and I'm not leaving you.
THORDEN: It's not like she can make things worse.
ALOY: Don't go anywhere.
I need to find whatever's blocking that drainage shaft.
And blow it sky high.
Hopefully without bringing the mine down on top of me.
Almost there.
Oof, made it.
There's the debris blocking the shaft.
If I can reach those explosives up on that track,
maybe I can blast through the blockage.
Burrowers.
I think that's all of them.
Now to find a way out of this room.
I need to find a way up to those explosives.
I should follow those tracks, see if they lead to the explosives.
Let's see where this leads.
There's the explosives up on the track.
Just need to get across somehow.
Might be a good idea to drop that ladder.
That did the trick.
Guess that got its attention.
Down it goes!
That's all of them. Now let's go check on those miners.
LOKUF: She's so dead.
THORDEN: We don't know that!
It looks like everyone's okay.
LOKUF: Ha ha ha! I can't believe we're not gonna die!
THORDEN: You did it.
LOKUF: I thought you blew yourself up.
Are you two okay from here?
I can get this idiot down, don't you worry.
Thanks, kid.
Better let Korvend know his men are all right.
I found the two you mentioned.
They're safe, but could probably use a hand.
Is that everyone?
It is.
I dread to think what would have happened if you hadn't shown up.
I knew we were blasting too much,
but the man who staked the claim here, Ulvund…
Grr, he kept pushing and pushing me.
I tried to shield my crew from his constant demands, every damn day.
I … I should have been stronger.
You were there for your crew when they needed you.
That counts for something.
Ulvund can threaten me all he wants.
I am not letting my people back into those mines.
Will you be all right?
Yes, I can take it from here.
KORVEND: Thank you, huntress. I'll see the last two make it out.
MINER: I knew we were blasting too fast!
Now they're mad.
I'll leave you here.
GUARD: Be welcome, outlander.
There you are! I happened to receive another visit from Ulvund himself.
I'm listening.
When I made his meal, I used three pinches of salt!
Instead of two!
Each journey begins with a single step, I guess.
ALOY: I think I have everything you asked for.
MILDUF: Then, just as you have inspired me,
let us see if I can return the favour.
MILDUF: Time to cook!
Wow, Milduf that was inspired!
Next time you want the best provisions, you know where to find me.
And your next order of any dish will be on the house.
Thanks. And don't forget to stand up for yourself.
MILDUF: Funny you should say that.
MILDUF: As it happens, I'm already cooking up my next portion of resistance.
MILDUF: Hope to see you again.
PETRA: Aloy! Change your mind about that brew?
PETRA: Come for that beer after all eh? Here! Siddown!
PETRA: Get a pint in her hand!
PETRA: Wasn't expecting you to swing by.
ALOY: Since when do I do what's expected?
PETRA: Hah! There's that spark!
PETRA: Fire and spit!
ALOY: Uh, fire and spit.
PETRA: Aaah! That's a blast from the bellows.
PETRA: Won't fix the forge, but at least
I can forget about my troubles for a while.
ALOY: Like what?
PETRA: Take your pick.
We got bodies to bury from the Bristlebacks.
The work stoppage.
Ulvund grating the gears about his concession decree.
PETRA: Hey! Weapons off the table!
PETRA: Right now, I'm just worried about those refugees out from Sunfall.
To come all this way, enduring forge knows what.
ALOY: Shadow Carja refugees?
PETRA: They don't call themselves Shadow Carja for one.
PETRA: At least, not any more.
PETRA: They are some other brand of sun-crazed.
ALOY: What are they doing in The Daunt?
PETRA: Um, looking for a new home, I gather.
PETRA: They're camped out by an old trail head southwest of here.
PETRA: And therein lies the problem.
PETRA: A Stormbird crashed up on the cliffs last week.
PETRA: And Tolland Cleanbroker's had his eye on the salvage ever since.
PETRA: But the refugees have barred entrance.
PETRA: Mustn't interrupt their sun-scorched ritual.
PETRA: Something about finding a "twilight path".
ALOY: Huh, never heard them talk about that before.
PETRA: Yeah, well, these particular Shadow Carja are an odd bunch.
PETRA: But whatever side of the Sun they're on,
they're peaceful through and through.
PETRA: Don't seem to want for nothing except a place to live, pray,
and just enough food to keep from starving.
ALOY: So they're just camped outside by a trail,
blocking entry to a wrecked Stormbird, waiting for what, exactly?
PETRA: Don't rightly know, but I'll tell you this.
PETRA: Should they ever wise up and salvage it?
PETRA: A Stormbird heart is worth a lot.
PETRA: And if they get there first, then by Oseram law, it's theirs.
PETRA: Overall they're a peaceful folk, not that it matters to Tolland.
PETRA: He'll crack some heads to get to that salvage.
Who is this Tolland Cleanbroker?
PETRA: Just some chuff-huffing pondsman, got a shop here in town.
PETRA: Lived in Chainscrape since there was a Chainscrape.
PETRA: He and Ulvund go back a ways,
like a pair of coals in a camp fire those two.
ALOY: So Tolland works for Ulvund?
PETRA: Ha! Ulvund might think so.
PETRA: But Tolland scrapes up his own scams.
PETRA: And he ain't the type to let a few refugees
get between him and Stormbird salvage.
So the Bristlebacks in The Daunt…
OSERAM: [burps]
PETRA: You're a pig!
ALOY: …where did they come from?
PETRA: That's the thing, no-one rightly knows.
PETRA: They just showed up one day,
rampaging around the valley like they exploded out of a forge.
PETRA: [sighs] Lost some good people.
PETRA: But bless the bellows, you cleared them out
and got this place working again.
PETRA: But we still got Ulvund grating the gears about his concession decree.
PETRA: If you don't put that down,
I'll come over there and show you how that game ends!
PETRA: Around here, everything's about Ulvund.
ALOY: How'd he end up in charge?
PETRA: He got here early like a squirrel smelling a fat nut.
PETRA: He knew rebuilding Barren Light would need stone and timber.
PETRA: So he jangled purses all over Mainspring,
PETRA: getting investors to front claims on anything
in The Daunt that might be worth a damn.
PETRA: Thing is, all the bankers back home know that this is Carja land.
PETRA: And the Sun-King can revoke those claims at any time.
PETRA: That's why he's desperate for the magistrate
to sign off on a concession decree.
ALOY: And people actually believe him?
PETRA: Lots of folks suffered at the hands of
the Mad King during the Red Raids.
PETRA: Give them half a reason they'll blame the Carja for anything.
OSERAM: Yeah, damn Carja slavers.
ALOY: Well, if I'm up that way, I'll talk to the refugees,
try to convince them to move.
PETRA: Much appreciated, they have it rough.
PETRA: Don't need Tolland making it rougher.
ALOY: I'm glad I stopped by.
PETRA: Any time, flamehair.
This Tolland guy might still be in Chainscrape.
I could have a word with him first.
VOLMA: 'Bout time that whistle blew.
HAKUND: Shop just opened up, and I've got a backlog of orders,
so I wouldn't hold my breath.
HAKUND: Brought out only the good stuff for you, Red,
seeing as you got that whistle blowin'.
VOLMA: Hey, I've been waiting to get my lucky hammer fixed for days!
HAKUND: You haven't done anything useful
like getting rid of any Bristlebacks, though, have you?
HAKUND: Take your time, I promise you won't be disappointed.
TOLLAND: Oh it's you, the machine hunter that bailed out the Carja.
ALOY: Never heard it put that way before.
What do you want?
Heard you've been hassling refugees up by the cliffs.
TOLLAND: Yeah, well, you heard wrong.
TOLLAND: There's salvage up there, a Stormbird.
TOLLAND: Nailed it myself with the harpoon here in town.
TOLLAND: Not an easy shot, if I do say so myself.
TOLLAND: I clipped its wing and it crashed
into the old tower up there. Killed it quick.
So if anyone's hassling anyone, it's the Shadow Carja filth
that's blocking the way up to my claim.
ALOY: And you're ready to crack some skulls to get to it?
TOLLAND: No need, it's a raggedy bunch,
probably all starve before I have to lift a finger.
ALOY: We'll see about that.
TOLLAND: Oh, yeah, we will, won't we?
TOLLAND: Now, shop's closed to Carja lovers. On your blasted way.
ODURG: Move those feet!
ODURG: The Saviour of Meridian! Come on over here.
ALOY: You wanted to speak to me?
ODURG: Well, you know better than anyone it's
a dangerous world out there, and not just against machines.
ODURG: Name's Odurg. This here's my training pit.
ODURG: Best place to practise close combat
this side of the Forbidden West.
ODRUG: Say, I wonder who'd win in a fight?
ODURG: You, the Saviour of Meridian, champion of the East?
ODURG: Or The Enduring, master of the West.
ALOY: Who?
ODURG: The Enduring. A legendary Tenakth fighter, the master of masters.
ODURG: I've heard the Tenakth have training pits just like this one.
ODURG: It's how their warriors get so fierce, see?
ODRUG: And only the very best from the pits
get to train with The Enduring.
ALOY: So to find The Enduring, I should look for these
training pits if I'm ever out that way?
ODURG: You'll have to go far if you do.
ODURG: The Tenakth are split into three clans.
ODURG: Three clans, three capitals, three training pits.
ODURG: My guess is you'd have to beat all of them
if you want to train with The Enduring.
ODURG: If the Tenakth don't kill you on sight, that is.
ODURG: But that's a far spark in the wind.
ODURG: As for right now, I also offer challenges to test your fighting skill.
Who would I be fighting exactly, you?
ODURG: Well, I know you're the Saviour and all,
but you have to beat all the others first to challenge me.
ODURG: Rules are rules.
ODURG: We only use dull blades and practise arrows, mind.
ODURG: These drunken fools would run themselves through otherwise.
ODURG: You'll have to leave everything
but your spear and practise arrows at the gate.
ODURG: But I'll look after your gear, not to worry.
ODURG: So, what do you say? Up for some training? [chuckles]
I might be.
That's what I like to hear.
ODURG: If you keep repeating the same attacks,
your enemy will dodge them.
ODURG: Vary your attacks and combinations,
make yourself less predictable.
ODURG: Come on, if your opponent keeps blocking,
then use a heavy attack or a power attack to break through.
ODRUG: Either that or hit them from beind.
ODURG: Pay close attention to your opponent's stance.
ODURG: Read their intentions, choose your attacks to break their defence.
ODURG: You think your spear can deal with that armour?
ODURG: Use attacks to energise your spear.
ODURG: Then hit your opponent with a heavy
or power attack to blast their armour off.
ODURG: That spear can give you the edge in battle.
ODURG: Keep energising it, and then your enemies.
ODURG: Triggering those energy blasts
should help you vanquish your opponents.
ODURG: Can you finish this?
ODURG: I see how you earned your reputation.
ODURG: A good series of attacks!
ODURG: You fight well.
ODURG: Impressive attack!
ODURG: I see how you earned your reputation.
ODURG: Ho ho, good, an impressive attack.
ODURG: You fight well.
ODURG: Impressive attack, you fight well.
ODURG: Let's test your skills.
ODURG: Yield! I yield.
ODURG: Well fought, friend, well fought.
ALOY: Are you okay?
ODURG: [laughing] Yeah. Oof.
ODURG: Serves me right for thinking I could go up
against the Saviour of Meridian.
ODURG: Here, have this. A little something for the new champion.
ALOY: Thank you, Odurg.
ODURG: Don't be a stranger, now.