The first report of them came from west of the quarry.
According to one terrified labourer,
said the ground trembled before they came charging down the hillside.
He took off and ran all the way here.
But unless they have wings I don't know about,
I don't see how they could have come over the mountains.
PETRA: A Stormbird crashed up on the cliffs last week.
PETRA: And Tolland Cleanbroker's had his eye on the salvage ever since.
PETRA: But the refugees have barred entrance.
PETRA: Mustn't interrupt their sun-scorched ritual.
PETRA: Something about finding a "twilight path".
ALOY: Huh, never heard them talk about that before.
PETRA: Yeah, well, these particular Shadow Carja are an odd bunch.
PETRA: But overall they're peaceful folk, not that it matters to Tolland.
ODURG: Well fought friend, well fought.
Are you okay?
ODURG: [laughing] Yeah. Oof.
ODURG: Serves me right for thinking I could go up
against the Saviour of Meridian.
Here, have this. A little something for the new champion.
Thank you, Odurg.
Don't be a stranger now.
Come back whenever you'd like to spar again.
ALOY: I should go.
DELAH: I'm sorry, I'll be right with you.
ALOY: Uhhh…
DELAH: Okay, I'm not saying it's a bad idea,
I'm saying it's overkill.
BOOMER: It's a weapon! Kill is the point!
DELHA: Not if it blows the user's arm off!
DELAH: Tch–tch–tch just stop talking.
DELAH: Where were we? Ah!
DELAH: [clears throat] So … ah … you!
DELAH: You look like someone who's always
searching for a new weapon.
DELAH: Am I right?
Actually, I– oh!
DELAH: Could you just not?! I am with a customer.
I'm not a customer.
BOOMER: I got it! Triple the powder.
It'll blow a Strider sky high, ba-boom!
BOOMER: One shot kill, guaranteed.
ALOY: Um, maybe I am.
DELAH: Then you are in the right place at the right time, Red.
DELAH: How would you like to be the proud owner
of the world's first machine enhanced—
BOOMER: —explosive, done in one, machine wrecking—
DELAH: —yet perfectly safe javelin thrower?
Are you two from around here?
Nah, the Claim. Dad sent us out west
in search of some unknown opportunity.
Said we'll know it when we see it.
Sounds like you had other ideas.
Let's just say that opening another trading post for my parents
isn't how I want to make my mark in this world.
DELAH: [sighs] I imagine travelling alone must be nice.
ALOY: So she's your partner?
DELAH: My apprentice … and my sister.
She's why we're out here.
There was was an incident …
ALOY: Involving explosives?
BOOMER: Ba-boom!
DELAH: …and Dad's precious homebrew.
He shipped us out the next day.
ALOY: Huh.
Saw a scroll when I was a kid
by some Carja scholar who wandered out west.
Had a scary drawing of a Tenakth warrior
hunting with a kind of javelin thrower.
DELAH: Effective? Yes. Basic? Undoubtedly.
But coming out here made me remember it.
And I am on the brink of vastly improving the tool's archaic design.
BOOMER: Whereas I will perfect it.
I can use machine parts to enhance the user's throw,
increase the projectile's velocity.
While Boomer here is adamant that enhancing the projectile is better.
DELAH: Namely with explosive tips.
BOOMER: Boomsticks!
ALOY: Why not both?
That … could work.
There's one small snag, I need the parts
to make the first working model.
BOOMER: Charger horns, intact.
Yeah, that.
Just be sure to shoot them off
before the machine goes down, otherwise they break.
But the real innovation is a Fanghorn rib.
BOOMER: There's a mean one east of here, blow it sky-high!
DELAH: Boomer!
You get them for me, it's yours, my treat.
You have a deal.
Boomer said that Fanghorn should be nearby.
There's the Fanghorn. Gonna have to take it down to get its rib.
Down it goes! Should be able to harvest its rib now.
Got the Fanghorn rib, now I just need the Charger horns.
There goes a horn!
Got everything I need for Delah and Boomer.
Now to see about that weapon of theirs.
Javad said the Bristlebacks were first spotted west of the quarry.
I should see if there's anything in the back of the valley.
Dead Bristleback, by the falls.
Better check it out.
That's strange. Parts of it have been tampered with.
Almost like an override.
Looks like it died on impact.
Maybe it charged off the cliff up there?
I'd better keep following the trail up.
An old mine.
And a lot of broken trees.
It's like a stampede went through.
Is this where the Bristlebacks came from?
But … how?
Unless…
This cave leads out of The Daunt?
Okay, let's see where this leads.
The old car tracks collapsed.
It looks recent.
Guess I'm not going that way.
There's smoke from deeper in the mine. An explosion?
Bristlebacks! I guess they got trapped here.
I'm gonna have to take them out before I can look around.
sometimes.
Okay, better take a look at where the smoke is coming from.
There's a lot of smoke.
It looks like the mine runs pretty far back.
[coughing] It's a dead end.
Bristlebacks must have collapsed these tracks, too.
That is a lot of blaze down there.
There's enough blaze here to blast a mountain open.
And there's a note on one of the barrels.
This note's addressed to Ulvund.
Looks like this mine was supposed to be shut down.
Ulvund must've gotten greedy,
kept blasting deeper into the mountain.
I should let Javad know what I've found.
So Ulvund was secretly blasting in the mine,
trying to squeeze it for all it's worth.
Until Bristlebacks stampeded through.
Maybe the explosions blew a way open? But from where?
LUF: It's not looking good, folks!
LUF: Oof! Them Shadow Carja are taking a beating!
ALOY: Those people are under attack.
ALOY: Hey, you up there! Aren't you gonna help?
LUF: Not my job. I'm just here
to keep an eye on things for Chainscrape.
LUF: Might as well call it quits!
Move.
LOKASHA: More machines on their way.
LUF: Oh! That's a nasty one.
CARJA: Go Lokasha, I'll help the Nora.
That's the last of them.
Better check on the refugees.
CARJA: Is it bad Lokasha?
LOKASHA: Ssh now, everything will be fine.
Is everyone ok?
Bruised but not buried.
LOKASHA: Our order will live to see another day.
ALOY: Are you sure about that?
LOKASHA: We're no strangers to hardship, Nora.
LOKASHA: We've crossed half the Sundom
with no more than the clothes on our backs.
LOKASHA: And as soon as our Sun-Priest returns,
our path will be clear.
LOKASHA: For now, we wait.
ALOY: Well, you're better off waiting somewhere else.
ALOY: Your people need shelter. There's a town east—
LOKASHA: Chainscrape. Yes, we know of it.
Savohar says it's not suitable for us.
ALOY: Who?
LOKASHA: Our Sun-Priest.
LOKASHA: Our order has made it this far thanks to his guiding light.
ALOY: Okay, and where is this Savohar?
He went up to the tower to meditate three days ago.
LOKASHA: And he won't come down until the Sun
shows him the way to our new home.
LOKASHA: The fallen Stormbird is an omen, he said.
ALOY: And how long do you plan on waiting for him?
LOKASHA: Until he returns.
LOKASHA: He will return.
ALOY: You're Shadow Carja, aren't you?
We are the Order of Twilight.
ALOY: The difference being?
When the usurper Avad killed his father,
we fled with the Carja in Shadow to Sunfall.
Our lives there were difficult.
Savohar saw our misery, lifted us up.
Protected us from the corrupt priests and heartless kestrels.
LOKASHA: When their rule ended,
Savohar led us from the shadowlands.
"The long night ends and the setting sun
will lead us to salvation," he said.
And so he named us the Order of Twilight.
LOKASHA: We journeyed west in search of a better life.
ALOY: Why didn't you go back to Meridian?
Avad is a patricide! We will not kneel to the likes of him.
We must walk in twilight to our new home.
ALOY: But shelter looks like a more pressing concern.
LOKASHA: His meditation can't be rushed.
ALOY: So he does this often, meditating for days on end?
Well, it doesn't usually take this long.
But he will guide us through.
He always has.
We have faith.
ALOY: There's an Oseram in Chainscrape, Tolland.
He wants the Stormbird up there.
Yes, he was here just yesterday.
A very unpleasant man, even by Oseram standards.
He made all manner of threats.
But we will not be intimidated.
That's all well and good, but he's got friends.
ALOY: Sooner or later, his whole gang will show up.
LOKASHA: Savohar will come through, he always does.
LOKASHA: We just need to give him more time.
ALOY: You're out of time, Lokasha!
ALOY: You need to consider packing up and—
LOKASHA: We won't leave him.
And we won't let others disrupt his meditation.
ALOY: Well, they're going to try.
ALOY: You're in danger here.
ALOY: You need to grab Savohar and get out.
Our situation … this is the worst we've endured.
LOKASHA: I know we cannot stay here,
but without Savohar to guide us I don't …
ALOY: Let me up there and I'll convince him it's time to move on.
But his meditation, if he hasn't received his vision, he won't follow.
At least let me check on him.
If he's been up there for days …
LOKASHA: Yes. Yes, that is sensible I suppose.
Please be careful.
LOKASHA: The trail up to the tower is falling apart.
Savohar is strong, but it could not have been an easy climb.
ALOY: It rarely is.
I should climb that.
Part of the ladder. Lokasha was right, the trail's in bad shape.
I think I can reach those beams if I jump against the cliff.
Okay, now how to climb higher?
Ladder must have broken off after Savohar passed through.
I need to find another way up.
Broken bridge.
I might be able to make the jump to the other side.
That's a lot of blood.
Savohar's?
He must have hurt himself pretty bad getting over the bridge.
It's not looking good.
It looks like he left a trail.
I can follow it with my Focus.
There's the Stormbird. Getting closer.
Machines. Savohar must have snuck past them.
I could probably slip past them.
Or take them out.
Yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah
That's all of them.
ALOY: There's Savohar, in pretty bad shape.
SAVOHAR: The true Sun before me.
SAVOHAR: Show me the way this eventide.
SAVOHAR: The true Sun above me.
ALOY: You must be Savohar.
SAVOHAR: The true Sun before me.
SAVOHAR: Show me the way this eventide.
No! No!
The vessel must be empty for the coming vision.
You don't need a vision, you need medical attention.
On the way up, I saw parts of the trail had given way.
ALOY: Is that how you hurt yourself?
My pain … all part of … the ritual.
You're hurt, bad, and your people are running out of time
Staring at the Stormbird isn't solving anything.
SAVOHAR: You don't understand the omen.
It fell … here … at the peak.
SAVOHAR: I just need to see the twilight path.
My people will find their home.
Listen, Lokasha is doing the best she can down there, but…
Machine attacks. Angry Oseram.
The order is scared, Savohar.
The last rays of the eventide will burn away their fear.
ALOY: What do you think is going to happen here?
If you sit long enough, the sun will show you something?
The path to a new home.
The fallen machine can only mean that…
…the storm has passed.
Our … salvation is at hand.
[sighs] Or some Oseram shot it and it hit an old tower.
The Sun will provide and I will not lose faith.
I'd be more concerned about losing blood.
ALOY: Look, I think you punctured a lung.
You can't heal it with prayer.
SAVOHAR: —Sun before me, show me the way this eventide.
ALOY: I think you've been staring at your salvation this whole time.
SAVOHAR: The true Sun above me,
SAVOHAR: The true Sun before me,
SAVOHAR: Show me the way this eventide.
That Stormbird heart is valuable,
enough to feed all the refugees waiting below.
And his answer is sunstroke and a prayer?
Why does every priest I meet think
blind faith is the answer to everything?
The Oseram that was watching the refugees
probably want to get Tolland.
I gotta get them out of here before he comes back.
There, the order should be able to afford shelter with this heart.
Some food and a change of clothes wouldn't hurt either.
Savohar?! How you holding up?
I need to get back over there.
I guess you did the best you could.
Rest easy now.
I'll make sure your people are safe.
I should let Lokasha know.
And give her the Stormbird heart.
LUF: Come on, don't make this difficult.
LUF: Get out of the way.
LOKASHA: No!
There's Tolland with his thugs.
LOKASHA: We will not yield.
We won't let you pass Oseram.
TOLLAND: I'm a generous gent.
TOLLAND: So I'll give you one more chance
to make it easy on yourselves and clear out.
LOKASHA: If you choose bloodshed, that's on your conscience.
Ain't it just like the Carja to make things harder than they have to be.
TOLLAND: Okay boys, you heard her. Get your "consciences" ready.
ALOY: Hold on now, Tolland.
You again?
TOLLAND: Listen, I'm all out of patience here.
TOLLAND: I clipped that Stormbird's wings.
TOLLAND: The salvage is mine!
I don't care who gets in my way.
Nora savages or Shadow Carja fleabags, I'm taking it.
You sure you want to do that, Tolland?
You know who I am.
What makes you think a single Oseram lunkhead can take me down?
I've got four guys!
I've got four guys, huh?
ALOY: From what I hear,
the law says that whoever gets the salvage first keeps it.
ALOY: Which in this case is me.
ALOY: Am I right?
You took the heart?!
I shot that Stormbird, me!
Am I right?
LUF: She's right, boss.
TOLLAND: Blast it, Luf, shut up!
ALOY: Might be hard to swallow,
but it's time to cut your losses, don't you think?
LUF: Come on, boss, it's not worth it.
TOLLAND: Okay, you win.
TOLLAND: Hey, I'm doing fine. I don't need that salvage anyhow.
TOLLAND: But these "people" need all the help they can get.
TOLLAND: Come on, boys. Back to Chainscrape.
TOLLAND: Back to Chainscrape. I need a drink.
LOKASHA: Again we thank you.
ALOY: You're welcome.
Now take this heart.
Use it to buy food, clothes, shelter for your people.
Maybe even land to build a new home.
LOKASHA: Savohar must make these decisions.
No, I'm–I'm sorry, Lokasha.
Savohar isn't coming back.
He's gone.
ALOY: I know it's hard, but your people need a leader now.
ALOY: Go to Chainscrape, talk to the forgewoman there, Petra.
Give her the Stormbird heart.
She'll look after you and your people
until you can get back on your feet.
Find your path.
LOKASHA: I'll do my best, Aloy.
LOKASHA: What choice do I have?
LOKASHA: Here, please accept this.
LOKASHA: It is modest, but I hope it helps in some small way.
To Chainscrape then.