ALOY: I will find Erend and I will help clear a path.
But after that, no more excuses.
Barren Light. Embassy.
VUADIS: If such be the will of the Sun.
It will be, trust me.
ALOY: You heard the whistle, time to go.
VUADIS: But I–I was supposed to have three escorts.
JORUF: I'm off to Barren Light, Vuadis.
Like Aloy said, Captain's orders. You can stay here.
Abandoned to the riff-raff? I think not!
JORUF: Guess you're coming with me then. See you there, Aloy!
DELAH: I know that look.
You've got all the parts, haven't you?
Here you go.
Outstanding!
I only need a few minutes to finish the prototype.
ALOY: I'll take the version that won't blow my arms off, thanks.
Hi.
So, did you blow up any machines to get the parts?
Or any bandits?
ALOY: You really like explosions, huh?
DELAH: Here we go.
BOOMER: With the boomsticks?
DELAH: Oh, you betcha.
ALOY: Um, is it safe?
DELAH: Probably.
BOOMER: Can I have one?
DELAH: No!
BOOMER: Aww.
DELAH: 'Cause we're going to make you something even better.
BOOMER: Ba-boom!
JAVAD: Saviour. What news do you bring?
Picked up the Bristleback trail by the quarry.
Looks like they stampeded out of the mine at the back of the valley.
The mine?
How could a herd of Bristlebacks come from there?
ALOY: I'm not sure.
ALOY: But Ulvund's workers were using
explosives to tap the tunnels inside.
JAVAD: For the love of Dawn, I told him it wasn't worth the risk.
Those tunnels, they run for miles underground,
even beyond The Daunt.
No, You don't think…
That Ulvund's blasting opened up a passage from the other side?
Perhaps. Yes, perhaps!
If this is true, we need confirmation.
An inquiry so thorough, so irrefutable, endorsed by the Saviour.
ALOY: Alright, I'll keep looking.
Sun light your path.
THURLIS: Come on, you can use that Tripcaster I gave you here.
THURLIS: I'll take care of this.
Thurlis.
So you decided to visit the hunting grounds.
Good on you.
Isvad here has all kinds of trials.
So hotshots like you can put their machine hunting skills to the test.
THURLIS: Or is th Tenakth call it, earning your stripes.
ALOY: I thought hunting grounds were Carja?
THURLIS: The Tenakth have them out west too.
THURLIS: Though if you ask the Carja,
Westerners stole the idea from the Sundom.
THURLIS: In fact, the Tenakth used this place for a while
after they kicked the Carja out of the region.
THURLIS: They even left behind some of the
special coins they handed out, to those who earned stripes.
Look, they're medals, Carja ones, more spoils.
I heard you can trade them for gear,
somewhere in the Tenakth clan lands.
Pretty gruesome, I know.
Then again, so were the Carja during the Red Raids.
THURLIS: Come to think of it, if you plan on going west,
I could convince Isvad to give you some.
THURLIS: If you earn stripes here.
THURLIS: Seems like they might be of use to you out there.
Thanks.
THURLIS: If you need anything for the trials, come see me.
THURLIS: I have some wares I'm sure you'd find handy.
THURLIS: You need the right gear if you're going hunting.
THURLIS: Take care, Red.
ISVAD: If you're looking for medals prized by Tenakth,
you can earn them here Saviour.
ISVAD: Oh, and I'd like you to have this, if you'd care to use it.
ISVAD: Consider it my thanks for getting Thurlis out of trouble.
ISVAD: Go down the ropes and I'll start timing you.
ISVAD: Everything's set up, just use the ropes to jump in.
ISVAD: This is yours, Saviour.
ISVAD: Grounds are all yours, just use the ropes to jump in.
ISVAD: A lot's changing in the world.
ISVAD: My duty is to these grounds.
ISVAD: This is yours, Saviour.
ISVAD: Until you return, Saviour.
Barren Light.
The last part of the Sundom before the Forbidden West.
[loud horn blares]
A Carja horn. Maybe that means the Embassy is starting soon.
Alright, I should find whoever is in charge here.
First, I could resupply at my stash.
Might be worth taking a look around too.
COOK: Friend from the Nora, come and buy!
Take it, enjoy it.
HERBALIST: Balms and herbs, here for sale.
STITCHER: Carja armour, to protect and to flatter.
There's Erend. It looks like he's had a few.
CONOVER: Saviour, I need your help!
CONOVER: SAVIOUR!
CONOVER: I beg you, Saviour, listen to me.
CONOVER: Saviour, you're my last hope.
YBRIL: Conover, she's Meridian's Saviour, not yours.
It's just Aloy.
What do you want?
Please, no-one will listen.
But the Eclipse, they're here in The Daunt.
Really, Conover? Aloy is the one that defeated them.
You're bothering her with this hogwash now?
CONOVER: Some of them must have fled west
after the battle at the Alight.
I saw one of our sentries, Laruvik, sneaking off to meet with one.
CONOVER: I tried to eavesdrop, but they spotted me.
CONOVER: And then Laruvik tried to kill me.
I …
… fought back.
It was him or me.
YBRIL: Unfortunately, there's no hard evidence
that connects Laruvik to the Eclipse.
YBRIL: And since Conover doesn't deny killing his fellow soldier,
Nozar sentenced him to death.
ALOY: What makes you so sure Laruvik was working with the Eclipse?
I was too far to hear everything,
but I heard them both say the word "eclipse".
YBRIL: It's not the most outlandish claim I've heard, but it's up there.
ALOY: Crying Eclipse is a convenient way to dodge a death sentence.
CONOVER: If I have to die, so be it.
But if we ignore this threat, others are going to die too.
ALOY: Tell me exactly what happened.
Weeks ago, during a shift change,
some trespassers slipped through the gate.
By the time anyone noticed they were halfway out the canyon.
Nozar didn't see the need to give chase.
"Let the Tenakth take care of them," he said.
YBRIL: Nozar's not one to be sidetracked.
He tightened up the patrol schedules,
reprimanded the sentries, and everyone moved on.
None of us are careless out here,
meaning someone left it open on purpose.
And Laruvik, well, he's always grumbling about officers.
But on this? He was too quiet.
He started acting different, jumpy.
So when I spotted him sneaking out
of the barracks after hours, I followed.
I found him arguing with a stranger.
And when Laruvik mentioned the Eclipse, I tried getting closer,
but they hurt me.
The stranger took off and Laruvik lunged at me with his knife.
Instincts took over.
Sentries heard the scuffle and found me standing over his body.
ALOY: Why don't you believe him?
YBRIL: We combed the woods, searched Laruvik's bunk,
searched it again, didn't find anything.
YBRIL: Look, Conover is a good man.
I don't believe he murdered Laruvik in cold blood.
YBRIL: But Nozar only listens to facts.
YBRIL: And that fact is Conover killed his fellow sentry.
YBRIL: He doesn't deny it, right?
CONOVOER: No, but more Eclipse are out there—
YBRIL: And considering there's no evidence
backing up this Eclipse story.
YBRIL: Well, we can't question a dead man.
YBRIL: Nozar's on edge with the upcoming Embassy,
and doesn't want distractions.
If you find a bunch of Eclipse soldiers hatching an evil plot
in the woods, please do let us know.
ALOY: The meeting you witnessed.
Did you hear anything else about their plans?
CONOVER: No. But the clearing where they met
is just east of here, across the river.
YBRIL: A dozen soldiers have already
searched it, Conover, there's nothing there.
ALOY: I can see things others can't.
YBRIL: It's a lost cause, Saviour.
We'll see.
CONOVER: Thank you, Aloy. Sun bless your search.
YBRIL: Don't get your hopes up, soldier.
This must be the clearing where Conover says he saw the eclipse.
Blood stains.
As a good place to start as any.
Pretty sure this is where Conover killed that guard.
Maybe my Focus can tell me if there really was a third person here.
I see plenty of tracks from the Carja search party, not helpful.
Broken branches.
Was someone up here?
Faint tracks.
Leading away from Barren Light.
I should be able to follow them with my Focus.
Let's see where this leads.
Maybe Conover wasn't lying after all.
Lost the trail, there's too many machines walking around.
Maybe I can pick up the tracks once I'm past them.
Uh-oh, I've been spotted.
Should be easy to follow the trail up ahead now.
Blood, a lot of it.
Whoever the runner was, this machine must have slashed him.
Should be easy to follow the blood trail with my Focus.
Looks like they're headed for that bridge.
Bandages. Looks like the runner tried
to treat their wounds before they went on.
Should be able to follow their tracks.
Where did you go off to?
The trail ends here, must have climbed up to that cave.
With that injury I'll bet he's on his last legs.
I'll save this for a dyer.
This looks like a good place for someone to hide.
ECLIPSE: He's dead! What're we supposed to do now?
ECLIPSE: We stay on track and make our way out west.
ECLIPSE: If we give up now, the usurper wins.
We have to find Vezreh.
ECLIPSE: In his shadow we will find strength.
ECLIPSE: I say we kill the lot.
ECLIPSE: Take on a whole garrison? Won't be easy.
ECLIPSE: We don't know Laruvik's dead.
ECLIPSE: He hasn't shown at the rendezvous point.
ECLIPSE: So either that fool guard killed him or he's lost his nerve.
ECLIPSE: We'll just have to blast our way through the gates.
ECLIPSE: And then what? Rayad was our only link to Vezreh.
And now he's dead too.
LIEUTENANT: We'll track Vezreh if we have to.
LIEUTENANT: But first we have to get past Barren Light.
LIEUTENANT: Next change of guard we go in fast and loud.
ALOY: Conover was right.
ALOY: I have to stop them before they hurt anyone else.
ECLIPSE: What if Laruvik talked and they know we're coming?
ECLIPSE: What if I stick this knife down your throat?
ECLIPSE: Save it for the heretics.
ECLIPSE: If only we'd caught up with Vezreh earlier.
ECLIPSE: No use crying about it now.
ECLIPSE: Soon we will march on the east, and all will fall.
ECLIPSE: You really think Vezreh has found
a new place for us out west?
ECLIPSE: He knows what he's doing, I'm sure of it.
ECLIPSE: I am the shadow and the darkn—.
ECLIPSE: The west is a deadly land. A fine place to forge our destiny.
ECLIPSE: Vezreh will lead us to glory. And revenge.
ECLIPSE: A new empire will rise and I will be one of his leaders.
That takes care of that.
It sounds like there's more eclipse beyond The Daunt.
If this Rayad was their only link to them, he might have a Focus.
It could tell me where they are.
I'm guessing that's Rayad.
Blood trail must've been his.
He bled out trying to get here.
I was right, Rayad has a Focus.
VEZREH: Loyal Eclipse.
VEZREH: If you're seeing this, it means
you've left the Sundom in search of something to follow.
VEZREH: Your journey is almost over.
VEZREH: Follow the Sun beyond the gates of Barren Light.
VEZREH: And bask in the glow of future conquest.
VEZREH: A new empire awaits!
There's co-ordinates here.
I'll have to pay this Vezreh a visit,
and crush his new Eclipse empire before it begins.
Rayad's mask should be enough to prove Conover's innocence.
I'd better take it back to Barren Light.
When we fought the Eclipse back in Meridian,
I thought that'd be the end of it.
Guess I was wrong.
KERUF: Saviour! Excuse me!
Ah Saviour! Tell me, are you seeking passage
into No Man's Land by any chance?
Maybe. Why do you ask?
Ah well, to hammer it plain there's treasure out west.
Unclaimed scrap and ancient metal.
KERUF: And I've got a sturdy band of salvagers
that knows the lay of the land.
You're not afraid of the Tenakth?
Heh, terrified! But I carry out most of my business in No Man's Land.
Neutral territory and all that.
KERUF: Barren Light is our port of entry…
…when its doors aren't closed for an Embassy.
I was hoping your arrival meant they might be opening soon?
I've got a business to run after all.
I want that Embassy to happen as much as you do.
Believe me, I'm working on it.
Good to know … and keep us in mind.
If you do manage to open the way,
our main camp will be just past Barren Light.
We'll buy any scrap you've got on you.
And if you're looking for machine parts,
we've got the best in the west guaranteed.
Alright, maybe later then.
If you can get those blasted gates open!
Guess I'm not the only one who wants to get those gates open.
YBRIL: Look alive, soldier. She's back.
Did you find anything?
Eclipse fugitives were camped out on the other side of the forest.
ALOY: And they were getting ready
to fight their way through Barren Light.
You just helped save a lot of lives.
Aloy, you know I believe you, but Nozar?
He might not be convinced by your words alone.
If he needs proof, show him that.
ALOY: And tell him the man he's got locked up
risked his life to expose and eliminate an Eclipse spy.
Huh, I guess you are his saviour.
YBRIL: Congratulations, soldier, you're a free man.
I'll have you out of there before sunfall.
I'll make sure this gets to Nozar.
That's it then. The end of the Eclipse.
Almost.
The tresspassers you mentioned?
The ones who got through Barren Light weeks ago?
ALOY: Their leader is dangerous.
ALOY: And he's out there in the Forbidden West building up an army.
CONOVER: Sun in shadow, you're going
out there to stop them, aren't you?
I'm gonna try.
CONOVER: I want to help. I can fight!
ALOY: I know you can, but you've been through a lot.
Once you're out of that cell you should enjoy your freedom.
You've earned it.
CONOVER: Take them out, Saviour.
ALDUR: That'll just give me more suffering come morning.
ALDUR: I can barely limp.
EREND: You keep saying things,
but all I'm hearing is a lack of determination.
Gentlemen.
ALDUR: That's our cue.
ALOY: Taking the edge off?
EREND: Well, if the end of the world is coming.
I don't want to be sober for it.