The lesson lives within the question, Aloy.
For years, you've trained to win the Proving.
But only for yourself.
As a Brave, it will be your duty to fight for your tribe.
My tribe?
You said I wouldn't need them.
But I never said the tribe wouldn't need you.
Dawn has passed.
This will be your last day in the Embrace as an outcast.
Use the time to set your mind
on the challenges before you.
When it is time for you to go to Mother's Heart
I will be waiting for you on the way.
I understand the final lesson Rost.
Do you?
But if I am going to stand for something
it'll have to be something I believe in.
Then I hope you find it, Aloy.
I hope you do.
[whistles]
This'll last.
[in distance]
Brom! It's your sister Olara!
It's heavy, world's growing white.
[in distance]
Are you out there?
Who are you calling out for?
Do you need help?
I have nothing against outcasts,
far from it.
But I shouldn't talk to you.
I don't want to get in trouble.
I don't see anyone else around to help.
I guess you're right.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to be callous.
My brother was cast out but his sentence has ended…
He should have come home, but he didn't and…
Each day I cut a notch on the wall
so I knew Brom's sentence was over.
Then I cut three more.
But he still hadn't come back.
I begged the Matriarchs to send Braves to find him
and all they found was a blood-soaked camp.
The Braves said he must be dead.
But I have to know the truth.
So I came out looking for him.
All I can think about is what might've happened.
Is he really dead?
Or maybe just wounded?
Is he suffering?
Does he need help?
I can't stand it not knowing.
Why was your brother cast out?
Brom was always a little different.
A little touched.
One of the hunters had a cruel heart
and never let him alone.
I was gone but an hour.
The hunter set after him like always but this time…
Brom struck back with a rock
and split the man's skull.
Spirits made him do it he said.
Whispers of the Forgotten.
What do you mean "Forgotten"?
All-Mother curses blasphemers who won't repent.
Banishing them from Her eternal memory.
Those lost spirits are the Forgotten.
Brom used to say they spoke to him,
told him to do things.
It was such a burden for him
and there was nothing I could do to help.
I'll do what I can to find your brother.
You will?
Then let me come with you, I won't be a bother.
I know how to stay out of sight.
I'm faster on my own.
If that is how it must be.
Just find him then.
Please.
This must be Brom's camp.
Better clear out those Watchers.
Blood but no body.
There's gotta be more to this.
Looks like a few drops of blood
lead away from the camp.
Whose knife is this?
Did someone attack Brom with it?
Looks like more blood leading away from here.
There, a bucket.
Did someone bring the blood to the camp?
The trail of blood ends here.
But whoever left it must've also left tracks.
Snow. It's not getting any warmer out here.
Got one!
That's … twisted.
I wonder if the blood from the camp
came from this boar?
If Brom did this…
why does he want people to think he's dead?
And why desecrate the shrine?
Hmm, what are those Scrappers picking at?
Looks like it was a Watcher.
Whoever I'm following made short work of it.
If it's Brom, he definitely knows
how to handle a spear.
Someone looted these supplies.
Brom was an outcast for a long time.
Why take food and gear now?
It's the supplies from the cache.
Why would they take them
and then just throw them away?
[in distance]
I'll kill myself!
I'll kill myself before I hurt her!
[in distance]
I won't listen!
Aaah! Not until you promise.
[in distance]
She's my sister! My sister!
I need to protect her.
I will, I'll kill myself.
I'll kill myself before I hurt her.
You? You're not a spirit.
What do you want?
I want you to step away from the edge Brom.
No!
Leave me alone!
Can't you see I need time to think?
How am I supposed to think
when everybody is shouting at me?
So many voices to listen to.
Must make your head hurt.
I promise my voice will be soft and soothing.
A soft voice like Olara's.
It's been so long.
Years.
Yes.
Yes, I … I will listen.
That's better.
Now tell me what's troubling you?
Spirits of the Forgotten.
Souls cursed by the All-Mother.
Their voices never let me be.
They want me to do things.
Hurt people.
If I go back to the Nora they might make me hurt Olara.
And I'll kill myself before I let that happen.
Do you have to listen to the spirits Brom?
They're speaking to me right now.
Always with me.
They take care of me. Keep me company.
Help me, except when they scream.
Like when that hunter knocked me down.
"Crush his skull with a rock!" they said.
And I did.
Brom! You're alive!
All-Mother be praised!
I'm sorry I followed you.
But I had to make sure he was alright.
No! No no no no no! No!
Please sister, I can't protect you!
I need no protection from you Brom.
How can you be certain?
The voices he hears call for blood,
even yours.
But surely he wouldn't hurt his own sister?
I've taken care of him since I was six.
Brom isn't ready to return to the Nora.
But I don't think he'll hurt you, Olara.
There's a place where I can stay.
A cave on All-Mother Mountain.
I suppose you could visit me there?
So long as I'm strong.
You will be Brom.
I'll help you.
Thank you, Aloy. I'll take care of him now.
May you walk in All-Mother's eternal memory.
And may the Forgotten leave you be.
I'll find a use for you.
Keep quiet now.
[in distance]
I need to speak to you.
I'm injured, I need your help.
You want to talk to an outcast?
I'm desperate for help.
Whatever the consequences.
You know the Matriarchs might cast you out
for speaking to me, don't you?
I don't care.
What's the problem then?
Trouble with your leg?
Forget about me, it's my daughter Arana.
She's in danger.
She went after a Scrapper up near Mother's Cradle.
I fear for her life.
Why would your daughter hunt a Scrapper on her own?
It's my fault.
I went after it first, and it tore up my leg.
I barely got away,
and I left a spear impaled in the machine.
That spear was made by Edena, my mate.
Who died last year.
It means everything to Arana.
She went after the Scrapper to get it back.
I'll accept any punishment if it means she's safe.
Please. Help me set things right.
I'll do what I can to help your daughter.
Make sure she's alright.
I'm begging you.
That must be Arana.
Sounds like she's in trouble.
[in distance]
I'm stuck up here!
I can't get down! Help!
[in distance]
Can I talk to you for a minute?
I just want to thank you.
Thank you.
I thought those watchers were going to tear me apart.
Your father sent me after you.
It's time to go home.
I figured.
But I can't go back until I get
my mother's spear from that Scrapper!
That spear must mean a lot to you.
My mother made it not long before she died.
I can't believe my father lost it.
He didn't mean to.
Scrappers are dangerous.
I know.
I just can't stand the idea that it might be gone forever.
Your father is worried sick about you.
He gets worried if I go ten steps to relieve myself in the bushes.
He just…
He doesn't want to lose you Arana.
I know.
But I do wish he wouldn't yell at me so much.
How did you wind up in that tree?
I tracked the Scrapper to Mother's Cradle.
Caught a glimpse of it too,
but then a Watcher saw me and called his pack.
By All-Mother, I'm just not a good enough
hunter to get that spear back am I?
I'll look for your spear.
You will? Oh thank you!
Go find your father.
His leg gave out while he was searching for you,
just south of Mother's Heart.
Oh no!
Okay, I'll go to him right away!
Thanks again.
Arana's trail ends here.
Must be where she saw the Scrapper.
If I follow its tracks I should be able to find that spear.
Mother's Cradle.
The trail ends here.
I'll bet it crossed the river.
Better check the other side.
There! Time to get that spear.
A well-made weapon.
Arana will be happy to have it back.
What is it now?
Always a pleasure doing business.
I guess that concludes our business.
All right. Good luck in the Proving.
Blessing of All-Mother and all that.
Let's do this!
It'd be fascinating, if they weren't looking for me.
Back to your business.
Gonna need this.
[in distance]
All-Mother be praised!
Aloy's back with the spear.
First you send Arana back to me.
And now you've got the spear.
When I first called out to you for help,
I didn't even know if you'd speak to me.
I'm glad you did.
Me too.
I can't believe you got the spear back!
Your mother knew how to craft them.
It's of exceptional make.
I'll never be the crafter she was,
but she did pass along a few tricks.
I'd be happy to take a look at your spear.
Thank you.
It sounds like she was special.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Because of you I still have the spear
to remember her by.
You didn't have to help us but you did.
She would've admired that.
Thank you, Aloy.
For everything.