Ever since the War Party massacre our lands go unpatrolled
and our borders unguarded.
We have no War-Chief to lead us.
Isn't that Resh's job?
Ugh.
Before you make the journey to Mother's Crown and beyond.
Is there any chance you could search for Sona?
Where was she last seen?
The War Party massacre site.
A wooded hollow across from Devil's Thirst on this side of the river.
You might be able to pick up her trail there.
If she went after the killers who attacked the Proving,
who killed those we love,
who tried to kill you…
I get it Varl.
I'll see what I can do.
My whole life, all of it in the Embrace.
The world just got bigger.
But also more dangerous.
[whistle]
A Nora village, up on the heights.
The say she fought beside Bast and Vala.
Surely you have other things to do beside talk to me?
You're Aloy aren't you?
They say you've been made a Seeker
with right of passage from the Sacred Lands.
Yes, to track the killers who attacked the Proving.
I can't image leaving All-Mother's protection.
But my sister Nakoa is like you.
Fearless.
She went north to find a Carja officer called Zaid.
Did the Matriarchs really give Nakoa permission to leave?
No. They refused her.
But nothing could stop her from going after Zaid.
He…
For ten years the Carja attacked without warning.
Devils like Zaid butchered Braves
and kidnapped civilians for blood sacrifice.
It all ended when the Mad Sun-King died.
The Matriarchs say his son wants to set things right.
But that wasn't enough for Nakoa.
He murdered our father during the Red Raids.
Nakoa saw it happen.
Hid in the cellar and forced herself to watch.
He changed her.
You could've gone with her?
Leave the Sacred Land and be purged from All-Mother's eternal memory? No!
I begged Nakoa to stay so she could avoid that fate.
She said she didn't care.
I don't know.
Will she really be cursed for avenging our father?
Seems … cruel.
I'm really worried about her.
I'll keep an eye out for her.
All-Mother bless you!
I know the Matriarchs won't let her return to the Sacred Land, but…
I just need to know that she's alright.
She must've passed through Mother's Crown.
My aunt Solai lives there. They might've spoken.
Maybe she can tell you more.
All-Mother, hear my prayer.
I kneel before you low and humble.
Pleading for strength and understanding.
Can you see beyond your sacred domain?
Does your eternal memory encompass the world?
If it does, watch over her. Be with her.
That Brave, sounds like he's suffering.
He was one of the War Party.
Wounded in battle down the ridge there.
He was too weak to be carried back to Mother's Heart.
So they brought him here.
Could you see the ambush from here?
I heard it.
Explosions and screams and …
… howls of machines, like monsters.
That's what he keep groaning and muttering about.
Machines like nightmares, ripping everyone to shreds.
I've seen people die before.
But never in such pain.
I want to be strong like you, but…
I take it you know who I am?
I do.
I know a lot of people didn't want you in the Proving.
But if you hadn't been there, everyone would've died.
Shows how much we know.
The very person we needed was someone the tribe never wanted.
I wish I could borrow some of your courage now. For him.
You don't need to borrow what you already have.
Nothing I do comforts him.
I don't even have any Dreamwillow to ease his pain.
There should be some in stashes along Brave Trails to the east, but…
I must keep vigil for this man.
I'll check the stashes for Dreamwillow if I get a chance.
You will? Thank you!
My only wish is to ease this poor man's suffering.
This must be where the War Party got massacred.
Such destruction.
Maybe the War-Chief left something behind.
Some clue as to where she went.
Lots of machines, all controlled by the killers.
They sent a stampede of them down the slope.
The Nora managed to take down a Corruptor.
But not before the killers used it to send the other machines against them.
[in the distance]
Brave, let us speak!
Scraps of food.
The killers rested here before springing the trap.
Lunch before a bloodbath.
Monsters.
You there!
The dead and wounded all cleared away.
Are there no more Braves or Healers here?
Just me.
You're hurt, what happened?
What didn't? It's madness out there.
War-Chief Sona sent me back to report.
I'm no good to her like this.
Varl told me that the War-Chief tracked the killers.
Did she find them?
We followed their trail but again and again
they sent corrupted machines to attack us.
My wounds started to slow me down.
So the War-Chief sent me back
to let others know she hasn't given up the fight.
So, you were here when the War Party was ambushed?
I was.
I thought after the Proving there could be no darker day.
But I was wrong.
The War-Chief was delayed gathering the rear guard.
Eager for revenge the Braves in the lead fell into the trap.
Dozens lost in minutes.
If Sona hadn't arrived and rallied us
no-one would've survived.
Varl sent me to look for Sona.
Do you know where she is now?
All I can tell you is where we parted.
Near the metal tower
south-east of the ruins at Devil's Thirst.
Look to the rise behind it with a lone boulder.
I'll head for the Embrace
and report what I know to Varl and the others.
May All-Mother lend you strength.
You'll need it, going alone.
My Focus is picking up some kind of signal.
Maybe I can scan it.
That signal, where is it coming from?
Those ruins, that must be Devil's Thirst.
A city of the Old Ones.
Of the Metal World.
A Tallneck.
Looks just like Rost described.
The signal must be coming from it's head.
I need to get up there.
Oh, come on!
Ha ha!
I think I can leap onto the Tallneck from here.
Alright, now I just have to reach it's head.
Just give me a moment and I'll be off your back.
So the Tallneck remembers everything along it's path,
and sends what it sees to other machines.
[flashback]
All I can tell you is where we parted.
Near the metal tower south-east of the ruins of Devil's Thirst.
[flashback]
Look to the rise behind it with a lone boulder.
This must be the rise Sona's runner told me about.
Dressings for wounds.
They must've taken a moment to rest.
Arrow shards.
That old bow has seen a lot of action.
A recent kill, freshly skinned.
The War-Chief stopped here.
So where did she go next?
Couldn't have been easy going on after the ambush.
The runner wasn't the only one who got hurt.
Might be a blood trail I could follow.
I should try my Focus.
Tracks.
Boots and blood.
Looks like Sona and her Braves headed for that ridge.
A dead Sawtooth.
Maybe Sona took it out.
She could be close.
You're lucky I happen by.
One heartbeat more and that Sawtooth would've torn you apart.
Half a heartbeat more and I would've killed it myself.
Er, so you're War-Chief Sona?
Varl asked me to find you.
Has he held the gate?
He has, bravely.
I saw him kill a corrupted machine himself.
But he worries for you.
Our tribe needs strength, not sentiment.
I've tracked some of the killers who struck the Proving.
I crave vengeance, do you?
You have no idea.
Show me then. Lend me your strength.
Follow.
[Sona]
The killers are just across this ridge.
Digging the cursed earth.
The sin of the ancients is buried in that soil.
Corruptor demons.
[Aloy]
I know of them.
I killed one at Mother's Watch.
[Sona]
A bold claim. I wonder if you'll live up to it.
Hours ago I sent Braves into hiding in the trees below.
On my signal they'll attack.
The enemy and their demonic machines outnumber us.
But we will have fury on our side.
We could have more than that.
Explain?
That's blaze. What we use to burn they use to blast.
It's how they dug out this pit.
So we put fire to it and then?
Boom.
Then let us begin.
Whoa, wait. Let's not rush.
Give me some time to make an approach.
If I end up alerting them, open fire.
Alright. Let's see what you can do.
[in the distance]
Who's body is that?
Farewell!
[Cultist]
Show no mercy!
Follow my lead!
[Cultist]
Blast!
Finish this!
[Nora Brave]
Picking my target now!
An easy shot!
This wasn't all the killers.
I counted more at the War Party massacre.
If I have to chase their filthy shadows
from here to Spear's Reach, I will.
You're hurt. Losing blood.
My health is not your concern.
No-one doubts your determination but you need rest.
She's right War-Chief. Give your wounds time to close.
Varl!
What are you doing here?
I ordered you to hold that gate with your life.
And so I did.
Until the runner you sent retruned with news of his encounter with Aloy.
And your location.
I left the gate well guarded.
My place is here with you.
With our vengeance.
Am I not owed that?
Maybe I should have a look around.
See if I can figure out where the rest of the killers are.
Do are you wish.
Everyone else does.
Mother!
Commanders.
Over the past month accidental Blaze explosions have a killed a dozen men.
Here in the Ring of Metal I've taken the precaution
of placing our entire stockpile in a covered shelter,
safe from stray sparks and lightning.
And I've posted guards to control access.
I urge you to take similar measures.
Or suffer the consequences.
Supply Master Thiran out.
A Blaze stockpile inside their base.
Sabotage that and we win.
I've found something.
The rest of the killers are camped inside a "ring of metal".
Any idea what that means?
Damn them!
The Ring of Metal lies in the ruins of Devil's Grief.
That ground is taboo.
I will return to the Matriarchs,
beg them to make an exception.
There's no time for that.
Blood spilled calls for blood spilled!
If the ground is cursed, then let our vengeance sanctify it.
You blaspheme!
Please, War-Chief. Break the taboo!
Devil's Grief is a cursed place.
But maybe Aloy's Seeker blessing can protect us.
I'll send scouts ahead.
Our force will assemble at the cliff above Red Echoes.
And launch our attack from there.
Sounds like a plan.
See you there.
Aloy…
…thank you.
You might take that back, when you see what I'm getting us into.
On to Devil's Grief then.
Full already.
Handy!
I can get out of this.
That's it, I'm already gone.
This'll help.
Safe, for a few minutes anyway.>>>>
There!
Gotta keep the upper hand.
Uh, right.
Now what're we doing?