The rest of the killers are camped inside a "ring of metal".
Blood spilled calls for blood spilled
If the ground is cursed, then let our vengeance sanctify it.
You blaspheme!
Please, War-Chief. Break the taboo!
Devil's Grief is a cursed place.
But maybe Aloy's Seeker blessing can protect us.
I'll send scouts ahead.
Our force will assemble at the cliff above Red Echoes.
And launch our attack from there.
Devil's Grief.
Foreboding sight, huh?
Don't you ever wonder what it used to look like?
Back when the Old Ones lived here?
You're not like other Nora.
That's what they tell me.
War-Chief.
Our scouts found enemy camps in the ruins,
guarding the approach to the Ring of Metal.
Then we should hit those camps first.
Make sure they stay quiet.
Agreed.
Wipe out the camps and our enemies
in the Ring of Metal won't see us coming.
I'll take out the alarms
We'll send Braves to each camp to lie in wait.
What you start, they'll help finish.
[Sona]
Braves!
It is time.
[Sona]
Time to fight!
Time to kill!
[Sona]
Maybe time to die.
We will regroup there, at the base of the tallest tower.
[Sona]
Then to the Ring of Metal and vengeance!
Today we break taboo to honour our dead and punish our enemies!
[Sona]
Blood spilled for blood spilled!
[cheers]
[Sona]
May All-Mother forgive our trespass.
And if not, may she lay her wrath solely upon me.
[Sona]
Now, to battle.
[cheers and whooping]
You're taking this pretty well.
The trespassing on tainted lands thing, I mean.
You think so?
I feel like that silly Carja priest at the Blessing,
quaking under his hood.
[laughs]
That night already feels like a lifetime ago.
You know, we weren't really close, Vala and I.
Always competing for our mother's respect, I guess.
Well, you have mine if it makes any difference.
Thanks.
It does.
But this battle? I'm not doing this for respect.
Yours, or my mother's.
I'm doing it for Vala.
I know she would have done the same for me.
Time to strike.
We'll follow your lead.
That's got their attention.
[in the distance]
Victory for All-Mother!
For the Sacred Land! For the Nora!
Corruption hurts my skin.
About to get made.
Look at this!
Ah, she went that-a-way!
[in the distance]
Something up there?
By the Goddess, get down!
[in the distance]
You will not escape me!
[Nora Brave]
All-Mother be praised!
We are all Braves today.
[Nora Brave]
Sweet victory.
The hunt is over.
[Nora Brave]
We have what we need here.
[in the distance]
Wait, he said. Can't be an instrument of shadow…
Okay,
[Cultist]
You cannot escape our hands!
[in the distance]
Here we are!
[Nora Brave]
Fear the Nora!
[Cultist]
I'm after the signal.
[Nora Brave]
Signal fires are death traps.
Haven't you got anything better to do?
[Cultist]
Eyes up!
She's trying to get over on us!
[Nora Brave]
We did it!
Victory for All-Mother!
[Nora Brave]
Keep them in your sights.
[sounds of fighting]
[Nora Brave]
All-Mother guide me.
We're finished here.
I'll find a use for you.
The camps have been dealt with, now to the Ring of Metal.
Its high walls protect the enemy.
We'll have to scale the height under fire if were detected.
I have another idea.
Their base has a weakness.
Send me in alone and I'll exploit it.
If I'm successful, I'll blow a hole in those walls
big enough for the entire War Party to charge through.
Sounds like a plan.
So long as I get to come with you.
A War-Chief should be grateful for two arrows
so eager to spring from the bow.
Yes Varl, go with Aloy as her spear mate.
But … be vigilant.
Yes, War Chief, I will.
Go now.
We wait on your signal.
[Varl]
You do have a plan, right?
[Aloy]
You followed me this far, even into the ruins.
I thought you trusted me.
[Varl]
I do. But how would you know that this base has a weakness?
[Aloy]
Patience, Varl.
We'll know soon enough.
[Aloy]
Up you go.
Take my hand.
[Varl]
Take the one on the right.
[Aloy]
I'll take the one on the left.
[Cultist]
What?
[Varl]
Two more. You take the one on the left.
There.
See their covered shelter?
Do you see those Corruptors?
Focus, Varl. That shelter is full of Blaze.
The whole stockpile of it.
If I set it off.
The explosion will destroy those Corruptors
and collapse the wall, too.
A breach for the Nora to charge through.
Can't hit it from here, though.
We'll need to get closer.
I'll get closer.
You head back.
Tell Sona the plan and lead them to that side of the ring.
I'll see it done.
And wen the wall collapses, I'll be first through the breach.
Now all I have to do is make it all happen.
If I can do this quietly, it'll be a lot easier.
Just need to get an angle on that Blaze and shoot it.
Spotted!
I'm spotted, I need to get to that Blaze, fast!
[Cultist]
Time to die!
[war cries]
[Nora Brave]
Watcher!
[Cultist]
I'll take you down.
Shoot at me?
[Cultist]
Got one right here!
I see 'em!
[Cultist]
Don't let it end like this, fight!
[Varl]
All-Mother, look upon our victory.
A debt of blood is paid.
Remember this day, brave Nora.
[Sona]
From your lips to the Goddess' ears.
Yes, remember it.
[cheering]
Be ready to leave this place.
Let your spears and arrows rest in the bodies of the fallen.
They are tainted.
Like these ruins.
[Aloy]
It's over.
They won't be able to kill again.
The killers, this corruption…
They're all parts of the mystery I'm chasing.
Where the trail leads, I go.
Lucky me!
Just stay out of their way for now.
Nutritious.
And one of these…
Got you!
[flashback]
Whatever the corruption is, it doesn't just affect machines.
It burns flesh and sickens the injured.
[flashback]
Do the corrupted machines have any weaknesses?
Fire seems to affect them more than ordinary machines.
[flashback]
A small mercy.
This is where it ends,
Not much gets past them.
The flames, they're burning it!
Flames burn stronger than usual.
Those machines.
You can see the corruption coming off them like smoke.
Time to clear them out.
It'd be fascinating, if they weren't looking for me.
Keep quiet now.
A Vantage.
I wonder what it will show?
Apocashitstorm Tour, day five.
Gray Swarms opened for Turtle Smash the night I OD'd here.
Or so the police report said, anyway.
I was 15 years old.
When I woke in the hospital, two days later…
your face was the first thing I saw.