[whistle]
Uh-oh, spotted!
My Focus is picking up some kind of signal.
Maybe I could scan it.
[whistle]
I must be closing in on the signal.
[flashback]
A "cauldron". What's that?
Ah, you're from inside the Embrace, so you've never seen one.
[flashback]
A cauldron is a sort of door, I guess.
No one knows what lies beyond.
A Cauldron!
There's gotta be a way in, somehow.
Quite a door.
The metal, the light.
It's like this entire place is part of some huge machine.
But who made it?
That thing looks like a triangular pipe.
What's it for?
That might give me some cover if I need it.
Those things are moving components around.
I wonder where?
That thing near the gap.
What does it do?
Oh, very helpful.
It looks like those flying machines move components around.
Might be able to take me somewhere.
Might regret this!
That's the heart of it all, it's gotta be.
So how do I get inside?
I've gone as far as this thing will take me.
You're down, the others haven't noticed.
Almost to the heart.
Need them soon enough.
This is how machines are made.
Woven out of light.
There are signals coming from all over the place.
That machine's not gonna let me tinker with this stuff.
Information about different machines.
This will help me override them!
So machines are built in places like this.
But why?