Varl told me you'd know the way to Meridian.
The Carja capital? West will take you to it.
But their soldiers will stop you long before you get there.
They can try.
No, what I mean is there's a Carja fort
that guards the pass between east and west.
Word is the Carja have sealed the gate,
out of fear of the corrupted machines infesting our Sacred Land.
The Carja call the place Daytower.
It's not far from the forsaken village.
Save these for the trail.
Grazers. I can override them if I don't spook them.
Scrappers. Happy to find salvage, as always.
Here we go again.
Gotta switch weapons.
[Carja merchant]
Come on, I don't have many shards and lives are on the line.
[Banuk]
You're right. Mine if I go looking for your friends.
So pay up or shut up.
[Carja merchant]
But without these explosive arrows they'll be torn to shreds.
[Banuk]
Not my problem.
Unless someone wants to pay me to pick up the pieces.
[Carja merchant]
How could you be so cold?
[Banuk]
Where I come from that's a compliment.
See you around.
Sounds like you have friends in danger.
Employees, not friends.
A caravan on its way to trade with the Banuk
along a trail that swarms with machines,
Scrappers and Longlegs from what I hear.
But there have been stories of something worse.
Something that strikes with no warning.
Without explosive arrows, they won't stand much of a chance.
Why would they leave their best ammunition behind?
I don't know.
Marzavid, the caravan boss, isn't the sort of man to make mistakes.
I brought the crate hoping to catch them here.
I barely got past the border before the commander sealed the gates.
For me to track them deeper into the wilds would be suicide.
Especially with those corrupted machines infesting the land.
If I come across the caravan, I'll do what I can to help.
Well, that's more than any of the worthless bums
hanging about this dungpit offered.
Here, take the ammunition I stockpiled for the caravan.
You're sure to need it.
And may the Sun shine upon you.
[crowd member]
I've hunted machines for so long.
I don't know what to think of a place where they're peaceful.
[crowd member]
Curiosities.
It looks like Lubavad's men had to abandon some of their goods.
Lubavad's men must have killed these Watchers.
I hope they haven't run into anything worse.
You there!
I hope you've come to help because we're getting slaughtered out here.
Lubavad sent me after you.
Oh, I see.
And did he happen to tell you why he packed us a crate
of Ridge-Wood instead of decent ammunition?
Three waves of Watchers and Scrappers so far,
and worse to come.
Without that ammo, we're good as dead.
He said you left the ammunition behind.
Then the old fool has gone cross-eyed.
Every crate we loaded, I checked twice.
The glyph said ammunition.
But when we opened it, it was full of Ridge-Wood shafts and nothing but.
I have the ammunition with me. Enough for everyone.
By the Sun, we might just stand a chance after all.
Alarms! Longleg approaching!
To arms! To arms!
Come on, then.
[in the distance]
There's more machines! Scrappers!
I'd have to leave something else behind.
You fight well, outlander.
I'm surprised Lubavad was willing to pay for someone of your skill.
He didn't pay me, actually.
I did this for free.
Never trust a Carja merchant.
Boss! The Songcores are gone.
What?
That's impossible.
Unless … unless Dirid took them.
When the first wave hit us, one of the men ran off. Dirid.
I thought he was a coward.
Turns out he's a thief too.
He couldn't have gotten far.
True, but we're in no shape to go after him.
Then I'll get him for you.
But this time I get paid.
Quick learner, eh. Fine.
Bring those Songcores back and you've got a deal.
Hello Dirid.
Who are you?
The caravan sent me.
Caravan? What caravan?
The one you sabotaged.
You figured no explosive arrows meant no survivors.
No witnesses to your crime.
Look, stranger, I have debts.
If I don't pay, the dicers will gouge out my eyes.
The caravan.
Did they live?
Yes.
I got to them in time.
Thank you.
As I turn
and embrace the Sun
my He burn away
my sins.
What a waste.
At least he died better than he lived.
Never know when I might need these.
You're back.
And with the Songcores I see.
And Dirid?
A Stalker got him. It wasn't pretty.
And you beat a Stalker.
That's worth a bonus.
Here, take my share.
You've earned it.
I'll see to the caravan from here.
I think the rest of the trip will go smoother.
Not gonna be a problem overriding that Lancehorn.
Catching it, though.
[whistle]
It's off!
No room.
I know how to override a Sawtooth, if I can get in close.
[whistle]
It'd be fascinating if they weren't looking for me.
All right!
I dropped it!
Gonna need this!
Didn't catch.
I'd have to ditch something.
Just stay out of their way for now.
Should have brought a cart.
This will do nicely.
Keep that for later.
An old gate, broken long ago.
So this was the Nora border before the war with the Carja.
The Carja fort, looks solid.
A little too solid to talk my way past.
No passage west, and no exceptions!
So long as corrupted machines prowl the valley.
Then why don't you do something about the infestation?
We have! We sealed the border!
Fine.
I'll come back once I've destroyed all the corrupted.
[laughs]
Huh? If you're serious, then may you go in light girl,
and the Sun guide your arrows.