I've done what I can to cleanse this valley of corruption.
Time to see if the Carja fort will let me pass over the mountains.
Sounds of fighting.
Has something attacked the Carja fort?
A Corruptor!
I'll find a use for you.
[Carja guard]
Truly the Sun shines upon us this day!
It wasn't the Sun risking its ass down here.
[Carja guard]
Girl! Approach.
So will you open the gate for me now?
[laughs] You heard her.
Open the gates! And send word to Captain Balahn.
[Carja guard]
Where you headed, girl?
West to Meridian.
The Way of Broken Stones is a hard run, even in the best of times.
You might wanna have a word with Captain Balahn.
He came from Meridian not long ago.
You'll find him in the fort on a balcony to the left, overlooking the valley.
Okay. Thanks.
We're the ones who should be thanking you for taking down those machines.
Walk in light, Nora.
[Carja guard]
Always stay alert, that's what I say.
We all have our place in the order.
[Oseram trader]
Nothing but trouble, that's all there is in Banuk lands.
[Carja guard]
Don't ask me where to go if you're lost. I'm a guard, not the Town Crier.
Captain Balahn.
I have questions for you.
First about another Nora woman who might have come through here,
and second about the trail to Meridian.
What can I expect on the way?
Well, there was definitely another Nora.
No way I'd forget that.
She caused an incident.
As for what to expect on the trail?
Nothing good.
More machines all the time and our scouts report corruption that way as well.
So much for sealing things off.
Keep to the roads, they're safe enough.
Though after what you did at the gate, I'll wager you don't scare easy.
It's a good quality.
I could put it to use if you don't mind a quick jaunt back east.
I know it's bold of me to ask a favour after you just did one.
But I can offer you answers in return,
if there's anything you need to know about the Sundom.
What do you need, Captain?
I sent several patrols east when we got word of corrupted machines there.
All of them confirmed my fears.
So I sealed the gates.
But it looks like we left some men behind when they were closed.
Walid, tell her what happened.
Machines attacked us near an abandoned Nora village, sir.
Lakir told us to pull back.
Then I lost sight of the others.
Never seen a Nora woman before, soldier?
Have some respect.
Report to her, not to me.
Lakir always stresses reporting back.
So that's what I did.
I felt terrible about leaving them behind.
Now that the gates are open again, I can send someone after them.
Can't you send more soldiers to find the missing men?
What about Walid here?
Most Nora still don't take well to the sight of Carja armour.
Officially, it's a risk to send patrols so close to your Sacred Land.
I'd prefer not to do that again.
But heading that way won't be a problem for you.
[mutters] Please say yes.
What was that, soldier?
Nothing, sir.
I'll see what I can do about your missing men.
I would be grateful, but not as grateful as Walid.
You hear that, lunkhead?
You might be off the hook!
[Oseram trader]
Raised machines, with their shamans, damn nonsense. It's worse.
[whistle]
Black smoke, red tatters.
More bandits like the ones at Devil's Thirst.
So much for being careful.
[whistle]
They know I'm here now.
[Nora Brave]
A little help over here, please!
You have my thanks and the thanks of my family.
[Nora Brave]
You saved my life.
I promise I won't waste it.
The machines must have come across Captain Balahn's patrol here.
One of the Carja soldiers fell here.
The other soldiers must have retreated.
But to where?
This Carja fell far from the first battle.
At least his death came quickly.
Sun's making a show of it.
This can't be the helmet from the last Carja soldier.
Someone nearly lost his head here, then ran off.
Blood everywhere.
A machine dragged something into the water here.
But maybe he made it to that island.
Blood everywhere.
[in the distance]
By the Sun, by the Sun!
I'm never really done!
[in the distance]
I brought down all the beasts
What is that, singing?
[in the distance]
But I missed out on the feasts!
I went to the beer fount too many times to count.
[in the distance]
I fingered every curl but I never won the girl.
By the Sun, by the Sun!
I'm never really done!
I wasn't expecting to be found, especially not by a Nora.
I wasn't expecting to find a half clad Carjan soldier singing like a drunk.
I apologize for my behavior.
I thought I was dead.
Come on.
Your commander asked me to bring you back to Daytower.
I refuse to be led back to my outpost by a Nora, like some prisoner.
Humph, fine!
Go by yourself.
Wait.
Look, I got in a tussle with a Snapmaw.
It ate the half of me that was armour and bow.
The thief is still in the water.
I can't go back without a weapon.
Find my bow, please.
I'll get it, just don't start singing again.
Better watch out for that machine.
It doesn't look friendly.
Got their attention!
That hurt it!
They're angry!
Might regret this.
Here's your bow.
Good luck out there.
Thank you.
I, uh, I didn't want to die in foreign lands like my men.
May the Sun light their passing.
Got one.
Here we go again.
Back to your business.
[Oseram merchant]
Nothing but trouble, that's all there is in Banuk lands.
[Carja artisan]
I'll take a Carja merchant over an Oseram any day.
Genuine craftsmanship.
[Carja merchant]
I've got all the best goods here!
Won't cost you a shard just to look!
Lakir came back on his own.
A little worse for wear.
He seemed a bit embarrassed when I mentioned you.
Dare I ask?
He has a lovely singing voice.
That's a capital lie if I've ever heard one.
I'll have a talk with him about it.
What is this place exactly?
Daytower marks the eastern edge of Carja territory.
A trading post, a waystation, one with an ugly reputation among your people.
During the reign of the last Sun-King, many Nora were taken captive.
Then gathered here for transport to Meridian and sacrifice.
But the Sun set on that.
I was appointed by the Sun-King Avad to make sure
all Carja at this outpost show respect to the Nora.
Did an Oseram named Olin come through here?
Twice.
He was part of the royal delegation to the Nora.
And they passed through on the way, then back.
They brought back stories of a vicious attack on your people.
My condolences, of course.
Sun-King Avad wants peace.
So do the Matriarchs, I'm told.
But old wounds are slow to mend, and both tribes are proud.
My task is to make sure there are no further provocations from the Sundom,
especially now after, well…
While your people recover from this terrible attack I mean.
Do you know where Olin is now?
Not exactly.
But he was on his way to Meridian.
I'm certain of that.
Everyone goes to Meridian.
It's a changed place, a living city.
Nothing like it was during the rule of Sun-King Jiran.
Avad,  our new king, has done all he can to make sure of that.
Slavery has been abolished.
There's a new alliance with the Oseram.
And the Sun Ring, where so many outlanders were killed,
is now a memorial to the fallen.
Mad Sun-King Jiran raided the Oseram for years.
Avad managed to get them on his side.
He had help, of course.
Ersa and Erend played a part.
Oseram siblings, bigger than life.
They gathered an army to free Meridian.
I marched with them, scaled the north cliff with my men,
and secured the Temple of the Sun.
Sent Jiran's kestrels and priests packing.
Now Oseram are a common sight in the city.
And a common sound too, they sure bicker a lot.
It sounds as though you approve of the new Sun-King.
He is the chosen of the Sun,
and what the Sundom needs after ten years of war.
A calming light, not a scouring one.
Sun-King Jiran would shed blood at any slight.
For Sun-King Avad that's a last resort.
Lucky for those who slight him.
Some whisper in the shadows that he's weak.
No, peace is strength as the Sun shall show.
Is there anything more you can tell me about the road to Meridian?
Sun-King Avad has devoted considerable resources to making it safe.
But by the Sun's witness,
it's been harder to control in peace than it was during the war.
Machines grow more dangerous all the time.
Add to that bandits, and new reports of this corruption.
We're stretched thin to protect a few outposts like this one.
As for everywhere else.
Well, travel at your own risk.
You said something happened with Nakoa?
The Nora girl?
Yes, something happened.
Attempted murder.
Prefect Zaid can tell you more about it.
You can find him near the main tower, up the steps.
Wait.
Zaid is here?
He is.
Look, I've heard what your people say about him,
but he swears it's a case of mistaken identity.
If there's a shadow to him, I've never been able to prove it.
And the forbearance he showed towards this Nakoa woman was impressive.
Go, speak to him.
Maybe he knows where she went, and try not to assault him please.
[Carja]
Is that really all you have? Won't do at all.
[Oseram trader]
Those Shadow Carja scum are gonna pay for what they did to Ersa.
[Carja guard]
I heard that Oseram merchants charge us double…
or even triple of what they charge their own tribe.
[Carja outlander]
Hmm, hope I don't catch a chill.
A spring in your step today.
[Carja outlander]
The Nora have always been suspicious of outsiders.
I suppose they had good reason.
[Carja artisan]
It's all those savages I don't like.
The longer this split with the Shadow Carja lasts, the more prices will go up.
[Carja artisan]
I utterly refuse to buy from an Oseram.
They'll cheat you soon as look at you.
[Carja guard]
The Hunters Lodge should never have admitted those women or savages.
It's a noble Carja institution.
[Carja artisan]
Corruption spreads. More Sunless days are coming.
[Carja guard]
Watch out for the Oseram merchants.
They'll soon cheat you as look at you.
[Carja guard]
So there are Oseram in the Sundom now.
I get up, I work.
[Carja guard]
Same as always.
You're Zaid.
And you're a Nora.
I can tell from your tone you've heard of me.
Let me ease your mind.
There seemed to be wild stories about me among your tribe.
But the Nora have me mistaken for someone else.
I'm not sure where the fault lies, but the fog of war often breeds confusion.
Unfortunately, some refused to acknowledge the error.
So it was with the last Nora who came through here.
You mean Nakoa?
Is that her name?
Ah well, it was a very unfortunate situation.
She attacked me in broad daylight.
If one of my men hadn't spotted her, I might well have been injured.
But we were able to subdue her without harm.
What did you do with her?
I let her go of course.
It was clear she thought I was responsible for unspeakable things.
So in a sense, her actions were justifiable.
But all this nonsense about torture and murder? That wasn't me.
They have me confused with some other commander.
I don't doubt some of my comrades did bad things,
but Sun-King Avad has worked hard to eliminate such brutality.
Where is Nakoa now?
I don't know exactly.
She left raving that she would find a way to bring me down.
But I did hear a report from the garrison at Lonesome Rock
That a young woman had been abducted by bandits.
Might have been her.
You've really gone out of your way to help, Prefect Zaid.
It's no trouble.
The Sun-King wishes to make amends with your people
and I am his humble servant.
I'll go to Lonesome Rock and get to the bottom of this.
I promise you that.
You do that.
And if our men are anything less than helpful, please let me know.
Can't trust him, not after what Yan told me.
That garrison is my only lead.
[Carja guard]
Always stay bright, always stay alert. That's what I say.
We have to trust in our king…
[Carja merchant]
Would you like to buy something today?
[Carja guard]
Machines or bandits try to get past me?
They'll have a fight. Mark my words.
[Carja artisan]
I face the Sun's pride because I know I earned my place.
[Carja merchant]
Take a look at these wares!
[Aloy]
Snow chill, itches.
[Carja outlander]
I hope you and your family are well.
[Carja merchant]
Don't pass up these goods!
Check out these wares.
[Carja merchant]
Only the finest goods here, see for yourself!
The world beyond the Sacred Land.
I need to find Olin and learn everything he knows.
Who the killers were, how they saw me through his Focus.
Who the woman is, the one who looks like me.
Why they want me dead.
Olin's trail leads to Meridian.
When I catch him, he will talk.
And he will pay for all the lives he's ruined.