Is there anything more you can tell me about the road to Meridian?
Sun-King Avad has devoted considerable resources to making it safe.
But by the Sun's witness,
it's been harder to control in peace than it was during the war.
Machines grow more dangerous all the time.
Add to that bandits, and new reports of this corruption.
We're stretched thin to protect a few outposts like this one.
As for everywhere else.
Well, travel at your own risk.
The world beyond the Sacred Land.
I need to find Olin and learn everything he knows.
Who the killers were, how they saw me through his Focus.
Who the woman is, the one who looks like me.
Why they want me dead.
Olin's trail leads to Meridian.
When I catch him, he will talk.
And he will pay for all the lives he's ruined.
[Bandit]
Stop messing around and show yourself!
Come out, I'll make it quick!
[Bandit]
If you won't fight, why don't you run on home!
Show your face so I can slice it off!
[Carja outlander]
I don't want to die away from Meridian!
Help me! My life is on the line!
[Carja outlander]
Help! I want to see the sun rise again!
[Bandit]
Got you located!
Don't mind me.
[Bandit]
Right here, you …
Disappeared.
[Bandit]
I won't quit 'til I find you.
Rost always said "patience".
Can stop tensing up.
They're scanning for me.
[Carja guard]
Should be out there fighting machines not pacing around here.
[Carja outlander]
It's a crime. I should report it to the Sun Court.
[Carja guard]
I have nothing for you, I'm afraid.
We all have our place in the order of things.
[Carja outlander]
This isn't up to their usual standard.
I've seen this four times already.
[Carja outlander]
Oh, wonderful.
Perfect weather for a walk.
[Carja guard]
I'm sorry for the wait, but all goods entering the city are subject to search.
[Carja merchant]
This is outrageous. We are loyal citizens!
How long do we have to wait?
[Carja merchant]
What am I supposed to do? Just sit here and let everything spoil?
I thought Meridian was open to all Carja.
[Carja merchant]
What happened to Ersa has nothing to do with us.
[Carja artisan]
Eh, I've seen better.
[Carja merchant]
If I don't get my goods to the buyer soon, they'll cancel the contract.
What's going on here?
Olin's in there somewhere.
And so's Erend.
That other Outlander I talked to the night before the Proving.
Erend said he'd introduce me to his sister if I visited Meridian.
Said she was Captain of the Vanguard.
[Carja merchant]
Just finish your business here and be gone, outlander.
[Carja artisan]
City's locked down on account of the murder.
[Carja guard]
Good luck getting through, outlander.
[Carja artisan]
If this keeps up, I'll be broke in a month.
[Carja guard]
We all have our place in the order of things.
[Carja merchant]
It's always the merchants who suffer.
[Carja guard]
Hold!
Stop right there.
In light of the recent attack,
no stranger passes into Meridian without submitting to search.
Recent attack?
What are you talking about?
The murder of Captain Ersa and her Vanguards, Of course.
Ambushed by Shadow Carja forces in Red Ridge Pass.
Ersa? You mean Erend's sister is dead?
How would you know his name?
I know Erend. Summon him.
I need to speak to him.
Ha!
I doubt that Erend, the new Captain of the Vanguard,
a man in grief, is going to waste his time on a grimy outlander.
Aloy! Hey, you're alive!
I thought you were dead.
Make way! Make way!
All the way to Meridian just to see me?
Have you been drinking?
Ah, not really.
A little.
So you're alive.
We should celebrate it.
Drinks on me!
We need to talk alone and you need to pull together.
Over there.
So you approve?
Of course I approve.
From now on, she may come and go from this city as she pleases.
As you wish, sir.
There, alone as you asked.
What did you want to tell me?
I heard what happened to Ersa.
I'm sorry.
I know she was special to you.
Special to me?
Ha!
Special to everyone.
She always knew what to do.
Bossed everyone around.
She kept me in line.
Now I'm supposed to fill her shoes.
Instead here I am stumbling around in them.
Give yourself some time.
You'll find your footing.
Not at the rate I've been drinking.
And what would your sister have said about that?
I know, you're right.
I should expect more of myself.
She always did.
Then stop feeling sorry for yourself and live up to her example.
So much for a shoulder to cry on.
Everybody loses people they care about.
I, uh … I lost someone too.
At the Proving, the man who raised me.
His name was Rost.
That's terrible.
But why is it every time something terrible happens,
everyone else tells you the worst thing that ever happened to them,
as though that makes it easier?
Yeah.
Why is that?
Anyway, there is something you wanted to tell me?
A lot has happened since we last spoke.
The Proving was attacked by a group of killers.
Not many of us survived.
We were in the village when we heard explosions up on the mountain.
Some of your Braves came back.
Said most of the contestants were dead.
I've never heard such a wail of grief as the sound that rose up from your people.
How did you survive?
How I survived is less important than how I was targeted.
Targeted?
What do you mean?
The killers came for me because of Olin.
But he's a friend.
No, he's a traitor.
I don't know who the killers are or what they want,
but I do know that Olin is working with them.
But … I mean … this …
I don't need you to understand, Erend.
I just need you to take me to him.
He's not here.
He went scrounging for scrap and relics days ago.
He could be anywhere.
Are there any places he frequents?
Places he returns to?
A house, here in Meridian.
Okay, then take me there.
I need to search it.
I guess, as long as I'm there to witness the search.
So many people here, all talking at once.
How does anyone think?
[Erend]
I don't, I just drink.
[Carja merchant]
I've got all the best goods here.
[Carja snob]
That girl, is she a Nora?
Apparently they're letting anyone into the city these days.
[in the distance]
How long will Avad hide in his palace? To lay siege to the Citadel?
Does he lack the stomach for justice?
Blood for blood! Vengeance for Ersa!
Year after year,
why does he spare those who enslaved and tortured and butchered?
Erend!
You should want vengeance more than anyone.
Your own sister murdered and her death unavenged.
One more word you scorched-out slag.
And I'll throw you in jail myself.
Get out of here.
Or I'll give you all the kick in the ass!
What did he mean about Ersa's murder?
[Erend]
Not now.
Okay, how are we going to get in?
Oh, that was … subtle.
[Erend]
Here we are. Try not to break anything. Other than the door.
[Aloy]
All of this for one man.
[Erend]
It pays to have connections in the Sun-King's court.
Does he know the Sun-King personally?
No.
He served the court as a scout sometimes and sold ancient trinkets to nobles.
But he never had an audience with the King.
If you're right and Olin's into something dark,
Sun-King Avad has nothing to do with it.
I'd stake my life on that.
Did Olin ever invite you in?
Nah.
Closest I got was a doorstep to help him home after a night out.
We drank a river that night, but I hold it well, usually.
Are you sure you're okay?
I'm sober enough, all right?
I don't need another lecture.
That's not what I meant.
I was talking about what happened outside with the crowd.
I don't wanna talk about that.
We're here because of what you said about Olin.
So do what you need to do.
The corner of this rug is frayed, and the floor near it is worn.
Let's see what's underneath.
Hey, how did that get here?
Question is how to get through it.
Without a key, you won't.
That's a vault hatch of Oseram make.
Nothing gets through.
We'll see about that.
[Erend]
Call it a day, girl. You're wasting time.
Looks big and heavy.
Could do a lot of damage if it fell down.
Let's give it a little push.
I did say not to break anything, didn't I?
It looks like a picture of Olin's family.
Time to get to the bottom of this.
Looks like Olin kept a journal.
[Erend]
Olin?
I knew he could read contracts, but I never took him for a poet.
No doubt now, Olin knew I was targeted.
A map.
The glyphs show places he visited.
[hologram]
Serve and they live.
Disobey and I will open their throats and leave their corpses to prune in the sun.
They took his wife and child captive.
They?
Who's they?
The killers.
They told him to obey or they kill his family.
There's your proof.
Read the last page.
He writes about meeting me and the order to kill me.
He called himself a friend.
That backstabbing cheat.
How did you learn to read glyphs?
And these things that you see, how do you do it?
The Focus.
It reveals the unseen.
And Olin's Focus? It's the same?
The device is the same, but…
Somehow Olin and the killers can speak to each other
with their Focuses over distances,
and see through each other's Focuses, too.
Like looking through each other's eyes.
So that's how the killers saw you? Through Olin.
Yes, so far as I can tell.
Now that I know where to find Olin, I should be on my way.
All by yourself?
Leave it to me. I'm faster on my own.
Wait!
If that device lets you see the unseen…
Out of the way, Erend.
I'm asking you to help me, Aloy.
I need to know who killed Ersa.
Not just that the Shadow Carja Army, I know that.
But the exact soldiers who did it.
I'm sorry about your sister, but that's your war, not mine.
Don't act like this isn't personal.
You came here hunting the people who nearly killed you.
Who massacred your people!
Why should you have justice and not me?
Look, I'll head for Red Ridge Pass where Ersa's body was found,
and wait for you there.
A few minutes of your Focus is all I need.
Don't make me beg.
Red Ridge Pass you said?
I'll see what I can do.
[sniffs] Spice!
[Carja merchant]
An Oseram would argue with the sun itself.
Smells like nothing I've ever smelled before.
Is that some kind of spice?
Hmm, you're an outlander.
Nora from the look of you.
I bet you're a machine hunter too.
I've hunted my share.
I'm known as a skilled hunter back home in Ban-Ur.
So I thought I'd try my luck at the lodge.
I thought I'd be simple. Hunt machines, gain ranks, see who's best.
But it doesn't work like that at all.
It's all rigged to keep the Carja at the head of the line.
If you're not Carja, you'll never rise in the ranks.
When Sun-King Avad took over, he promised a new day.
Meridian open to all. But it's a sham.
Sure you can get a seat at the feast, but you just can't eat the food.
Sounds like someone needs to shake things up with the lodge.
Maybe, but it isn't gonna be me.
I don't need those snobs to tell me I can hunt. I'm going home.
If you decide to go, be sure to give them a good,
old-fashioned Banuk farewell mark, in my honour.
A "Banuk farewell mark"? What's that?
Piss on the floor.
Preferably someplace they won't find it until it gets nice and sour.
[Carja outlander]
The people here won't stand for tyranny.
Meridian has proven itself above such things.
[Carja merchant]
Only the finest goods here, see for yourself.
Don't pass up on these goods.
[Carja guard]
Meridian is a marvel of engineering that has stood for generations.
[Carja merchant]
Fine goods for a fair price.
[Carja guard]
Machines or bandits try to get past me, they'll have a fight.
[Carja merchant]
These aren't goods, they're necessities!
Check out these wares!
[Carja guard]
The Nora will survive. They always do, it's that barbarian resilience.
You need to win three Half Suns at our Hunting Grounds
to gain admittance to the lodge.
You mean these?
Very well then.
Congratulations and welcome.
Our members reap rewards and adventure and live on in legend.
Am I a member now?
No, you're only a fledgling.
Junior members are called Thrushes.
To join and become a Thrush,
you need a senior member called a Hawk to sponsor you.
So I need to find a Hawk.
Yes, but a Hawk can only sponsor one hunter at a time.
And I'm afraid most of them already have one.
I have overcome worse odds.
Where do I start?
Upstairs.
Present yourself to the Sunhawk Ahsis, our leader,
who should introduce you to a Hawk.
I hope it's worth it.
What do you mean?
You'll see.
By the Sun!
King Avad's edict really is taking effect.
I never thought I'd see a Nora here! And a woman at that.
What edict?
King Avad insisted that the Hunters Lodge had to welcome everyone.
Man, woman, outlander, regardless of tribe.
Ersa, Captain of the Vanguard, came in and delivered that news personally.
You should have been there, it was glorious!
But I figured they would sweep it under the rug
and say no woman or outlander qualified.
Yet here you are.
Are you a member?
Me? No.
Carja don't exactly encourage their daughters to run around hunting machines.
But all the changes in Meridian have been good to me.
So you have marks for me?
What do you mean?
From the Hunting Grounds.
Oh, right. You're new here.
What do you want with my marks?
You hunters and your badges.
I'm not gonna take them.
I'm going to give you a weapon that sets you apart.
What do I do with these marks?
If you earn marks in all three trials
at each of the five Hunting Grounds, come to me.
I can give you up to three weapons.
One for fifteen Half Suns,
one for fifteen Full Suns,
and one you'll love for all Blazing Suns!
I need a few more.
Okay,  once you get marks from the trials at every Hunting Ground,
come back and we'll see what I can give you.
What have we here?
A Nora fledge.
Bet I've been hunting longer than you have.
Are you a fledgling?
Not for long.
I have a Hawk who's about to sponsor me.
So you're out of luck.
Typical savage barging in here without a thought,
right after one of our own was killed.
Go away.
I've been trophy hunting for years.
Still haven't gotten a sponsor.
I'd ask Talanah to sponsor me, but her sponsor just died.
Can't imagine what she must be going through.
Excuse us.
Ah, the machine rider graces us with her presence.
You're a Nora, are you not?
A fighter from the savage lands.
The Sacred Land.
But yes, I fought for everything I got.
Huh.
Tell me, do the Nora often wander into other people's homes
and do whatever they like?
Of course not.
But that is what you're doing, right now.
Stinking up our lodge, pestering your betters.
You're hardly my better.
Ligan said I had to meet you to become a member.
That would be true if there were any chance of you becoming a member.
But you're a savage.
And no savage will rise in the ranks of the Hunters Lodge
while I am the Sunhawk.
Now begone.
No, I was led to believe there are rules here.
If they count for nothing than even your position is meaningless.
So quit blustering and tell me, is there a hawk who is free to sponsor me?
Very well.
Talanah is free.
Wouldn't that be fitting? Trash sponsoring trash.
Now get out of my sight.
You're Talanah?
Ahsis said you were a Hawk without a fledgling to sponsor.
Or are you trying to drive me off too?
It's okay. I've dealt with worse.
Mmm, I'll bet you have.
But you're wrong.
It's not okay, especially not today.
What happened today?
One of our own just died fighting Redmaw.
You'll never face a more dangerous Thunderjaw
Cuts through trees, rocks, people.
I'm sorry to hear that.
It's part of the hunt.
Is there any actual hunting in this lodge?
So far, it's been all talk.
Yes, of course.
You fight a machine, then bring its trophy to Ahsis the Sunhawk.
Then no-one can deny you brought it down.
Ahsis, what's his story?
He's the Sunhawk of the lodge, the highest ranking assho– sorry, member.
He's taken down Ravagers, Stalkers, Behemoths.
So? I've taken down a lot of machines.
As have I. Even brought down two Stormbirds.
But he's a Hawk who brought in the trophies first.
That's how it works.
Whichever Hawk defeats the greatest machine first becomes the Sunhawk.
Who is this Ligan? The man at the door.
Ligan, he's a Hawk.
He had an impressive run in his day, but he doesn't fight anymore.
He supports the lodge in other ways,
unlike the other Hawks who hoard all the best kills and drink the bar dry.
How does one become a Hawk?
When a Hawk dies, his Thrush is promoted in his place.
No matter how anyone feels about it.
I'm ready to hunt. So tell me, what do I have to do?
You want them to regret looking down on you?
Then speak to them in their language.
Kill three Sawtooths, two Ravagers and a Stalker.
Deliver their trophies directly to Ahsis, that should shut them all up.
So if I do that, you'll sponsor me.
I'll consider it, just to make Ahsis boil.