I'm ready to hunt. So tell me, what do I have to do?
You want them to regret looking down on you?
Then speak to them in their language.
Kill three Sawtooths, two Ravagers and a Stalker.
Deliver their trophies directly to Ahsis, that should shut them all up.
So if I do that, you'll sponsor me.
I'll consider it.
[Carja noble]
…waste of time.
[Carja merchant]
Check out these wares!
Only the finest goods here, see for yourself!
That must be the Spire.
It's huge.
[Carja guard]
Always stay bright, always stay alert. That's what I say.
[Carja merchants]
- Don't pass up these goods!
- You'll like what I have for sale, I promise.
[Carja merchant]
Don't pass up these goods.
You'll like what I have for sale, I promise!
[Carja merchants]
- Won't find better wares.
- Come take a look, I'll give you a good price!
[Carja merchant]
You like what I have for sale, I promise.
[Carja merchants]
- You'll like what I have for sale…
- You'll regret not stopping when you're in the thick of it.
[Carja merchant]
I've got all the best goods here.
[Carja merchants]
- Take a look at these wares!
- Won't cost you a shard, just to look!
[rude Carja]
Mind your business outlander.
[Carja merchant]
I've got all the best goods.
Only the finest goods here, see for yourself.
[Carja merchant]
Fine goods for a fair price.
I've got all the best goods here.
Just stay our of their way for now.
Another day passing.
It'd be fascinating, if they weren't looking for me.
Passed the test.
Ha!
Low and quiet does it.
Calm, calm.
Keep quiet now.
I can get out of this.
Back to your business.
Here they come.
Here we go again.
Keep that for later.
I'll shake it out later.
Come on!
Can't be too prepared.
[Carja guard]
It's not what I imagined when I was a boy, but it's decent work keeping the city safe.
That was worth it.
Get it while I can.
Dust won't stop blowing.
Gotta put up a fight.
Got you!
Nutritious.
Let's get on with it.
[distant cry]
[whistle]
[Carja spearman]
Here! A Broadhead!
[flashback]
Where is Nakoa now?
I don't know exactly.
[flashback]
She left raving that she would find a way to bring me down.
But I did hear a report from the garrison at Lonesome Rock,
[flashback]
that a young woman had been abducted by bandits. Might have been her.
This must be Lonesome Rock.
If it's a trap, I might need to go in quiet.
[Carja guard]
I'm so bored, I'm bored with being bored.
I'm bored with you talking about being bored.
[Aloy]
Seems like an ordinary outpost.
[Carja guard]
I'm bored with you complaining about me being bored.
[Aloy]
I'd better look around.
[Carja guard]
I wasn't complaining about you being bored.
I was complaining about your complaining.
[Carja guard]
Well, now I'm complaining about your complaining.
[Carja head guard]
If you two don't shut up, I'm going to complain to Zaid, and then things will get ugly.
[Aloy]
There are chains in the cart.
[Carja head guard]
Hold Outlander!
What are you doing here?
Hunting.
I've been tracking a Sawtooth for the better part of a day.
Well, you must have lost the scent because we haven't seen any round here.
Now, be on your way and quickly.
[Carja head guard]
She's snooping around!
Wrap up and tie her down boys.
[Carja guard]
I'm down.
Alright, let's see what Zaid's hiding out here.
Well, they don't want to talk, so let's see if they're hiding something.
Not just chains, manacles.
They were moving prisoners somewhere.
The tracks lead to that compound.
Maybe Nakoa is inside.
[Carja outlander]
That Nora girl we got in the hole is nice and lean.
Don't get ideas.
[Carja outlander]
Zaid says hands off or it'll hurt her price at auction.
Sounds like Nakoa is here.
And I'm gonna have to cut through these guards to get to her.
You can see them, they can't see you.
[Carja outlander]
I see him!
[in the distance]
Is someone there?
[Prisoner]
Please, help us get out of here.
Prisoners chained up to be sold as slaves.
[Prisoner]
Talk to Nakoa. She'll know what to do.
Nakoa? Yan sent me.
Look, we can talk more once we get everyone out of this pit.
Yan sent you?
I don't believe it.
I guess one of his prayers finally worked.
You'll need a key to get us out.
One of Zaid's men should have it.
I've got the key.
I'll help the others.
Let's go!
I knew you were going to be trouble, girl,
but you will make it worth our while in the end.
The end is now Zaid! For you and your men.
[Aloy]
You gave him a quicker death than he deserved.
My father was a hunter.
He taught me every animal deserves a clean kill.
How did Zaid come to run a ring of slavers?
All the scum you just killed.
They butchered for Zaid during the Red Raids.
The new Sun-King kicked them out of the army.
But Zaid managed to lie his way out of trouble.
Then saw a new way to make a shard putting his grunts to work here.
How did Zaid capture you?
I tried to get him at Daytower, but he caught me.
Then let me go so he could have his men grab me later.
And after?
Said he was gonna sell me into slavery like the other
poor bastards that came through here week to week.
But he took his time, kicked me around whenever he stopped by.
Guess me trying to kill him hurt his pride.
You've been through a lot.
I'm fine.
Are you sure?
Zaid's dead.
I was ready to go through anything to make that happen.
And I did.
What are you gonna do now?
The others were in that cellar for months.
The more run down they got, the harder it was for Zaid to sell them.
They need food, rest, and hope.
I'll take them to Meridian and tend to them.
You're not even going to try to go back?
What about Yan?
The Matriarchs won't let me back.
Even if they would, I wouldn't go.
They can burn for all I care.
As for Yan, I know a way to get word to him.
I'll miss that runt, but at least he'll know I'm safe.
Time for me to go.
Look, I don't even know your story.
Must be a good one if they gave you the mark of a Seeker.
If you ever feel like telling it, look me up in Meridian.
I'll be there until the others get back up on their feet.
Until then,
…thank you…
…for helping me cut this rot from the world.
I don't know.
Maybe now I can put Zaid behind me and remember my father as I should.
Thanks again, for all your help.