Now that I know where to find Olin, I should be on my way.
Wait, if that device lets you see the unseen…
Out of the way Erend.
I'm asking you to help me, Aloy.
I need to know who killed Ersa.
Why should you have justice and not me?
Look, I'll head for Red Ridge Pass
where Ersa's body was found and wait for you there.
A few minutes of your Focus is all I need.
Don't make me beg.
Not yet.
Never know when I might need these.
Ah, she went that-a-way!
[Cultist]
The Sun can't save you now!
I can't spare the weight.
Tasty.
This is what you intend?
To bring these ancient things back to life.
Their power serves us.
[Olin]
Machine demons from beneath the ground.
It's a nightmare.
[Cultist]
Nightmares? Yes. The worst dreams of our enemies come true.
Yes! Rise!
So much for catching him alone.
These things will destroy us all!
They will only destroy our enemies and bring us back the lands that wer—AAAH!
My Focus, stopped working.
Search the area! We may may have intruders.
[voice from Focus]
Forgive this intrusion Aloy, you left me no choice.
Who is this?
[voice from Focus]
An interested party.
Now the Focuses are disabled, but I don't know for how long.
[voice from Focus]
The rest is up to you.
Who is this?
[Olin]
The Nora girl lives!
[Cultist]
kill her!
[Olin]
No!
[Cultist]
You had your chance.
That's right, no-one here.
Full already.
[Olin]
I promise, I'll tell you everything!
The killers who came from me at the Proving, who are they?
The Eclipse, some kind of holy warriors.
A cult of the Shadow Carja.
Shadow Carja?
Except they're not like any Carja I've known.
They don't pray to the Sun.
They worship some kind of devil.
I'm not interested in their superstitions.
Oh, it's not a superstition.
Their devil is real. It has a name, a voice.
And you've heard it speak?
Steel to my soul, I heard.
Just once when it saw you. Such a voice.
A cold, awful jangle.
It scrapes your bones and hollows your guts, a metal sound.
But like nothing dug from the earth or smelted in a forge.
Hades, that's what they call it.
Hades? And what did it say?
"System threat detected". Just three words.
The Eclipse were sent to kill me because I look like another woman.
Older, maybe twice my age, short hair. Who is she?
I don't know. My Focus found her image once.
I had taken a delve near Maker's End, there was a door.
Beside it, a kind of ancient device that contained the woman's image.
My Focus recorded the location.
When I surfaced, they were waiting.
I laughed when I saw the priest, but then he showed me Helis's encouragement.
I didn't laugh after that.
They gave me a Focus to watch my every move.
I followed orders.
Why you?
I was a scrounger, a rummager in dark places.
Good at what I do.
I suppose they knew I would serve them well as a scout.
What are these Eclipse cultists after, besides me?
They never said!
But given the Carja civil war they must want
to overthrow Sun-King Avad and take Meridian back.
Why didn't they get to Avad through you?
Too much dirt under my nails for an audience with one true Sun-King.
But whatever Ersa or Erend told me?
The Eclipse heard every word through my Focus.
That's why I couldn't warn you.
If I tried they would have killed my family!
When they attacked the Proving a man came for me.
Tall, strong, dead eyes?
Helis.
And who is he?
The terror of the Sun.
Stacker of Corpses we Oseram called him
when he was the Mad Sun-King's champion.
If only he died with his king.
But now he leads the Eclipse.
I tell you, he's the most dangerous man alive.
Why are the Eclipse digging up ancient machines,
and how do they get them to work?
I thought they wanted them for scrap, but they brought them back to life.
Plugged some kind of device into the corpses so that Hades
could whisper to them and call them from their grave.
I've fought that kind of machine before. Are there others?
Much bigger, bristling with ancient weapons, those they call Deathbringers.
I've only seen them buried in the ground.
But after today, anything is possible.
Sounds to me like they're raising an army.
If so, the world will fall.
And I helped dig the pit.
I've heard enough.
I won't beg for my life.
But if there's any mercy in you free my family, please.
Where would I find them?
My Focus recorded the location.
There are always guards there.
You look like you can handle yourself.
Your…
Your role in events was coerced.
Perhaps you're not an evil man.
Just a weak one.
I am.
The only strength I ever found in this life was my family.
It will take many good deeds to make up for the crimes you've committed.
You're sparing me? After all I've done?
Yes.
Forge a new life, Olin.
One of better make.
Then the rest of my life will be lived in your debt.
Go to the place where your family is being held and wait for me.
We'll make their lives the first ones you save.
I didn't earn this mercy, but I will die to make myself worthy of it.
I will be waiting for you.
It's Erend, and he's in trouble.
[Erend]
Take cover!
Die, damn you!
[Erend]
I'm glad that's over with.
Thanks for the help.
[Erend]
Come on over here and have a word.
Can't be too prepared.
[Erend]
Come on, what are you waiting for?
What are you doing out here all alone?
Where are your men?
I'm not going to risk their lives.
I don't mind putting my worthless ass on the line, but not theirs.
Sorry I had to drag you into it.
Don't worry, this is just an average day for me.
You know, take down some machines, track some killers.
Right, I'd hate to see a busy morning for you.
Ready to get started?
Are you sure you're all right?
Well, I'm sober, so … no.
Well, I'm glad you're thinking straight at least.
Don't get used to it.
Tell me exactly what happened to Ersa.
Start from the beginning.
No one knows for sure.
She left in the middle of the night with a few of her best men.
Her best men, but she didn't bring you?
No, I'd been drinking a lot.
Maybe she thought, ah damn I don't know, I couldn't hack it.
Search parties found their bodies the next day
and the corpses of some Shadow Carja cowards.
It was an ambush.
The Shadow Carja are animals.
They beat her so bad we can't even show her face before burial.
I'm so sorry, Erend.
Yeah, well, when I find the soldiers who did this, they'll be sorry too.
You don't have any idea why she left in the middle of the night?
No, but it must have been urgent.
A message, a report of some new Shadow Carja threat.
I don't know.
Why would the Shadow Carja do this?
Because they hate us and Ersa most of all.
She teamed up with Avad to kick their asses out of Meridian.
They've been licking their wounds for two years.
But they finally found a way to get back at her.
Alright, show me where Ersa fell and I'll do what I can to help.
Come on, follow me.
[Aloy]
Why would Ersa come all the way out here?
[Erend]
I don't know.
It doesn't make sense.
[Aloy]
Is this Shadow Carja territory?
[Erend]
No, they broke the ceasefire as soon as they set foot in the Cleft.
Almost there.
[Erend]
Right, this is it, where the ambush happened.
Our soldiers have been over it, but maybe that
fancy artifact of yours can find a clue or something.
[Erend]
Please, I need to find the bastards that did this.
A Shadow Carja spear.
That must be Shadow Carja armour.
These look like drag marks.
Those bloodstains, not the kind would pool around a corpse.
Arrows scattered there.
They look like smears.
It's perfectly sharp, never seen action.
Strange, not a scratch on it.
They look good as new, never fired.
Did someone move a body through here?
[Erend]
What do you see there?
This stain forms a line as if blood dripped off the edge of something, like a cart.
See? Cart tracks.
I think someone moved the bodies here, then scattered them across the field.
Wait, are you saying the dead found here were killed somewhere else?
But why would the Shadow Carja do that?
At this point?
I'm not taking it for granted that the Shadow Carja are responsible.
Of course they were.
Well, let's follow these tracks and find out.
[Erend]
I get why they wanted Ersa dead, but why fake an ambush?
[Aloy]
There's more to this and we're gonna figure it out.
These guys aren't Shadow Carja.
They're from my tribe, the Oseram!
Is this how your people usually greet each other?
[Oseram mercenary]
Incoming!
[Erend]
Uh-oh, what's that?
[Aloy]
I think it's calling in machines. Get ready.
[Erend]
I liberated Meridian!
See what happens when you mess with the Vanguard!
[Aloy]
That hurt it!
Oseram, not Shadow Carja.
Looks like I was wrong about everything as usual.
Please, use that second sight of yours.
I have to know what really happened.
I'm on it.
So much blood.
What are those leather straps?
A lot of people died here, a massacre.
Armour straps, cut with a knife, and a rock with blood on it.
These look like Vanguard weapons.
There's no blood on them.
Ersa's men didn't fight back.
Those rocks, they're shattered.
Something hit these stones, something I've never seen before.
This is Ersa's helmet.
I thought she died in the field below, but must have been here.
All this trickery for what?
Feels like it's just to torture me.
I have a theory.
But it takes a little imagination.
So far, your theories are better than other people's facts.
Alright.
I think the Oseram ambushed Ersa and her men with a new weapon.
They mounted it on that tripod up there.
It fires waves of force, maybe sound.
Looks like it cracked the stone there.
I think it paralyzes people instead of killing them, it dropped the Vanguard right there.
No blood on their weapons.
No fight.
But why paralyze them if you're only gonna move them and gut them?
They were trying to hide something.
Look here, a bloody rock.
That they used to smash Ersa's face in.
Or someone else's.
These leather straps have been cut as if they took the armour off someone.
That can't be.
Her body is lying in state in Meridian.
I saw it!
You said she was unrecognisable.
Maybe they switched another body into her armour.
Someone around the same size.
And mutilated it enough so it could have been anyone.
Even Ersa.
Go back to Meridian.
Take another look at that body.
If it's really Ersa, of course I'm wrong.
But if I'm right…
…then my sister could be alive!
I'm going! Meet me back there when you can.
Dawn breaking, every time's different.
Stocking up.
I'll tuck that away.
It's drawing back.
Always watching.
[Carja spearman]
You're trash, now!
Here we are!
Got it!
[whistle]