[Carja guard]
Don't ask me where to go if you're lost…
[Carja outlander]
…seasoned tourist, but the Banuk deny…
[Carja guard]
…many have died and many more…
[Carja merchant]
I can't help but smile with sunshine.
[Aloy]
Erend said to meet him at the Sun Palace.
Now might be the time.
[Carja guard]
These damn Oseram stirring up tensions.
I'm keeping my eyes open.
[Carja merchant]
Won't cost you a shard just a look.
Don't pass up these goods.
[Carja outlander]
…of all cities and within, the great…
[Carja merchant]
Come take a look, I'll give you a good price.
[Carja outlander]
Hope you're well.
[Carja artisan]
Some Oseram is building…
I may not have all the answers, but there is a book of bylaws here
which can tell you more about the lodge.
Umm, suddenly you're a lot nicer.
I saw you talking to Talanah, she's tough.
You'd be lucky to keep up with her, machine rider or no.
Go on and give Ahsis those trophies!
I thought I told you…
I'm here to present trophies to the Sunhawk of the Lodge.
Three Sawtooths, two Ravagers and a Stalker for good measure.
I suppose Talanah helped you with this.
I brought these down myself.
Will you accept them?
Fine, yes, I accept them.
But tell Talanah she should stop playing with sludge if she wants to get Redmaw.
[Carja outlander]
…that could destroy a village and disappear into the hills.
When I gave him my trophies,
Ahsis said you should be spending more time finding Redmaw than helping me.
That bunghead isn't wrong, but there isn't time to find Redmaw right now.
You're gonna help with something else.
Oh, and what might that be?
Meet me outside.
[Carja outlander]
A little sweat and hard work never hurt anyone.
You want to help?
Here's someone who needs it.
Go ahead Ilsadi.
I live in Lone Light, northeast of here.
I barely escaped because Glinthawks attack anyone who ventures out.
We have so few shards.
Will you help? We have nowhere else to turn.
Sometimes members receive an honorarium for the hunt.
Ahsis should have accepted this one, but he refused.
The price was too low.
How generous.
In the past, I would have gone with Tarkas to handle this.
What say you and I take it on?
I'll meet you at Lone Light.
What about Redmaw?
Are you in or not?
Alright.
I'll meet you there as soon as I can.
I'll make sure Ilsadi makes it back to Lone Light.
Meet you there?
It's just northeast of here.
[Vilgund]
Able bodied adventurers.
Preferably with no friends or family.
[Vilgund]
But I'm not choosy.
Hoy there Outlander!
Name's Vilgund.
Did you come to the city looking for work?
Good shards.
Enough to buy garb, more becoming of your…
Okay, stop there if you want me to hear you out.
I only meant a well-molded woman such as you…
[clears throat]
Are you some kind of merchant?
You don't seem to have any wares.
More of an opportunist.
Girl … Nora girl … [clears throat]
Huntress.
We live in a world of opportunities.
Risky opportunities.
But why should risk stand in the way of a lucrative prospect for the likes of me?
Alright, I'm more of a gambler.
I heard an interesting rumour about a Banuk camp.
They say the Banuk there live alongside machines.
Peaceful as you like, keep 'em, use 'em, sing to 'em.
If it's true, if we learn how they do it,
think how valuable that would be to all the tribes!
When you say valuable, you mean they'd pay you for it.
The last bunch just wanted to know about the reward.
You're a smart one.
I hired men to investigate.
Just investigate, that's all.
Those Banuk are canny, too canny.
I paid up front.
Well, half up front.
I've had no word back.
So now you're hiring someone to find the last men you hired?
Psh. They're a sunk cost.
What can you tell me about the Banuk?
Well, the Banuk women, snow witches all.
Cold eyes, cold … [clears throat]
They choose to live up there in Ban-Ur in the ice.
Trying to have a conversation, it's like chipping them out of the stuff.
They prefer machines for company.
That's why I'm putting my shards on this rumour.
Then they might not want outsiders to know about this place.
Ha!
Their mystic act.
No care for possessions, for luxuries? Pile of slag!
Those people bargain harder than the winter frost.
If I did look into your rumour…
You won't need to climb up the shoulders of the world for it!
It's on the edge of Banuk land, beneath the Anvil of the Moon.
And you look like you know your way around the Savage East …
… the east.
If it's true, they walk among machines without fear in this camp, well.
You can't miss that, can you?
Payment on return.
Irid.
Didn't want to startle you.
Oh, yes.
I heard of the tragedy that befell your tribe.
The Sun hung low that day as we traveled back.
So, this is the temple of the Sun Priests.
Where we offer are daily prayers for balance.
I'm afraid only Carja can participate.
But you are welcome to observe.
Don't worry, I'm used to it.
What are these prayers?
To recognize the Sun is to recognise we live in renewal.
By Its rise and fall we determine what to take up and what to set aside.
Offered to Its pure heat, the skin peels and old time is burned away.
We treasure the blisters.
That sounds … painful.
Well, there is no glory without sacrifice.
The temple looks out on the tower across the valley, why?
It is said that the Spire's shadow lay across this mesa
when our ancestors came to the valley searching for a home.
Thus, Sun and Spire joined, showing the Carja where to build.
The dawn of Meridian!
Always illuminating, Irid.
There is a matter not officially sanctioned.
That someone off your boldness…
You don't have to squirm Irid, let's hear it.
Uh, one of our brethren, my friend Namman,
has stepped from the Sun's light in protest.
I've supported his efforts as much as I can, but…
Would you speak with him in the Sun Ring?
I'll see what I can do.
May you always go in light, my friend
[distant singing from the Sun Ring]
[Carja noble]
Ha! King Avad's decree brought the Hunters Lodge in line.
Hear they had to admit another woman into the ranks.
[singing]
[Carja artisan]
Who's really in charge of Meridian, huh? The Oseram, that's who.
Whispering in our Sun-King's ear.
[Carja outlander]
Captain of the Vanguard, murdered?
[singing]
[Carja outlander]
Shadow Carja ambushed Captain Ersa, but how did they lure her out there?
[singing]
[Sun Priest]
You're Nora.
I'm the Mournful Namman.
My apologies that we meet like this.
Like this?
In grief. You hold yours close like a talisman.
Wait, forgive me.
You didn't come for reparations?
Someone you lost to the Sun Ring?
No, I know about the Red Raids, but the Carja owe me nothing.
I see.
Well, I could use the help of a strong-willed outlander.
Then I would owe you very much indeed.
I didn't think your priesthood would ask outsiders for help.
If only the Sun would set on our pride.
Until this is done I am no Sun Priest.
To wear a red robe was an aspiration.
I aspired.
Now our hoods make us blind.
We whisper reconciliation, but forget how the old King's priests sang the words and blessed the killing.
You're disappointed with the Sun Priests, but you still wanted to be one?
I spent my whole life looking up to the temple,
my brother's voice echoing in its arches.
Even he couldn't turn me away, and how he tried in the end.
He said, "When we were loved, our robes were dyed in cinnabar,
now they are stained in blood."
How so?
Our robes are handed down to us.
Most of the old priests fled rather than be seen in the glare of a new Sun.
And so we left to wear their sins.
For me, at least, they hang heavy.
Where is your brother now?
He waits for me on the trail of the Sun, I hope.
He spoke out against the sacrifices.
For a priest to question the Sun-King's will?
His punishment was worst of all.
You lost someone you loved too.
I'm sorry.
No, not lost.
When I took on these robes,
I found his memory.
Why did the priests go along with all that bloodshed?
Sometimes we Carja are more concerned with what is tradition than what is right.
Huh.
Maybe the Carja and Nora aren't so different.
These people seek to honour their loved, their lost, with their own voices.
Not mouthing Carja rituals to Carja stone.
But there are obstacles.
While Meridian holds its breath for any disturbance, these robes only tie my hands.
What kind of obstacles?
The first pilgrim is an Oseram,
who seeks to visit the Shrine of Kings on the road to the city.
He waits there now, forbidden to enter by an old Sun Priest who'll suffer no heathen.
This Utaru lost her companion on the edge of the Jewel,
at a pool where Snapmaws gather.
A shrine was built their to ward off the machines.
Its effectiveness leaves much to be desired.
And the Banuk would paint a mark on the Sun's Climb.
A call to the machine spirits I understand.
They need no beckoning.
Glinthawks perch there, drawn to the Spire's shining.
So, clear the machines out of two shrines and move a priest out of the other.
All I can ask for is your charity and that their stories are heard.
Namman, rituals and prayers can't bring back those who are lost.
No, but it can help those who grieve to find themselves.
It can lend them strength and hope, like a new sunrise.
I'll do what I can to help those in mourning.
To honour their memories is to honour us all.
You're not like the others.
You wear machine parts, but you hunted them yourself.
How can you tell?
A hunter knows a hunter.
My people run with the great metal herds among the northern glaciers.
But the Glinthawks at Sun's Climb are too strong for me.
So I cannot fulfil my vow to paint the story of my people there.
How the madness of the machines spread to the Carja,
and they sent their soldiers,
feet frost-blackened, to bring us here in chains.
Our Shamans, who sing the machine songs — many were taken to their deaths.
Their songs go unfinished in Ban-Ur.
Help me honour them, help me paint their story.
I ask you this, hunter to hunter.
You look like you've traveled far outlander.
From the Great Plains, but not alone.
Never alone.
This was a city of cages two harvest ago.
Wooden bars leave marks.
I kept those marks.
I can still feel the bars.
They took you as a slave but you escaped?
During the liberation.
My friend and I, they put us to work in the quarries together.
We'd grown alike, so we fled together.
But in the smoke, the trees, we ran right into the machines.
I kept running, I thought she was just behind me.
She is still, wherever I go, just behind me.
And that's why I came back. To finally free us from that moment.
But I need your help to do it.
I've been asking the nobles of the Sun Court to hear on my cause.
Just the grace of their ears.
You want me to shake them down too?
Don't tempt me.
I'm still a priest.
I need to get going.
May the Sun shine upon you.
[Carja noble]
I'll never leave Meridian, the view alone makes life worth living.
[Carja guard]
Always stay bright, always stay alert, that's what I say.
[Carja artisan]
Meridian is the centre of the world. Everyone comes here eventually.
[Carja guard]
[yawns] I'm awake, and alert. Damn it.
[singing from the Sun Ring above]
[merchant]
Ah, you're everything I'm not, strong, brave, active.
Come, talk a spell.
Alright, what did you want to discuss?
You're an outlander which is good, but a Nora which might be bad.
Do you fear the ruins of the Old Ones like many in your tribe?
No, although some can be dangerous.
Then you may have come across what I seek.
In your travels have you found strange vessels
emblazoned with symbols of the Old Ones?
They consist of a hollow cylinder with a crescent handle affixed at both ends.
If you bring me these vessels in sets of four, I will gladly trade what I have for them.
So you are interested in the Old Ones?
More than interested!
I study every ancient artifact I can get my hands on.
But years of study have made me too comfortable at my desk.
I can't even bear the sun, if the truth be known.
I don't know how I'll manage to take a partner.
My family presses me for an heir.
Uh, don't look at me.
Oh, no, no, no, I'm not looking.
In fact, my father already has someone he wants me to wed.
She doesn't interest me.
I wish I had a brother to carry this burden.
I would rather be left to my precious little vessels.
What sort of ritual were these vessels made for?
I'm convinced they were used in conjunction with each other in sets.
Some people believe they were used for tea ceremonies.
Others think they held sacred essences and oils for worship.
But I believe they were used for the solemn custom of shaving one's beard.
One for water, one for lotion, and so on.
Each fluid in its special vessel
majestically applied to the face at each stage of the rite.
It must have been breathtaking.
But which vessel was used for which? I have to know!
I have to continue my research!
Are you sure people didn't just drink out of them?
Drink? Out of such finally crafted earthenware?
Don't be ridiculous!
I will leave you to the hunt.
Be sure to delve into the ruins.
[Carja outlander]
I like Meridian fine, but I prefer the country.
Or at least I did before the machines got so bad.
[Carja noble]
I don't know about this ceasefire.
The Sundom prospers, Sunfall will want a piece of it eventually.
[Carja noble]
Who's gonna lead the Vanguard now, Erend?
The boy's a drunken wreck since the bastards got his sister.
[Carja noble]
Sun-King Avad hasn't got the stones to put an end to those traitors at Sunfall.
[Carja guard]
We all have our place in the order of things.
[Carja artisan]
Good day.
[Carja guard]
There are no shadows under the noonday sun. Words to live by.
Greetings Aloy.
I am known as Blameless Marad.
Please come with me.
You're needed for an important consultation.
What do you mean?
Where's Erend?
He's inside attending the Sun-King.
Where we should be without further delay.
Follow me, please.
[Marad]
The Sun-King is eager to meet you.
The machine tamer with a curious eye for detail.
[Marad]
It's all very intriguing.
[Aloy]
I'm not here to intrigue you.
[Marad]
Too late.
[Aloy]
All of these people are here to see the Sun-King?
[Marad]
Yes, and each has come to ask a favour of him.
Unpleasant, but that's politics.
[Carja noble]
First the Oseram get special treatment,
and now outlanders from the Savage East?
[Carja noble]
What possible interest could the Sun-King have in her?
Passed by some outlander woman? Unacceptable.
[Carja noble]
I've been here for two hours and this Nora goes to the front of the line.
[Marad]
Ignore them.
Nobles are like children who whine when they don't get a second helping of dessert.
[Aloy]
What's the Sun-King like?
[Marad]
The most important thing is what he isn't like — his father.
I think you'll find him to be a reasonable man.
Aloy of the Nora, she who sees the unseen. Welcome.
It would seem you have done me a great service.
Erend.
Tell her what you found.
I checked Ersa's tomb.
You were right, Aloy.
The body is missing a scar below her right knee.
I gave it to Ersa when we were kids fighting over a toy sword.
If the body is not Ersa's then we must assume she is still alive.
And I will not abandon her.
We only know she was taken, not who took her.
I can help with that.
Ersa has an enemy among the Oseram.
A warlord named Dervahl.
Impossible!
Every clan in The Claim has been hunting for him since the liberation.
He has to be dead by now.
No other Oseram had the motive and ingenuity to lure Ersa into this trap.
I expect to find him lurking somewhere near the border.
I've already sent an agent to investigate.
He'll be waiting for word from us at the market place in Pitchcliff.
I can't move troops to the border without provoking the Oseram.
But I could send a few Vanguardsmen.
And perhaps an exceptionally gifted Nora as well?
Erend, Marad, let me discuss it with her privately.
I hate to impose further after all you've done,
but this is a matter of great importance to me.
It sounds like Ersa means a lot to you.
Without her Oseram Vanguard, I would not have been able
to liberate Meridian and end my father's brutal reign.
Since then, it has been difficult to maintain peace between our tribes.
But Ersa has a way of making her people see reason.
So you see, I need her back at my side.
And quickly.
Why would Dervahl go to so much trouble to kidnap Ersa?
He felt she betrayed him.
She fought by his side until she realised
he planned to raze Meridian and butcher its people.
And she came to me.
Together, we stopped him and liberated the city from my father.
He truly thought of himself as a Sun God.
His mind was broken.
He believed that blood sacrifice would solve, well, everything.
So he raided the other tribes for victims, especially the Oseram.
Dervahl fought back.
He crafted powerful weapons and rallied his people.
My father responded with the ultimate cruelty.
He captured Dervahl's wife and daughter.
And sacrificed them in the Sun Ring.
Dervahl has spent every moment since trying to get revenge.
Your politics seem very complicated.
The Oseram are friends, but enemies too.
I couldn't have liberated Meridian without
the help of Ersa and her Oseram Freebooters.
Many of them have settled here.
But the ealdormen of the Oseram clans in The Claim
have become jealous of their success.
So have many Carja nobles.
It's a volatile situation, especially given the fact
that my father raided the Oseram for years.
Ersa helps keep the peace.
Promising a future based on mutual gain.
But some, like Dervahl, will never let go of their venom.
I'd like to ask you something about the Sundom and its politics.
By all means.
What can you tell me about the Shadow Carja?
What do they have to do with Ersa?
They are remnants of my father's regime,
holding out at the fortress of Sunfall to the west.
Like him, they care only for domination.
And seek to draw upon the power of the Sun by spilling blood in its name.
Since Ersa helped me take this city from them, they were perfect scapegoats.
Dervahl knew this, of course, and planned it well.
I need to get going.
I know.
Well, they say kings should never beg.
But please, help me find Ersa.
Who says that?
Marad, for one.
Don't hesitate to ask him or Erend if you have further questions.
[Carja guard]
It's not what I imagined when I was a boy, but it's decent work keeping the city safe.
Aloy, how can I be of service?
Why do they call you "Blameless Marad"?
Well, it depends on who you mean by "they".
And what "they" might wish to blame me for.
[sighs] Talking to you is tiring.
So they say.
What is it you do exactly?
Whatever is needed of course.
Are you always so evasive?
It depends.
You were right about Avad.
He seems genuine.
He is the Sun-King.
I serve him the best I can.
Huh, did you serve the last one as best you could too?
Well, I served him to his enemies.
It was the best I could do for the Sundom.
What did you do?
Nothing I could be blamed for.
What will I find at the border?
An outpost full of Oseram, most of whom want nothing to do with Dervahl.
Still, he inspires great loyalty in those who fought with him against the last Sun-King.
He will not be caught alone.
And don't forget he is a master craftsman.
Nothing delights him more than his dangerous toys.
What makes you so sure Dervahl did this to Ersa?
I don't care for sure or certain, I prefer likely or probably.
How many Oseram are clever enough for this ruse?
Capable of building the weapon you describe, who hate Ersa so?
More than one? Not likely.
Dervahl? Quite probably.
Even if people think he's dead?
That is surely another reason to be suspicious of certain words.
It's time for me to leave.
It would appear so.
[sighs] So, I thought Ersa was dead and I thought Dervahl was dead.
Dead doesn't seem to mean what it used to.
All I know is that it's time to find my sister and get some payback.
I hope Marad's guy grabs us a lead.
Did Ersa ever tell you anything about Dervahl?
We were both under his command for a while, sort of.
Helped him recruit an army to take out the mad Sun-King.
But then he got real creepy with Ersa.
Needless to say, she wasn't interested but he wouldn't let it go.
Not to mention the fact that we realised he wanted to murder every Carja.
Not just the bad ones.
Long story short, he's a Grazer-licking dungbag.
Avad seems committed to finding your sister.
Yeah, those two got along.
Some people say they shacked up, but I don't buy it.
Seems a little skinny for her.
Okay, some bad images are forming in my head.
Let's just focus on finding her and kicking Dervahl's ass.
Don't stand me up in Pitchcliff, okay? Ersa needs us.
[Carja guard]
Meridian. I couldn't imagine living anywhere else.