Let's get on with it!
Calm, calm.
Back to your business.
Nutritious.
My Focus is picking up some kind of signal.
Maybe I could scan it.
This'll last.
Okay, they're heading back.
Just stay out of their way for now.
Can stop tensing up.
I can still get the upper hand.
They're scanning for me.
I thought they'd go on forever.
A cauldron.
There's gotta be a way in, somehow.
I wonder what's down here.
Some kind of liquid flowing through that pipe.
Looks like I'm not the first to look for a way in.
What a waste.
These will keep.
They were curious too, but I'm better prepared.
I hope it's enough.
That circular device.
What does it do?
Looks like things are going my way.
That rushing sound again.
Need to find a way through that shell.
Can't have you giving away the hunt.
Makes this a little easier.
Alright, that should get me through.
Not this time.
Save these for the trail.
Easier when I was a kid.
Saving these for the trail.
You're down, the others haven't noticed.
The machines collect Blaze from the wilds.
And it all flows here, like blood to a heart.
So the Cauldron runs on life itself.
Calm, calm.
I need to be closer to use that.
I'm safe, for a few minutes anyway.
Now's my chance!
Low and quiet does it.
I'd have to ditch something.
You're alert.
I'd have to leave something else behind.
That's where I need to go.
The belly of this giant beast.
Can't be too prepared.
That's where I need to go.
Can't carry more.
They're scanning for me.
Red light!
This is beginning to get a lot harder.
Passed the test.
That's it, more machines I can override.