I live in Lone Light.
I barely escaped because Glinthawks attack anyone who ventures out.
We have so few shards.
Will you help?
We have nowhere else to turn.
Sometimes members receive an honorarium for the hunt.
Ahsis should have accepted this one, but he refused.
The price was too low.
How generous.
In the past, I would have gone with Tarkas to handle this.
What say you and I take it on?
I'll meet you at Lone Light.
What about Redmaw?
Are you in or not?
Alright, I'll meet you there as soon as I can.
A start!
That'll keep my stomach quiet.
By the Sun! Are you Nora?
I've never seen one at a Hunting Grounds before.
Or the Hunters Lodge.
How interesting.
Who are you? Where are you here?
Well, I'm a hunter, of course, and a member of the Hunters Lodge.
But I don't mind being out here.
At least no one complains about my clothes, or my manners, or my personality.
"Don't let him in, he'll drive people off with his incessant chattering"
or "he stinks of fish again", that sort of thing.
I don't stink of fish, do I?
No, it's more like wet fur.
Well, that's something.
What do you do here?
The trials here focus on the most important part of hunting.
Keeping your stamina up.
Hunting isn't a sprint.
It's a gauntlet.
So all you offer is training?
What trial will you run today?
The remains of Watchers rest on three rises.
Loot all of them before time runs out and you'll pass.
It sounds simple, but watch out for all the other machines down there.
I'll start timing once you slide down the rope.
You won a Blazing Sun on your first attempt!
Congratulations!
For this trial you'll need to be able to tie down
a Trampler and shoot off a component.
But you'll need the right weapon first.
in this trial, you must tie down a Trampler and shoot off the component under its belly.
I'll start timing once you choose a rope.
You won a Blazing Sun on your first attempt!
Congratulations!
Now's your chance to show you can snare Glinthawks.
Lure them close to you, then tie them down in time to pass this test.
Are you ready?
Spotted!
You won a Blazing Sun on your first attempt!
Congratulations!
I should leave for now.
'Til the next hunt!
[Talanah]
About time you showed up, more Glinthawks incoming!
More coming!
[Talanah]
You're not walking away from this.
Better. No more time to recover.
That seems to have taken care of them.
But more always come.
The soldiers at Morning's Watch don't even bother to fight them anymore.
It seems like they're coming from upriver.
I could track them back to the source, but if more come here…
I'll watch the village, you go ahead.
I thought you wanted to do this together?
You don't need me to hold your hand.
Patterns on this flower are so strange.
[Carja outlander]
For the Sundom!
I've just got to tough the storm out.
More Glinthawks.
You're not gonna like this!
There!
There are Snapmaw carcasses everywhere.
No wonder the Glinthawks were drawn here.
Those blinds, amateurs will leave easy tracks to follow.
These must be the Snapmaw hunters.
I'm here on behalf of the nearby village.
Seems your kill zone is creating a Glinthawk problem for them.
Yeah, well, they're not the only people with problems.
If we don't get enough Snapmaw hearts to pay off a loan, we lose everything.
I don't follow?
I borrowed shards to buy seeds.
The harvest went bust, and now they're coming for the debt.
We could lose the farm, our home.
I'm sorry about that.
But Glinthawks are attacking people because of what you're doing here.
Not my problem.
None of us are leaving until I get what I came for.
None of us?
You didn't think it was just us two, did you?
I'll make it simple for you.
Stop slaughtering machines for one component, leaving the rest to waste.
Now I'll make it simple for you.
That's not going to happen.
So get out of here.
Seems we've come to an impasse.
Make your move.
So be it.
[Carja outlander]
Enjoy your last breath!
[in the distance]
Aloy!
Fools! Bit off more than they could chew.
What a waste.
But now I know you can handle yourself.
You were watching the whole time?
Of course.
Tarkas, may the Sun light his passing, taught me many things.
First of which was: a Hawk never abandons their Thrush.
Wait, are you saying…?
I'd like to sponsor you for membership.
What do you say to hunting machines, winning trophies, and unseating Ahsis?
I'm in.
I'll meet you back at the Lodge as soon as I'm able.
I can always use these.