I will not abandon her.
We only know she was taken.
Not who took her.
I can help with that.
Ersa has an enemy among the Oseram.
A warlord named Dervahl.
I expect to find him lurking somewhere near the border.
I've already sent an agent to investigate.
He'll be waiting for word from us at the market place in Pitchcliff.
I can't move troops to the border without provoking the Oseram.
But I could send a few Vanguardsmen.
And perhaps an exceptionally gifted Nora as well?
Little more.
Need them soon enough.
Low and quiet does it.
Hello!
These'll keep.
[Oseram]
Can't get a wink of sleep.
The beds around here, just like the people, too damn soft.
This must be Pitchcliff.
Marad's agent should be in the market place by now.
[Oseram worker]
Got a pair of sturdy Oseram hands, know how to put 'em to use.
There'll always be work for me.
[Oseram worker]
There's plenty of work here, but not light.
No sign of Marad's guy?
He's had plenty of time to investigate.
We'd better look for him.
Damn right.
Well, someone left here recently and they were in a hurry.
[Oseram worker]
…wink of sleep. Bought my bed from a Carja, just like them its soft.
[Oseram outlander]
Every resident of this city deserves safety and security. That's the deal.
Has to be Marad's guy.
Dervahl's thugs must have made him.
Maybe because he found something.
Look at this.
I think he drew a map with his own blood.
Right, those kind of maps you know you'd better follow.
That might be Pitchcliff.
He marked a spot to the north.
Could be Dervahl's location.
My men are waiting outside of town.
I'll grab them and meet you there.
[whistle]
Let's make this quick.
Here they come.
Come on, now!
Machines, looks like they've been chained up.
Dervahl's a tinker.
He probably experiments on them.
Or strips them for parts.
Maybe I can use them to make some trouble.
I'll go in first.
Hold off until the fighting starts.
Alright, we've got your back.
Dervahl's men.
It's about to get ugly.
[Erend]
I hope so.
[Oseram Vanguardsman]
By the forge, move!
Low and quiet does it.
Dervahl says you gotta eat dirt.
Okay, no more sneaking.
[Erend]
Ersa must be in there.
We have to get through.
They must use these to protect themselves from that awful sound.
Ersa!
Erend?
Dervahl tried to break me.
Shows what he knows.
I should have been with you.
Why didn't you come for me?
I know I'm a useless drunk, but…
No, idiot.
I got a message from Dervahl saying he wanted to parlay.
I didn't come for you because I knew it was a trap.
I couldn't let you get hurt.
Just didn't think it'd be that good a trap.
Thought I could take him out.
[coughs]
Now, listen.
Dervahl's planning something big in Meridian.
He said he'd force Avad to watch as the smoke darkens their precious Sun.
Your king needs you.
No more playing around.
You're gonna have to grow up fast.
I will.
I promise.
You damn well better little brother.
Ersa!
No, no! Please!
I won't let you down.
I promise.
Erend, I'm…
I'm so sorry.
We've gotta find Dervahl.
But Meridian's a big place.
I'll…
I'll look through his things.
Maybe we can narrow it down.
Just give me some time with Ersa.
Such a strange device.
It's beautifully crafted.
What happens when I turn it on?
[Dervahl]
"I think I've got it working."
"There. Now, say something, both of you doves."
[Dervahl's wife]
"I don't know. What do you want me to say?"
[Dervahl]
"Whatever you want."
[Dervahl's wife]
"I just want to hear your voice and keep it for later."
[Dervahl's daughter]
"I'll sing Papa! La la la la la la la!"
"[giggles]"
[Dervahl]
"There, a song and a laugh."
"Even better than words."
[Dervahl]
"And now I can hear them whenever I want."
[Dervahl's wife]
"We're done then? Off to bed with you."
[Dervahl's daughter]
"Good night, Mama."
"Good night, Papa."
[Dervahl's wife]
"Is she gone?"
"What are we going to do?"
[Dervahl's wife]
"The raids are getting closer and closer to Mainspring."
"How much longer can we hide like this?"
A keepsake from his family.
Dervahl's got nothing left to lose.
This machine's been picked apart with precision.
What's Dervahl learned from all his tinkering?
Do I even want to know?
Dervahl's records maybe?
Just notes about crafting.
Oh, and a letter tucked between the pages.
Lots of Blaze headed to Meridian.
If we find it, I'll bet we find Dervahl too.
I think I found something that can help.
Let's head back to the palace.
Go.
I won't be long, but I need to tend to my sister.
[whistle]
Here they come.
They saw us.
Low and quiet does it.
I'll find a use for you.
Here we go again.
Those Glinthawks must be here for the scrap.
[Carja outlander]
…only experience adventure…