Got one.
You'll do.
Fresh as it comes.
Down you go!
Can stop tensing up.
That should be enough fluid.
These things are hard to catch.
Stay down!
Save these for the trail.
[Bandit thug]
She's coming for us!
It's killing time!
[Bandit thug]
I'll finish you!
Got another shot for ya!
[Bandit thug]
Wanna play? Here's your invitation.
Forget about travelling light.
Rain. Ah well, I'm mostly waterproof.
Okay, alarm's down.
Still sniffing around.
They've taken those travellers captive.
I'll get this open, hold on.
It's all right, I'm getting you out.
Got too much already.
[Carja guard]
We need warriors like her, ready to stand up for the Sundom.
[Carja outlander]
She didn't even hesistate…
That crazy Oseram tried to kill our Sun-King,
but the machine rider stopped him.
[Carja outlander]
Lucky that the Nora was there to protect the Sun-King.
What on earth were the Vanguard doing?
[Carja guard]
We will never be able to repay you for the life of our Sun-King.
Just because he failed to kill the Sun-King,
doesn't mean he's any less guilty. He should pay.
Can't be too prepared.
This must be Sunstone Rock.
It's being attacked by machines!
[Carja guard]
I don't like our chances!
You wanna tell Warden Janeva we backed down?
[Carja guard]
Let's take our chances!
Victory is ours.
[Carja guard]
You pulled us out of a tough spot, outlander.
Welcome to Sunstone Rock.
[Carja guard]
You should speak to Warden Janeva, inside.
We have won.
[Carja archer]
By the Sun, it's over.
[Carja guard]
It was a machine lure.
We don't know how they got it.
[Warden Janeva]
Rasgrund concealed the parts on his person, no doubt.
[Carja guard]
We searched him. How…?
[Warden Janeva]
You don't want to know how.
[Carja guard]
Always stay bright, always stay alert. That's what I say.
Warden Janeva, this is the one who defeated the Behemoths.
Outlander, I'm impressed. I don't impress easily.
Tell me, how do you fare with hunting living prey?
Haven't had any complaints. Why?
Three dangerous prisoners have escaped.
I need my men here getting the others back in line.
None of this would have happened
if we dealt with criminals the old way.
But I've clashed that gong before.
And here I am.
And here you are.
What's the old way?
To be buried up to the neck and left for the Sun's judgement.
Seems to me like the judgment's already been made.
Not one of them committed another crime.
So the Carja keep their criminals in this place?
Since the liberation.
We've had them all from thieves
to the mad King Jiran's former Kestrels.
The Sun-King believes in the power of change.
And sure enough, some did change.
Shed their skin, like lizards.
I thought all criminals were the same once.
That's why the Sun-King gave me command of Sunstone Rock.
As an education.
Sounds like an honour.
I mean, I haven't seen any other women in Carja armour…
No, I'm not one of your sisters.
No woman can wear Carja armour.
When I was young, I chose to become a soldier.
One good enough to join Avad's honour guard.
There was talk about what I was.
So I'd say "Test me, then I'll break your arm".
After enough arms had been broken there was less talk.
I'm curious, but I'd rather we didn't have to start fighting.
Agreed.
So you want these prisoners brought back?
No, I want them put in the earth.
I doubt they'll give you any choice.
They had their chance with the Sun-King's generosity.
So now they face mine.
A bounty on all their heads.
Who are these dangerous prisoners?
Three from the isolation cages.
Don't feel sorry for them.
They've lived well off the Sun-King's conscience.
First, is Rasgrund. Oseram trap maker, hates the Carja.
Crazy as a loon in heat.
Caught in one too many blasts, or one too few.
Then there's Ullia, a Tenakth warrior,
if that means anything to you.
Not really, another tribe?
Reavers from the south, bloodthirsty.
Some say they're cannibals, but she slurped gruel well enough.
And the last is Gavan,
a traitor who smuggled weapons to the exiles.
Compared to the other two, this one doesn't seem so bad.
He helped drag out a civil war.
All for the shards it got him.
A machine has more warmth.
If I did this for you, I'd need a lead on them.
Well, when Ullia first swept through the Sundom,
it was with the jungle bandits.
I say she'll go back.
Rasgrund we pulled out of a crack in Dusk Mesa,
where he'd been tinkering with his bombs.
And Gavan will be trying to pay his way across the lake.
I'd burn my palm on it.
Look in Brightmarket.
Need them soon enough.
Okay, I already got rid of the bandits.
I don't think it'll be hard to find this warrior.
[Ullia]
I told you they would come. Drive her into the dirt!
No way we could have talked about this, huh?
All the Carja did was talk.
Talk and bleed, and talk and shackle me.
But you? You fought like a Tenakth.
I'd have taken you for my child.
You can't just take a child.
The strong take from the weak,
and in the taking are made stronger.
These stories, pricked into my skin.
Look!
Children, riches, lives, and land.
All of these have been mine.
Drink of my [cough] my blood and I'll live on.
No, Ullia.
I've got enough stories to carry.
[Carja guard]
Did she really save the Sun-King? A Nora?
[Carja villager]
The Sundom's grown too soft.
Too much Oseram influence at the palace.
[Carja villager]
What's he thinking letting Dervahl live?