So you want these prisoners brought back?
No. I want them put in the earth.
I doubt they'll give you any choice.
They had their chance with the Sun-King's generosity.
So now they face mine. A bounty on all their heads.
If I did this for you, I need a lead on them.
Rasgrund we pulled out of a crack in Dusk Mesa,
where he'd been tinkering with his bombs.
And Gavan will be trying to pay his way across the lake.
I'd burn my palm on it.
Look in Brightmarket.
Never know when I might need these.
It's down!
Let's get this over with.
Ah, damn.
Hardly little plant. You'll help.
Gotta keep the upper hand.
[Bandit thug]
What's the matter, girl, scared?
…for some pain.
[Bandit thug]
Wanna play?
Keep that for later.
Got their attention!
Here we go again.
[Rasgrund]
Ho there!
I thought they'd send soldiers.
[Rasgrund]
The mighty Carja empire must be more strapped than I thought.
How sad.
[Rasgrund]
No matter, bounty hunters die like the rest.
Welcome to my ravine of death.
[Aloy]
Are you serious?
[Rasgrund]
Sadist, murderer, trap-maker. All these things.
That's why they put me in that stinking hole.
[Rasgrund]
I'm curious.
I don't suppose those Behemoths
I called to the prison killed Janeva?
[Aloy]
You're gonna be disappointed.
[Rasgrund]
Yup, that's why I have my toys. To distract me from the pain.
Still alive?
[Aloy]
Yes!
[Rasgrund]
Oh, you're a trickster.
Careful now, don't slip.
[Rasgrund]
Not yet, little acrobat.
Whoopsie!
[Rasgrund]
But you're not on fire yet!
Persistent aren't you?
[Rasgrund]
You got me. No more traps.
Tell Janeva I'll be a good boy from now on.
You expect me to believe that?
What's in your hand?
Oh, this? Oh just a little… oops.
I guess he died doing what he loved.
Stocking up.
[whistle]
No turning back!
Another hit in.
I'll tuck that away.
Some kind of figurine?
I think it's Banuk.
Now they're hunting me.
[whistle]
Sun's headed for the west.
[Carja villager]
The Sun-King owes his life to an outlander.
What a strange time we live in.
If this Gavan came through here,
the inn seems like a good place to start asking.
As the Sun is my witness, never had a Nora in my house.
What about a man named Gavan?
Umm, no.
Can't say I've heard that name.
But we're a trading town, get a lot of people through.
All kinds I'm sure, like ones who don't want to be followed.
I never heard of your Gavan.
If he's trouble, well, can't say I'm sorry.
Now I have things to be doing Nora girl, if you don't mind.
Well, he wasn't suspicious at all.
Time to take a look around.
[Carja villager]
How did he get so close to the Sun-King?
The Oseram guard will be blaming their shadows for their mistakes.
Hello, Gavan. You wouldn't have gotten this off without help.
You didn't make for the harbour.
And you didn't go alone.
Clever!
So, did Gavan find his friends or his enemies?
Suppose they're all the same to me.
Looks like they're not happy to see him back.
[Hashiv]
Don't you pass out, Gavan! I'm not done with you.
If you can break out of Sunstone Rock,
you can take a bit of knife play, can't you?
[Hashiv]
You didn't break out. You're a snitch.
Come to bring Meridian down on us.
[Hashiv]
This is my operation now, so I have to make a show of you.
Hey!
[Bandit thug]
Get down or get shot!
So they woke up.
They sent you to take me back to Sunstone?
Not to take you back.
Huh, well, Hashiv's done your job for you.
Janeva said you were a smuggler only for the shards.
Is that true?
I could tell you anything.
A sick mother, or I did it for the poor children.
But you'd be lying.
In the year I spent in a cage,
all I regretted was killing that guard because it got me caught.
You can take that back to Sunstone Rock.