Maker's End, not much farther now.
Olin said he found an image of the woman I resemble on an ancient device.
If she's my mother, why would there be traces of her
all the way out here, so far from Nora land?
I don't get it. Who is she?
[voice from Focus]
Her name is Elisabet Sobeck.
[Aloy]
You! Spying through my Focus again?
Well, go on, what do you know about her?
[voice from Focus]
Stay on your present course and before long
you'll know her as well as I do. Maybe better.
[voice from Focus]
But be wary.
Maker's End is crawling with Eclipse troops.
[voice from Focus]
To help you deal with them, I've left some useful equipment just outside the ruins.
Hardy little plant, you'll help.
Nutritious.
How much will this snow cover?
Move along now.
Can breathe again.
[Cultist]
Got to get the demons raised.
Might be able to take them out one by one, if I stay out of sight.
[Cultist]
Who did this?
Don't mind me.
[Cultist]
Whoa…!
Right where he said it would be.
Not a bad selection.
I'll put those to use.
Why are you doing this?
[voice from Focus]
Because I want you to succeed.
Good hunting, we'll talk later.
Wait!
Pff, damn him.
It's heavy, world's going white.
Okay, you're okay.
Might regret this.
[Voice from Vantage cache]
Apocashitstorm Tour, day one.
Where better to start than at the end?
[Voice from Vantage cache]
Or where the end started anyway.
Ground zero.
[Voice from Vantage cache]
Where it all came crashing down.
My career first.
[Voice from Vantage cache]
Then everything else.
And I mean everything.
No room.
Corrupted Watchers, acting as guards.
The Eclipse and corrupted machines, co-operating.
One happy family.
[Cultist]
Got a body over here.
The Shadow gives you strength, use it!
I'd have to ditch something.
These dig sites, they're massive.
Snow chill, itches.
Should've brought a cart.
All these ruins. What did the Old Ones do here?
Okay, no more sneaking.
Quietly.
[Cultist]
… take a look at that guard.
Corruptor. Might prove a challenge.
Got too much already.
Full already.
What have they been uncovering here?
I can't spare the weight.
Snow haze, white as bone. Huh, that thought got dark.
An explosion?
Another explosion.
[in the distance]
All weapons operational.
Time to get it moving, and be quick about it.
[in the distance]
No daydreaming.
Rotate turret!
Aaaaand fire!
Has to be one of the Deathbringers Olin talked about.
Fitting name.
[Cultist officer]
My Focus, it's stopped working.
[Voice from Focus]
I've disabled his Focus. The rest is up to you.
[Aloy]
I'll handle it.
I'll never get into that tower, unless I destroy that thing first.
Steam's blasting out. I wonder if those are weak points?
[Cultist]
What's that in the tall grass?
Gotcha!
[Cultist]
Bleed for the Shadow!
Ha! Hitting that thing really hurt it!
Got too much already.
No room.
Let's see what you have to say.
What … what is this?
[Metallic voice from Focus]
THE ENTITY LIVES?
UNACCEPTABLE! UNACCEPTABLE! UNACCEPTABLE!
What the hell was that?
Hades?
Hey, mysterious stranger.
Did you see that?
No answer, huh? Figures.
Things just keep getting stranger.
I need to find a way inside the tower.
Looks tight, but I can squeeze through.
[Computer]
Hold for Identiscan.
Huh, one of these again.
pffff
[Computer]
Genetic profile confirmed. Entry authorised.
Greetings Dr Sobeck. Please step inside.