[Computer]
Genetic profile confirmed. Entry authorised.
Greetings, Doctor Sobeck. Please, step inside.
[Computer]
Doctor Sobeck, you are 355,510 days overdue for your meeting with Mr Faro.
Please proceed to the 35th floor.
Wait, wait, wait … three hundred and fifty thousand?
That's hundreds of years ago.
What's going on?
Forget about travelling light.
[first recorded voice]
The protocols used polyphasic entangled waveforms.
Quantum encryption, black quartz stuff, way beyond military grade.
[first recorded voice]
That's what you demanded.
So that's what we delivered.
[second recorded voice]
You don't code something you can't crack.
All we need is a backdoor.
[second recorded voice]
Upload the latest service update and the problem goes away.
[first recorded voice]
You specifically forbade us from leaving anything resembling a backdoor in code.
Every protocol to Black Quartz standard, your words.
[first recorded voice]
Look, if you need me to fudge some projections,
it's nothing we haven't done before.
[second recorded voice]
I don't need fudged projections!
I need a way to reassert control over the Hartz-Timor swarm.
[first recorded voice]
I don't know what to tell you, Ted.
You're asking the impossible.
So, codes.
They needed codes of some kind to control the machines,
but they got out of control.
Sounds bad.
I can't spare the weight.
A Deathbringer.
Or a statue of one, anyway.
A machine built to kill. And they honoured it?
[Hologram]
Welcome to Faro Automated Solutions, where
all the problems of tomorrow are being solved today.
[Hologram]
With over 25,000 human employees
based in nations and corporate holdings across the globe,
[Hologram]
Faro leads the world in every sector
of self sustaining, fully automated technology.
[Hologram]
From revolutionary consumer products close to home,
like the Faro Focus,
[Hologram]
to the dynamic Chariot line of peace-keeping robots
halting bloodshed in conflict zones across the globe,
[Hologram]
Faro remains committed to making the future
smarter, brighter, safer, and always surprising.
[Hologram]
Faro Automated Solutions.
For every problem of life, a smart solution.
[Aloy]
So they made the Focus.
25,000 people? That's bigger than a tribe.
So they made machines and devices.
I guess those things were common in their world.
What was this place?
What were they doing here?
[voice from Focus]
It was a corporation.
A group of people, not unlike a tribe.
[voice from Focus]
And they made machines.
[Aloy]
Yeah, go on.
[voice from Focus]
I've uploated some data files to your Focus.
They'll help you understand.
[Ted Faro]
Now I know this must seem like a bizarre change in direction.
I mean, we're Faro Automated Solutions, right?
[Ted Faro]
Number one robotics firm in the world.
Why would we clear our production slate to fabricate
human operated vehicles and weapons systems?
[Ted Faro]
The relics of the past.
All I can say at this juncture is…
[Ted Faro]
…trust me.
We will be exploiting a massive uh, growth opportunity
by retooling and reallocating capacity according to my plan.
[Ted Faro]
So I will need revised projections of mass fabrication
velocity across every pipeline within 36 hours.
[Aloy]
So they were making machines.
Then they stopped to make other kinds of weapons. Why?
The air.
There's no smell to it, not even old death.
Nothing natural.
Should have brought a cart.
Another cave-in, but I could get through.
Looks like I can climb here.
I bet I can use that as a ramp to get back up.
Made it.
[Hologram]
The FSP5 Khopesh provides a one-size-fits-all solution
to main battle force capability.
[Hologram]
Metamaterial construction delivers unmatched recoil dampening.
Allowing you to field any weapon package that conforms
to your budget needs and conflict resolution profile.
[Hologram]
Patented biomass conversion systems allow
extended emergency operations with minimal environmental impact.
[Hologram]
Multilinear target processing provides simultaneous real-time threat analysis
and legal review for autonomous domestic operations.
[Hologram]
Or control can be slaved to the swarm's neural network
for weapons-free force application.
[Hologram]
Either way, when it's time to call out the big guns, it's time to call Khopesh.
[Aloy]
The Deathbringer.
So this was the heavy hitter. "Main battle force" indeed.
[Hologram]
The BOR7 Horus.
Imagine your complete engagement ecosystem comprehensively managed
by a high-speed learning machine network.
[Hologram]
Whether your need is to replace battlefield losses or intensify force projection,
the Horus's onboard manufacturing capabilities mean
you'll never get stuck waiting for the next arms delivery.
[Hologram]
Simply redefine your force parameters and the Horus will fabricate additional units
to fill the ranks for an affordable per-unit licencing fee.
[Hologram]
Meanwhile, the biomass conversion systems of other Chariot line models
allow them to keep the Horus fuelled, repaired, and ready.
[Hologram]
Extending its operational tolerances beyond that
of any competing titan-class platform.
[Hologram]
That's the Horus advantage. Always regulating, always ready.
The future of automated warfare made real today.
[Aloy]
The Metal Devil.
So these were Faro machines too.
"Manufacturing capabilities" — they could make more of themselves.
Then how would you ever stop them?
[Hologram]
The ACA3 Scarab combines conventional
and information warfare capabilities in one package.
[Hologram]
Designed for high-speed, all-terrain reconnaissance.
It boasts the world's highest survivability rating
of any scout-class autonomous agent.
[Hologram]
Maybe it's the Scarab's emergency biomass conversion systems
that ensure it always makes it back to base.
[Hologram]
Even if fuel supply lines have been interdicted.
Or maybe it's the Scarab's ability to slave enemy robots to its own network.
[Hologram]
Now that's force multiplication.
Add a prehensile manipulator arm that can handle a host of functions.
[Hologram]
From 360-degree less lethal riot management,
to surgical repairs of allied Chariot line models.
[Hologram]
And you've got the workhorse of any cutting edge peace-keeping fleet.
[Aloy]
The Corruptor.
"Slave enemy robots to its own network".
Sounds like its talking about how it corrupts machines.
I'd have to ditch something.
So people were angry at Faro.
At the corporation.
They blamed this place for something, something bad.
Looks like the way up.
What's left of it.
Gonna be a long way up.
Frozen metal most of the way.
You're not making this easy, Doctor Sobeck.
If plants can find a way to hang on up here, guess I can too.
Freezing out here.
[Ted Faro]
…that began when they engaged in unauthorised offensive operations against robots and human personnel of the Hartz-Timor Energy Combine.
Now I wish that I could relay that the crisis has been…
[Ted Faro]
…exaggerated, but it's not.
The peacekeepers have not responded to stand down codes.
[Ted Faro]
And by all signs they appear to be replicating at a… precipitous rate.
Now what I can promise you and absolutely assure you…
[Ted Faro]
…is that I am already devoting every possible resource
towards reaching a speedy conclusion to this issue.
[Ted Faro]
So when you hear the bad talk about us, against this company,
in the days, maybe weeks, to come,
just bear in mind that we will get past this.
[Ted Faro]
And a day's coming when none of this will matter.
[Aloy]
"Peacekeepers" — that's what they called their machines?
They were built for war, not peace.
Tasty.
Got too much already.
A way up.
All it takes is a few good handholds.
All right, made it. Wonder what we'll find?
I'd have to ditch something.
A power cell.
I'll need it to get to the armour in that ancient ruin I found.
Should've brought a cart.
[Computer]
All data has been erased from this device.
Do you wish to deploy Alpha privileges to recover purged data?
[Aloy]
Yes, I believe I do.
[Computer]
A file has been recovered.
[Ted Faro]
Elisabet, good to, uh…
It's been years.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Where's your legal team, Ted?
[Ted Faro]
No need, I dropped all 18 lawsuits the moment you landed.
I assume your data confirms this?
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Alright, this promises to be interesting.
[Ted Faro]
Perhaps we could have lunch brought in.
You know, get reacquainted…
[Elisabet Sobeck]
I know you Ted, you've screwed something up.
Something big, or you wouldn't have eaten the crow necessary to get me here.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
So spit it out.
[Ted Faro]
There's … a glitch in the Chariot line.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Your killer robots?
[Ted Faro]
Peacekeepers, yes, those.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
So shut them down.
[Ted Faro]
Obviously Liz, we would if we could.
They're not responding.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Are you telling me a swarm has gone rogue, Ted?
[Ted Faro]
It's worse than that.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
[sighs] Show me the data then.
And I'll take that lunch, alone.
Ted Faro brought Elisabet Sobeck here? But they hated each other.
[Computer]
Another file has been recovered.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
This isn't a "glitch".
It's a catastrophe.
[Ted Faro]
Fully aware.
It's bad.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Bad?
[Ted Faro]
Jesus, Liz.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
It's not bad, Ted.
It's apocalyptic.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
You built a line of killer robots…
[Ted Faro]
Peacekeepers!
[Elisabet Sobeck]
…that consume biomass as fuel!
[Ted Faro]
In emergencies!
[Elisabet Sobeck]
And you made them capable of self-replication!
[Ted Faro]
Limited self-manufacture, controlled.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Not any more.
The glitch severed chain of command.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
The only nation this swarm answers to now is itself.
[Ted Faro]
You, you think I di–
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Everything else is just food!
And at the rate it's replicating, Ted, it will strip the Earth bare in fifteen months.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
We're not talking the fall of civilisation.
We're talking extinction.
[Ted Faro]
I get it, Liz.
So how do I stop it while it's contained?
[Elisabet Sobeck]
It's not contained, it can't be!
[Ted Faro]
You know what I mean!
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Right, before the truth gets out, you mean.
[Ted Faro]
Liz, I will do anything you say.
Keep working it, and whatever you recommend, I'll do.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
I'm gonna hold you to that, Ted.
The Faro robots threatened all life on Earth, but somehow she defeated them.
The world of the Old Ones fell but life went on, or we wouldn't be here.
[Computer]
A final file has been recovered.
[Ted Faro]
"Project Zero Dawn"?
Jesus, Liz. There has to be another way.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
If there were a nicer way to fix your mess, I would have proposed it.
[Ted Faro]
But this? This?!
When I asked you to find a cure, I didn't expect it to be worse than the disease.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
It's not, Ted.
It may be grim, but it's our only chance.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Now sign the proposal.
[Ted Faro]
Sign it? I can't sign that!
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Yes, you can.
[Ted Faro]
That? Liz, I cannot in good conscience sign that.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
You've got a choice, Ted.
[Ted Faro]
I know.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
I'm speaking to you from a VTOL en-route to U.S. Robot Command.
In fifteen minutes, I meet with General Harris and the rest of the Joint Chiefs.
[Ted Faro]
Wh—what?! Are you crazy?
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Now your choice is what I tell them.
Sign and I'll tell them the wealthiest corporation on Earth
has guaranteed the funds necessary to build Zero Dawn.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Exactly as I've designed it.
Or don't sign and I will make sure they,
and everyone else on this planet, knows the real cause of the glitch.
[Ted Faro]
Jesus, Liz.
You don't have to threaten me.
[Ted Faro]
I'll sign.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Look on the bright side, Ted.
From here on out you get to do what you've always been good at.
[Elisabet Sobeck]
Footing the bill while others get their hands dirty.
[Ted Faro]
God forgive me.
What made her solution so terrible?
What did she do to stop the robots?
[Computer]
Executive access detected. Express lift opened.
This, this doesn't add up.
Sobeck couldn't have been my mother.
She lived ages ago.
All this searching and I'm still no closer.
[voice from Focus]
That's your reaction to everything you just learned?
To whine like a spoiled child?
You should really try talking that way to me face to face!
As you wish.
Do you really have no idea how monumental
are the discoveries you just made, Aloy?
I expected more of you.
So, you have a face.
Got a name to go with it?
Of all the questions you could ask right now, that's the one you choose?
I've spent decades searching the ruins of the Old Ones,
trying to solve the mystery of what happened to them.
For years I've suspected that Faro robots destroyed their civilisation.
But I could never confirm it.
And in minutes you uncover more ancient knowledge than I have in a lifetime.
And what you want to know is my name?
If you're so smart, why do you know so little
after a lifetime scratching around in the dirt?
It's not my fault you're bad at what you do.
I came to these ruins looking for Elisabet Sobeck.
Not because of the things she did centuries ago,
but because people are trying to kill me right now, today!
I've got bigger problems to deal with than your crap.
Congratulations.
You just graduated from whining to throwing a temper tantrum.
I'm sure Elisabet would be proud.
You have no idea what I've been through, how hard it's been.
My whole life I grew up not knowing who I am or where I came from.
And then come the Eclipse trying to kill me,
just because I look like this Elisabet Sobeck woman.
And they killed the man who raised you,
and you were found in the mountain as a baby.
I already know this through your Focus.
You've been getting a free ride on my Focus,
risking nothing while I risk everything.
All I have to do is take this thing off my head
and you'll be blind, deaf, and dumb.
So quit complaining and answer my questions.
Very well. Sylens. That's my name.
Now, why don't you try asking another question?
Something less trivial.
Every time I take a step forward, the answer slipped farther from my grasp.
[sighs] You just don't understand.
It's not that I don't understand, Aloy.
It's that I don't care.
If the answers keep slipping away every step you take,
then you'd best start running to catch up.
Maybe then you'll realise just how big your problems really are.
Alright Sylens, you've made your point.
I came to these ruins hoping to learn more
about this Elisabet Sobeck, and I have.
But I still don't understand my connection to her,
or why the Eclipse is trying to kill me, or who Hades is…
No answers, just one question after another.
Who are you Sylens, and what are your intentions?
You really need to make this personal?
I'm a lone wanderer who left his tribe behind a long time ago.
An explorer of forbidden places, a searcher of lost knowledge.
Exactly as I said.
Why do you know so much about the Eclipse?
I happen to know a lot about a lot of things.
If what you're really asking is whether I work
for the Eclipse or anyone else, I don't.
I'm nothing if not independent.
You've been using my Focus to spy on me.
How is that possible?
Every Focus emits a signal.
A voice that only other Focuses can hear.
I know how to string those voices together.
How to make them talk to each other, to communicate even over vast distances.
How do you learn to do that?
Years of study and experimentation.
In principle, it's not so different from how you override machines.
I override Focuses.
And you can spy through other Eclipse's Focuses too?
Usually.
All I'll say is that overriding the connections is … complicated.
That thing that spoke to me outside, that made that Focus explode?
That was Hades?
The Eclipse describe him as a buried shadow, some kind of devil.
It didn't seem like a person or a machine.
More like a phantom with a terrible voice.
All that certain is that he wants you dead.
Because of my connection to Elisabet, has to be.
Hades is using the Eclipse to resurrect Faro robots.
You said you've known for some time that
Faro war machines destroyed the civilisation of the Old Ones.
The evidence pointed that way.
But until now, I never knew the full scope of their danger.
That they could process organic matter into fuel.
Or that the Horus class could manufacture more robots.
Like a cauldron on legs.
But the robots we've seen so far,
the Corruptors and Deathbringers, they don't do those things.
Not yet, anyway.
So far, we haven't encountered any that are undamaged.
At full power who knows what they're capable of?
But if Elisabet found a way to stop them centuries ago…
In some of the ancient data I've recovered,
there are hints of so-called superweapons being developed.
Maybe Hades is worried I'll do the same thing.
This is speculation.
Wasting time.
Is there any chance that Elisabet Sobeck could still be alive somehow?
It's highly unlikely.
She couldn't have been my mother if she lived centuries ago.
Some of the ancient data I've recovered includes mentions of life extension techniques.
Pharmaceuticals mostly, an ancient word for medicine.
But some were still trying to perfect ways of freezing and unfreezing people.
Freezing and unfreezing people?
Cryogenics, they called it.
But there were problems with it.
Given Elisabet's technological acumen,
I can't definitively rule out that she found a way to make herself immortal.
The only way to find out is to keep going, to keep making discoveries.
Thanks to you, we've only just now learned
that Faro robots once threatened to end life on Earth.
But it didn't happen.
The Old Ones' civilisation was destroyed but life, life was saved.
Obviously. So what did Elisabet do?
How did she stop the robots before all was lost?
What was Project Zero Dawn?
Exactly the question.
Elisabet told Ted Faro she was headed for a place called
"U.S. Robot Command" to tell people about Zero Dawn.
The place still exists as a ruin.
The Oseram call it the Grave-Hoard.
"Grave-Hoard"? Cheery name.
You'll find it in the eastern mountains,
buried under the tangled coils of a Metal Devil.
Or a BOR7 Horus rather, as we're learning to call them.
I'll contact you when you get there.
I can't wait.
Some day we'll meet in person and your manners had better be improved.
Well, getting down will be a lot faster than getting up here at least.
U.S. Robot Command next.
To learn the secrets of Zero Dawn.