NALTUK: Perhaps Ourea should meet you after all.
NALTUK: What she truly seeks is hope.
After what I just saw, you could show her that.
She's in retreat beyond those mountains, the Icerasps.
You'll have to walk the Shaman's Path to get there.
Follow the markers through the ice caves
and the waterfalls, and make the climb to the shrine.
But be careful.
The path is meant to be an ordeal.
The final trial of a young Shaman's training.
And I'll find Ourea at the end of it?
No, she goes further up, somewhere inside the mountain.
You'll know you've reached the end when you come to a shrine,
a great machine covered in bluegleam.
Shamans who complete the path take a piece of it as reward.
If you make it that far, you should too. You'll have earned it.
I'm pretty far up. The Shaman's Path must be around here somewhere.
This must be one of the markers Naltuk told me about.
Looks like each marker points to another, giving directions.
Wrong way.
Guess I'm heading deeper into the cold, creepy ice cave.
This isn't the way out. Some gear, though.
What's this chime for?
To help guide the way with sound?
If there's more maybe my Focus could find them.
Yup, Focus can pick up the chimes. Should help me find my way.
Another marker, good.
This isn't the way out. Some gear, though.
Okay, that way then.
I took a wrong turn.
Not this way. Then, where?
Huh, I see, up.
Stalkers, better be careful.
Okay, through here.
Better go back … after I grab this loot.
There we go, hopefully out of this cave.
Done with the cave. So what's next on this path?
How does this bridge work?
It looks like it needs to fill up with water before I can cross.
Around the bend we go.
Now how do I cross this one?
Down? Looks like I need to get up to that rope.
Down it is.
There's the way up.
I need to pull the rope to move this thing into position.
Okay, the bridge is filling up.
Made it.
Could forget what warm feels like.
Burgrend wasn't exaggerating.
There's definitely something new out here, and I don't think it's friendly.
Don't like the sound of that.
Got too much already.
Scary new machine, down.
Now back to finding Ourea, which means I gotta climb.
I should be able to get up there.
This must be the shrine Naltuk was talking about.
Guess I should take some bluegleam.
Sparkles. I can see why it's worth a lot.
Naltuk said Ourea went past the shrine, up into the mountain.
I'd better take those stairs.
An ancient door, maybe Ourea is inside.
RECORDING: March 10th, 2046.
RECORDING: I just spent sixteen hours in here.
RECORDING: Trying to install upgrades
to improve efficiency for the central processing unit.
RECORDING: Project Firebreak is going to need the brain power.
RECORDING: Let's just hope I'll have enough of my own.
RECORDING: Anita stayed with me the whole time.
RECORDING: We got a lot done.
RECORDING: But every time she brushed by and I smelled her hair…
RECORDING: Oh boy, I should just go to bed.
Lots of strange equipment.
What was this place?
Locked. Maybe my Focus can help.
Looks like the door was wired to something over here.
RECORDING: This is Director of Security Blevins.
RECORDING: Resending the emergency supply order.
RECORDING: Try reading it this time, okay?
RECORDING: You …weasels don't want me calling my people in SLC.
RECORDING: Director of Security Blevins is riding us like a petty tyrant.
RECORDING: I can't even sneeze without triggering his control issues.
Those nodes on the floor must be connected to the door.
Well that did … something.
What am I supposed to do with these lights?
These things turn, changing the flow of light.
Alright, let's see if the door's open.
RECORDING: Another email from my sister.
RECORDING: I haven't got time to think, let alone reply.
RECORDING: Oh, that photo of the girls she sent
didn't do much for my conscience.
RECORDING: Jenny looks pretty proud of her pilgrim costume.
RECORDING: Crap, I've never missed Thanksgiving before.
RECORDING: And chances for Christmas? Near zero.
RECORDING: I can't even tell them
that all the work I'm doing is to keep them safe.
RECORDING: How am I going to explain to Kenny that Firebreak is doomed,
RECORDING: without a guiding intelligence
advanced enough not only to think, but to feel.
Fresh air ahead.