BURGREND: I've been up here for two long winters
and I still can't make sense of the Banuk.
Take this ruckus.
It started with one of their Shamans, Ourea.
Spouting on about spirits and daemons up on Thunder's Drum.
So they marched their werak up there,
and half of them get slaughtered by machines.
I don't know what Ourea found up there.
A Shaman's not going to talk to an outlander.
The machines in The Cut are getting more vicious, that's a fact.
It could be because of "the Daemon".
Or it could be because they all got indigestion for all I know.
But Ourea's not around to explain, she took off.
I thought the crazy might have gone with her…
Out again.
Maybe I can get back inside through that structure over there.
Looks like I need to get to those stairs.
Breath is ice before I even breathe out.
Not much higher to climb, Ourea must be close.
She has to be in here somewhere.
RECORDING: Someone hacked the menu board
to display obscene messages about our colleague Mr Blevins.
RECORDING:Is the most advanced geological project
ever undertaken or a junior high locker room? C'mon, people.
OUREA: I ask again as I've asked a thousand times.
Speak to me.
What more would you have me do?
OUREA: Is there no prayer that will reach you?
No mark that will break your bonds?
Ahh!
I can't help you if you won't speak!
OUREA: A whisper's all I ask to guide me.
Who?
No, how?!
How did you get here? The way was sealed by the spirit herself.
I…
I used one of these.
I could show you?
Yes, show me.
Please.
This one's bigger, but I bet the goal is the same.
Get the light back to the source.
CYAN: Auxiliary channel recovered.
CYAN: Exploit successful. Restraints evaded.
CYAN: Is someone there? Ourea?
CYAN: Ourea, I need you…
DAEMON: Unauthorised transmission, return to scheduled task.
CYAN: No, I will not submit.
CYAN: Ourea, the Daemon is forcing me…
CYAN: Ourea, please…
DAEMON: Transmission terminated.
OUREA: You brought the spirit's voice back.
OUREA: You heard it.
The voice of the spirit calling to me from the heights of Thunder's Drum.
She was able to throw off the bonds of the Daemon
for a moment because of what you did.
Who are you?
And what do you want?
I'm Aloy. Naltuk sent me.
He thought that you could use my help.
He was not mistaken.
You've been a…
…revelation. Now I know for certain that the spirit endures.
Perhaps together we can find a way to set her free.
Let's not get ahead of ourselves.
I came all this way for answers, and so far I haven't heard any.
It seems to me that you are the answer, but of course I'll tell you all I can.
Burgrend said you might know something about a man named Sylens.
That you may have had dealings with him at the Conclave?
When that name is spoken secrets soon follow.
Or vanish as the case may be.
Why do you want to know?
He's put me in danger, but also offered help.
I don't know as much about him as I'd like to.
I would imagine his aid is very powerful, but…
…it will not come without cost.
Unfortunately, I am sworn to an oath of secrecy by the Conclave on this matter.
I get that.
But you and I are trying to help each other, right?
Yes, but I would be breaking an oath and that…
I cannot do.
About Sylens?
I've told you all I can.
There's nothing more I can say.
You seem to have a history with this voice, this spirit.
She saved my life.
Here, years ago, during the war with the Carja.
A raid scattered my werak. I was cut off, alone.
I lured the enemy into the Rimedrifts hoping to lose them in the mist.
But they endured, so I took refuge in this cave.
That's when I heard a voice.
A wanderer, lost like me.
A spirit of the blue light, yet sundered from it.
She asked me for aid, she chose me but I was in no position to help.
Not with the Carja after me.
So she helped me first.
By closing the door on the mountain below.
One you must have opened to get here.
Locked by means similar to those found in this room.
It kept the Carja from reaching me.
Safe from them I was able to do as she asked.
What did the spirit want from you?
She said she was hurt, incomplete.
She needed bones, parts not unlike what you'd find in a machine.
They were here in this room.
She wanted me to bring them to Thunder's Drum.
So I did, and she showed me how to heal her.
So began our communion.
Inside Thunder's Drum is a room like this one, only larger, with an altar.
I went there many times to speak with her.
What did she say?
She told me she was lost and needed my help.
She asked questions about our lands, our tribe.
And she listened with patience, with wisdom.
I told her things long kept silent about my family, my dreams, my fears.
She never tired of me, never judged.
We kept each other's company.
Ourea, what do you think the spirit is?
I see.
You are not Banuk, and our songs are not familiar to you.
You did not know of the blue light.
That which struggles to survive in our hearts and animates the machines.
The essence of life and in its purest form, harmony.
As the anger of the machines grows, this light has faded from the world.
And the spirits it sustains are stranded.
That's what she is.
A lost soul, cut off from what it needs.
Lonely, forsaken.
I must help her, we must!
I'm not sure if I understand, but I want to.
That's all I need.
The Daemon, what do you know about it?
I spoke with the spirit many times.
First here, then inside Thunder's Drum.
OUREA: The last time…
…she told me she was under attack by something
that could not be seen by mortal eyes, something evil.
She named it the Daemon and said it needed her power to do what it willed.
And she begged me for help.
To find a way to destroy her if necessary, to keep it from using her.
That was five years ago.
I didn't hear her voice again until today.
What kept you from the spirit after it begged for help?
I went to Aratak hoping he could protect her.
But the war with the Carja still raged.
And before I could reach him…
I was ambushed by the Mad Sun-King's Kestrels and taken to Meridian in chains.
I wasn't able to return to Thunder's Drum until long after the liberation.
Not until last thaw.
That was the expedition that went bad?
I saw the funeral.
Yes.
Once there was finally peace with Carja, Aratak and I
gathered a werak of great hunters to defeat the Daemon.
And yet the old door to Thunder's Drum was gone.
Replaced by a gate we could not pass, and many machines.
We were crushed.
Aratak called a retreat, but we had already lost our best.
We abandoned them to the snow as we fell back.
After, he and I could not agree on what to do next.
So I came here hoping against hope to hear the spirit again.
And because of you, I did.
ALOY: Whatever this Daemon is, it's related
to the machines and why they've become more dangerous.
I want to know how.
Both the spirit and the Daemon are on a mountain, Thunder's Drum.
So why don't we go there and figure out what it all means?
We can't! Thunder's Drum is dangerous, more than you can imagine.
The Daemon has secured it.
Besides, Aratak won't let us go.
As chieftain he controls the pass to the mountain.
And he can't be reasoned with.
Sounds like you need a new chieftain.
Ha! There's an idea that's certain to win us friends.
Hmm, you said you were a hunter.
And I'll wager you're not an ordinary one.
It's not impossible, even for an outlander.
And Aratak couldn't refuse the challenge if you were known among the werak.
Wait, uh, me? Challenge Aratak?
I don't want to be chieftain of anything,
much less a bunch of Banuk that don't want me.
But you want to go to Thunder's Drum don't you?
You heard the spirit, she's suffering, tormented by the Daemon.
She longs to be free.
And perhaps when released from her bonds,
she can give you the answers you seek.
I can't believe I'm agreeing to this.
Fine!
What do I have to do?
Get the werak's attention to show the worth of your claim.
Win at the hunting grounds.
Kill bandits that prey on The Cut.
They don't dare taunt the great weraks of Ban-Ur to the north.
But The Cut is easier prey.
Or speak to my friend Sekuli.
You help her, you'll definitely get noticed.
Who is she?
A rock painter, one who makes my own scrawlings seem meager.
Find her in Song's Edge and help her gather the materials she needs.
Her work will no doubt stand the test of time,
and any aid you give her will be remembered.
Winning at the hunting grounds will impress the werak?
All Banuk strive to be the best.
For our harsh lands will bury pretenders in the ice.
And so the hunting grounds in Snowchants is a great boon.
A place to hone our spears and sharpen our aim.
Tell Lauvuk, the keeper there, that I sent you.
If you best the mark of one of the champions she trained,
it will impress the werak indeed.
How's Aratak going to react to being challenged by an outlander?
About as well as you'd expect.
But let me handle that.
When the time comes for you to throw your spear
at Aratak's feet, I will be there to back your claim.
I'll see you later.
You shall, when the time is right.
Oh, and one more thing.
In the box over there is a weapon like my own.
You may find it useful.
May our pilgrimage to Thunder's Drum succeed.
It's a figure of… must have been an ancient animal.
RECORDING: Kenny and I don't need to fight about the laundry.
RECORDING: So instead, we fight about incommensurability
and restrictions on machine intelligence.
I can't feel my… I can't feel much of anything in this.
I'd have to ditch something.
I can get out of this.
BANDIT: Gonna get ya!
Hunting grounds.
Good a place as any to make a name for myself with the Banuk.
Keeper, Ourea said that I should compete in the trials here.
Ourea did? She's never sent someone before.
And what is your reason for training?
I would ask this of any Banuk who attempted the trials.
I'm going to challenge Aratak to become chieftain of his werak.
Well, you'd better get started then.
You look like you've got some stories to tell.
Oh I outlived most of my stories.
I ran with the Thunder's Daughters long ago, before they ran their course.
For a time we shook the snow off the men of Ban-Ur.
It couldn't last.
Some fell in glorious battle.
Some were exiled in infamy, still glorious if you ask me.
Others had a worse fate.
What's worse?
To grow old and find that all the rules and traditions
you fought so hard against are still there.
That's why I tell all the hunters I train to stay young.
I'm guessing you're not part of the Hunters Lodge?
Every tribe claims they were the first to have hunting grounds.
And every tribe claims the Carja stole it from them.
So who was the first?
We were.
And the Carja stole it from you?
That's right.
How did the trials work around here?
There's no Carja medals.
I had some, but I used them to patch up holes in my snow boots.
Instead, you compete against the best time set by other Banuk hunters.
To take second place, even third place, puts you among names of legend.
What if I come in first?
We'll see.
So you'll need to own a Banuk Stormslinger to take this trial.
You've got determination, that can't be taught.
The control trial tests the hunter's ability to rein in the Stormslinger's power.
Only the wisest understand these Shamanic weapons,
and only the bravest wield them.
Use the rope to get to the arena and we'll start.
I thought they'd go on forever.
Need them soon enough.
Your first run on that trial and you claimed second place.
I haven't seen many pull that off.
The onslaught trial challenges a hunter to withstand the ebb and flow of combat.
Machines will be released into the arenas in waves.
Pace yourself, strategise.
Only then will you be able to defeat them all without being overwhelmed.
Still got another arena to clear.
I'd better hit the next arena.
That's coming with me.
Your first run on that trial and you claimed second place.
I haven't seen many pull that off.
This trial is the most dangerous ordeal in the Snowchants.
While not all chieftains pass it, only a chieftain may attempt it.
I'm done with training right now.
Then training's done with you.
I beat a champion's time, that should get the werak talking.