ALOY: I can't believe I'm agreeing to this.
ALOY: Fine!
What do I have to do?
Get the werak's attention to show the worth of your claim.
Win at the hunting grounds.
Kill bandits that prey on The Cut.
They don't dare taunt the great weraks of Ban-Ur to the north.
But The Cut is easier prey.
A rogue Oseram has equipped a gang in the Plumelands with strange new gear.
Just the kind of thing you seem to make sense of.
Must be the cave that Shaman told me about.
Long way down, and not natural either.
Might not be alone down here.
Here's one of the metal birds.
Something's been hacked out of it.
Maybe I can find another of these flying machines.
Full already.
Just have to go up.
If I could move that flying machine over a little…
Could use my Focus, see what it turns up.
Maybe there's some way to get that flying machine over here.
Huh, not so grounded after all.
Now I can get across.
There's the door lock.
I'll need to configure it.
RECORDING: If those punk technicians think I'm gonna sleep on them
waltzing in here and screwing around with the drone routines,
RECORDING: They have seriously underestimated my sense of mission.
RECORDING: Let's just reset that hololock, echo, zero, echo.
RECORDING: I didn't ask for a bunch of flying cameras.
RECORDING: I need security, not surveillance.
RECORDING: And security means firepower.
RECORDING: As God is my witness, I will not be caught squirting blanks
if and when a major act of terrorism desecrates these facilities.
No-one's touched this machine since it got sealed in here.
Shouldn't be hard to remove.
I'll show it to that Shaman when I'm back in Song's Edge.
First strike!
So this thing will improve my spear, huh?
So much for being careful.
It'd be fascinating, if they weren't looking for me.
RECORDING: Ursus americanus.
RECORDING: The magnificent American black bear.
RECORDING: Brought to you by Montana Recreations!
ENJUK: Never even felt the cold, did you?
ENJUK: If he hadn't preserved you, would anyone even know you'd disappeared?
I hate to interrupt…
Oh! I…! Yes, hello, I…
An outlander at the Shrine of Forgotten Beasts.
Welcome. I'm Enjuk.
Uh, Aloy.
The shine of what?
When the Old World still breathed a great man built
a tiny totem to this beast and stored the visage inside.
When the totem is placed on the pedestal…
…the animal is painted onto the empty air and the beast lives again.
Well, almost.
You said a great man made these figurines?
Indeed. He was, I believe, a student of the natural world.
Like me, but surpassing my abilities a thousand times over.
The great Montana Recreations.
Perhaps the finest natural scholar the Old World ever produced.
His voice claims responsibility for the totems, the vessels.
For the knowledge he accumulated.
I share his desire to understand the beasts,
to catalogue their behaviours and preserve their images.
I like to flatter myself that I'm an apprentice of sorts.
We rely as much on beasts as we do on machines, for food, for warmth.
But do we study them with the same fervour? I do!
For example, I have this theory about foxes.
Why do foxes have red fur?
Think about what they eat.
Meat?
Raw meat, bloody meat, see?
Natural causation, logical connections. It only makes sense.
You've thought a lot more about foxes than I have.
Someday, perhaps, if I am persistent, I can earn his name.
Enjuk Recreations.
So these totems, the images they show are of animals that no longer exist.
They're gone, like the Old Ones.
So it seems.
I found this one in the wilds, remembered the indentations
in the pedestals here, and saw how they matched the base of the totem.
The great Montana Recreations must have made more,
but time has scattered them.
RECORDING: Ursus americanus.
RECORDING: The magnificent American black bear.
RECORDING: Brought to you by Montana Recreations!
ALOY: How would you like to find yourself cornered by that thing?
ENJUK: I suspect I'd like it very much indeed!
ENJUK: What a beautiful beast you were.
What do you think of these, Enjuk?
ENJUK: The Cut may have forgotten you, little ones, but I will not.
ENJUK: And now that you've returned to your pedestals, I can show others!
RECORDING: Odocoileus virginianus.
RECORDING: The majestic mule deer.
RECORDING: Brought to you by Montana Recreations!
ENJUK: Not built like a predator, but…
ENJUK: Perhaps it needed those horns
to take down its prey in the absence of sharp fangs?
RECORDING: Ursus arctos.
RECORDING: The menacing grizzly bear.
RECORDING: Brought to you by Montana Recreations!
ALOY: Those claws look like they could rip someone in half.
ENJUK: Perhaps in its youth, but you heard Montana Recreations.
ENJUK: He said it's grizzled, old. It's hunting days are behind it.
RECORDING: Puma Concolor.
RECORDING: The fearsome cougar.
RECORDING: Brought to you by Montana Recreations!
ENJUK: Its coat is sand coloured. Could it have been a burrowing animal?
ENJUK: Perhaps those teeth were only used for digging.
I can't spare the weight.
I forget what warmth feels like out here.
I'm ready, gotta be!
Strange tones in this stuff.
Found me, even though I'm hidden.
You can see them, but they can't see you.
BANDIT: Try to run!
BANDIT: Why? Why? Take this!
Their helmets are as thick as machine plating.
That shot knocked it off.
Bandits aren't subtle.
Clearing them out would send a different kind of message.
They won't be using this again.
No room.
I'd have to leave something else behind.
Don't mind me.
Save these for the trail.
Ah, she went that-a-way!
Finally.
Smells peaceful.
I hate peace.
A lot of people die peacefully.
Not me.
I got a feeling.
Search the camp!
BANDIT LEADER: Call that a search?
BANDIT LEADER: Glad I don't pay you lardskills a retainer.
BANDIT LEADER: Could any of you find a charcoal pile in a flat field?
BANDIT LEADER: I don't think so!
BANDIT: Too close!
BANDIT: She's still here?
BANDIT: Somebody needs a killing!
BANDIT: Wanna play?  Here's your invitation.
ALOY: He's down, and won't be torching anything else.
BANDIT: This'll ruin you.
The Oseram's fire weapon, could come in handy.
BANDIT: Got another shot for you.
BANUK: …the frozen Tallneck in the Frostfigures.
BANUK: We sing the songs of our ancestors.