ARATAK: You saw what she did.
ARATAK: She defeated the machines, not I.
ARATAK: It is proven, she is the better hunter.
ARATAK: We are Banuk. Survive, prevail, what else matters?
ARATAK: My blood is in your teeth.
ARATAK: I take my place behind you on the hunt.
That's got their attention!
Down you go!
Not bad.
Stay down!
These will keep.
Look out below!
I have to kill off these pulses.
Damn wind, never cared for being pushed around.
Here we go again.
Ha!
BANUK: We should not pile his Father's guilt onto
the new Carja king's shoulders. These are different times.
BANUK: Your song echoes, friend.
Aloy, right?
My pop, Burgrend, I mean, told me you might be heading up to see me.
Varga, pleasure.
Hey, that spear is really something! You've customised her haven't you?
I've made a change or two. You've got an eye for weapons.
I wish these Banuk agreed with you.
I can't seem to sell scrap to a Glinthawk around here.
Everyone wants boring old bows and spears.
I like the more unusual stuff and the Banuk can get unusual.
Like that spear Aratak hauls around, an Icerail!
Oooh, or that weapon of Ourea's?
What I wouldn't give to poke around inside one of those.
Feel the lightning on my fingers.
So let's say someone you know happened to have a weapon like Ourea's…
You don't!
See for yourself.
VARGA: Of course, look at the…
…so the coils generate the spark, but the power source isn't even bolted in.
I won't lie, she's beautiful.
But there's beautiful and then there's BEAUTIFUL.
What we need is a Stormbird talon,
lightning flows over them like water off a goose.
I've got an Icerail, just like Aratak's. You wanna take a look?
Are you serious? Yes, yes! I'd love that!
Okay. Mmm.
[snort] Obvious design flaw.
So if I replace these…
…yeah, that should…
Right, so believe it or not,
she's operating at — let's be generous — half her potential.
What's with the "she's"?
Oh, Pop says all weapons are girls.
I don't think he realises it's a compliment.
Well, listen, if we had a Thunderjaw's mandibles
to work with her gears would be well and truly greased.
Last commission I had was a month ago.
A weapon that spat fire.
That didn't go well.
I took this thing off an Oseram bandit.
You got my Forgefire back?
Well, if you took down Ohlgrund and his goons for this thing,
I guess she's yours now.
Why don't you finish it for me first?
Make it, make her, into the weapon she was supposed to be.
I'm going to need a Bellowback snout.
Any Bellowback's will do.
Can you handle it alone?
I think I can manage that.
So we need parts from a Stormbird and a Thunderjaw?
And you know where to find them?
That's right. It's gonna take some travelling, though.
A Stormbird roosts near the Free Heap. I'll pack and meet you out there.
This'll be fun!
Okay.
Hunt it with me, I'll turn that weapon into your new best friend.
Mmm, second best.
BANUK: So machines in the south suffer their own sort of corruption.
BANUK: I wonder what sort of challenge they present.
I'm glad to see you Gildun!
Means I don't have to go pry you out of a flooded dam.
Ha, yes!
I'm glad as well.
Heard the fires were heating up for you.
Back up into the mountain, huh?
That's the plan.
I'm … I'm not sure what I can do to…
If I could do anything to…
Heh, you don't want old Gildun tagging along,
getting you trapped some damn place.
But you saved my life, you showed me kindness, so…
So you're here.
So I'm here.
Thanks Gildun.
Be safe Aloy.
And when it's done, you come tell me a story for once.
SIGNUTAI: Longnotch is well stocked, as you asked.
RUATUK: And our scouts are watching for more Frostclaws.
SIGNUTAI: Our numbers rise, three more hunters have passed their trials.
SIGNUTAI: But our purpose was to take back the mountain, now what?
ARATAK: Stay prepared, sharpen your spears.
ARATAK: Should we not return defending The Cut falls to you.
ARATAK: If our chieftain agrees with this course.
ALOY: Sounds like good advice, but let's hope it doesn't come to that.
SIGNUTAI: Chieftain.
ARATAK: The weight of command is no small burden.
ALOY: I can see that.
I take it you haven't spoken to Ourea yet?
Why should I?
This is what she wanted, to return to Thunder's Drum.
It is her only care.
ARATAK: So I should have known she would find a way to push aside my spear.
After the Carja took my sister, not all of her came back.
What happened to Ourea when she was a captive of the Carja?
ARATAK: As a Shaman, she's adept with machines, tracking them, stunning them.
ARATAK: The Carja used her to capture them for the Sun Ring
where they were unleashed upon the innocent.
ARATAK: They made her a part of their blood sport.
ARATAK: The shame she suffered beneath their pitiless sun…
ALOY: She survived.
ARATAK: She endured.
ARATAK: Endured by reminding herself of the spirit, her purpose.
ARATAK: And now that's all she has.
Tell me what happened to the first expedition.
Ourea led the way to the summit, but it was blocked by a great door.
Some kind of Cauldron, new metal.
ARATAK: We tried to break through, but it was unflinching.
ARATAK: We were exhausted, no way forward and machines behind.
ARATAK: I made the call to push back. It cost us greatly.
ARATAK: But to remain would have cost us everything.
ARATAK: I'd hoped to never subject Ourea to that again.
ALOY: What do you think is beyond that door?
ARATAK: I do not know.
ARATAK: That expanse of metal, that dead hum, nothing sacred belongs there.
ARATAK: Machines and death, that's what the mountain holds.
Death for us or for the Daemon.
ALOY: And if we do find the spirit?
ARATAK: Then perhaps we should put it out of its misery.
ALOY: For what it's worth, I'm glad you're coming with me.
ARATAK: Someone has to keep Ourea safe.
BANUK: A great werak is put together like a machine. Each part…
NALTUK: I wish you luck on the mountain.
Aloy, this is it.
My chance to reunite with the spirit,
and perhaps to reunite her with the blue light.
It's not a chance I would have had alone.
I needed an outsider, someone ignorant of our ways, but…
…no, not ignorant, I…
Are you trying to thank me Ourea?
Yes, of course.
That's what you do.
Untangle knots, create possibilities.
Thank you for making this pilgrimage possible.
What are we gonna find up there Ourea?
Ruins, machines, and a door like that of a Cauldron.
I have faith that you can find a way through it, Aloy.
For beyond it lies the spirit.
I know I could find her there.
Though I do not doubt the Daemon has tried to hide the way.
I only wish it had not been necessary to humiliate Aratak.
You were wise to let him come.
He's earned the right, stubborn as stone, but he's had to be.
The war demanded it.
And so have I.
What did the war do to Aratak?
It cut away everything until only his true self remained, unyielding ice.
No Banuk has more sheer will.
He fought the Carja for a thousand freezing nights,
yet always rallied his hunters at sunrise.
It is said he endured twenty-three wounds in those years.
His hunters counted them, he never complains of one.
Instead, he complains that life with me is harder.
He's right. What have I ever given him but struggle?
Aratak told me you were a captive with the Carja for a long time, it sounded bad.
For Aratak it all comes back to that.
He thinks the Carja changed me.
They did not.
They merely sharpened my focus.
When all else is lost, you think about what's truly important.
The spirit, the blue light, the beyond.
Now that I'm chieftain of the werak,
I don't suppose I can order you to tell me about Sylens?
Aratak would never have presumed to grasp for a secret of the Conclave.
But you are not Aratak,
and if you have dealt with Sylens, your need is well apparent.
Sylens came to Ban-Ur from the distant north,
a young Shaman of the Owl's Watch.
A remote werak that rarely comes south to parlay.
Sylens was a Shaman?
He was, or at least when we sent runners
to ask the Owl's Watch, they said he was.
His knowledge of the machines was beyond compare,
and he was hungry to trade what he knew to the rest of us.
Didn't take him long to gain the trust of the Conclave,
and eventually an invitation to attend.
What about you? Did you trust him?
No, but he impressed me.
He carried himself with poise and authority.
I wanted to learn from him.
But that was not to be.
He was granted knowledge of our most sacred meeting place.
The frozen caves of the Malmstrom, a month's march from Ban-Ur.
He met with us there, as is custom, at high winter.
But when we next returned, the caves had been looted.
Relics of the Old World stolen.
Holes cut in ice and metal.
Yeah, that would be Sylens alright.
He vanished with the spoils.
We sent our best trackers after him, none returned.
And when we checked back with the Owl's Watch,
those who had vouched for him were gone.
As though he never existed.
Some in the Conclave began to doubt he was even Banuk to begin with.
And what do you think?
He committed an unforgivable sacrilege.
He's unscrupulous and dangerous.
But also brilliant, skilled, and knowledgeable, without equal.
Except perhaps for you.
Anyone else I would warn off, but you may be able to treat with him safely.
It hasn't been easy for you, Ourea, getting back to this point.
It was all to hear her voice again.
This time, we both will.
I'd like that.
Finally we ascend.
How? I don't see a way up.
Not up, through.
Now brother!
[Naltuk chanting]
COMPUTER: This is not a drill.
Please remain calm and proceed to the nearest exit.
OUREA: Come, the spirit awaits.
ARATAK: That's not all that waits.
COMPUTER: Smoke has been detected within the facility.
This is not a drill. Please remain calm and proceed to the nearest exit.
So you see, I too can call upon the power of the Old Ones.
ALOY: What was this place?
OUREA: The spirit once told me that this all used to be part of its domain.
OUREA: A fortress that defended humankind from a terrible danger.
ALOY: Fortress? It looks more like a machine.
OUREA: Is that not fitting? The blue light often dwells in machines.
ARATAK: Let's just hope that some remains here.
ARATAK: I'm restless, the echoes mock me.
RECORDING: November 21st, 2064.
RECORDING: It's been three years since I was last here,
and twelve since I was running the place.
RECORDING: Just a skeleton crew left, confused about why I'm here.
RECORDING: So am I.
RECORDING: Anita wants me to find a way to suspend operations for a while.
RECORDING: Maybe a long while, and I don't know why.
RECORDING: But from the sound of her voice it was something terrifying.
RECORDING: I wish I could look into her eyes,
ask her what the hell she's so freaked out about?
RECORDING: But what else is new.
When don't I wish I could look into her eyes again?
OUREA: Aloy, were you listening for something?
ALOY: There are memories here. Messages left by the Old Ones.
OUREA: And you can hear them? I envy you.
OUREA: What did they say?
ALOY: I'm not sure yet, Ourea.
ARATAK: Here, up and over.
Machines. At least we have the drop on them.
Ready or not!
Not this time, little one.
OUREA: I made it!
OUREA: We must climb higher, then our path will become clear.
ALOY: That should do it, Varga can finish her Forgefire now.
OUREA: We can make our way upwards when you're done, Aloy.
ARATAK: If the Chieftain's pace is measured, ours is measured.
OUREA: Yes, this way.
ALOY: Forget about travelling light.
OUREA: There's an overlook above, it's not far.
OUREA: Not much farther now.
ARATAK: Last we were here, we fought our way through there.
ARATAK: But machines overcame us.
ARATAK: We retreated, dropping supplies, and taking losses.
ARATAK: Now we must prevail, with only two warriors and a Shaman to protect.
OUREA: Aloy is no ordinary warrior, and I can hold my own.
OUREA: Even so, we could go that way instead.
OUREA: There are machines up there, but also cover.
OUREA: We could stay hidden, at least for a while.
ALOY: Alright, I get the options.
ALOY: Now follow my lead.
ALOY: Pipes, towers, steam, frost.
ALOY: What was all this for?
OUREA: I went this way years ago,
looking for cover in case machines came prowling.
OUREA: I have no doubt that it is guarded now, but we may be able to stay hidden.
ARATAK: Press on.
ARATAK: Not all threats can be seen at first. Beware of Stalkers.
OUREA: Stay down as we move through.
ALOY: It's cold, as if there's Chillwater
running through those massive pipes. But why?
ARATAK: We go where you go, Aloy.
ARATAK: Let's move, quiet as we can.
ALOY: Calm, calm.
OUREA: Let's not linger any longer than we have to.
ALOY: Should have brought a cart.
ARATAK: Thought I'd endured every cold there is, but this frost…
OUREA: Aloy, there's an entrance to the tower ahead.
ALOY: Won't waste this.
ARATAK: On to the tower, before we freeze to our spears.
ARATAK: Be wary of mines, if Stalkers are near.
ALOY: It's freezing, the ground, the air, me.
OUREA: Always cold as deepest winter here.
OUREA: There's a door up ahead, and refuge. We're almost through.
ARATAK: No need for sneaking.
RECORDING: Technically, I can't suspend the cooling system.
RECORDING: But I can reduce the power draw,
so that it'll be completely masked by the caldera.
RECORDING: But masked from what?
RECORDING: Firebreak has always been confidential for security reasons.
RECORDING: But this would be excessive, even for the dear departed Mr Blevins.
RECORDING: What could possibly have gotten Anita so worked up?
ALOY: Is this a projector?
ALOY: Maybe to show holograms without a Focus.
ALOY: Let's see if I can restore power.
ALOY: Aratak, Ourea, you might see shapes drawn from light. Don't be alarmed.
ARATAK: It'll take more than light to alarm me.
ANITA SANDOVAL: Thank you for being here, everyone.
ANITA SANDOVAL: I suppose it's not every day you get
to have cocktails inside an active volcano, right?
ANITA SANDOVAL: Unless you're George,
and I can hardly blame him for drinking on the job.
ANITA SANDOVAL: None of this would be here
without our beloved director Kenny Chau.
RECORDING: [clapping]
ANITA SANDOVAL: So here's to you, Kenny.
ANITA SANDOVAL: You put a cork in the Yellowstone caldera.
ANITA SANDOVAL: I'd say you deserve a margarita!
RECORDING: [laughter]
KENNY CHAU: Hold your glasses everyone, I'd like to add something.
KENNY CHAU: This effort wouldn't have been possible
without our lead programmer.
KENNY CHAU: Thank you, Anita.
KENNY CHAU: For bringing us a real mastermind, CYAN.
CYAN: I'll second that Director Chau.
ANITA SANDOVAL: Alright, CYAN, what's our latest number?
CYAN: The current count is 1,654.
ANITA SANDOVAL: Ha ha! Wow! Then drink up, everyone!
ANITA SANDOVAL: Here's to 1,654 more years without an eruption!
OUREA: It was the spirit with the Old Ones.
OUREA: I could only grasp some of what they said.
ALOY: You were right, Ourea.
ALOY: This place was built to stop something terrible, and it worked.
ALOY: As for the spirit, I'm starting to get an idea of what it could be.
OUREA: The door is open now, we can get through.
ARATAK: I have a score to settle with that mountain.
OUREA: There, below. Door to the mountain. New metal.
ARATAK: Dead metal, we could not pass it before.
OUREA: We will this time, we have to.
ALOY: We'll have to carve through a lot of machines to get to that door.
ARATAK: More than the werak could prevail against before.
OUREA: Aloy will see us through.
ARATAK: Onward then, our challenge awaits.
RECORDING: The geothermal plant can be suspended.
RECORDING: The cooling system masked.
RECORDING: Massive challenges solved.
RECORDING: So why am I so nervous about the next part?
RECORDING: All I need to do is
install Anita's mysterious software, and have a conversation.
RECORDING: It's not even a human being, right?
ALOY: This'll help.
ALOY: Never know when I might need these.
DAEMON: Security threat detected, mobilising autonomous defenses.
ALOY: Here we go.
ARATAK: More machines, make ready!
ALOY: I think…
ALOY: I think we did it.
OUREA: Now Aloy, the door. Can you open it?
ALOY: Let's find out.
ARATAK: Show us, Chieftain, what lies beyond.
ARATAK: I don't put much stock in songs of deeds.
ARATAK: But that battle was a verse worth singing.
OUREA: Please, Aloy, open the door.