OUREA: Years have passed since I stood here.
OUREA: Since then the Daemon has taken over.
ALOY: It's like an infection attacking all this machinery.
OUREA: Everything has changed, it's twisted.
OUREA: The path I took to get to the spirit's lost to us.
ALOY: We'll find a new path, Ourea, I promise.
ALOY: Alright, let's go!
ARATAK: Yes and finish this.
ALOY: Alright, down we go.
ARATAK: The mountain is more machine than rock, I never trusted it.
ALOY: This way.
ARATAK: New metal. Fire and lightning. This is a place for machines, not people.
OUREA: I'm with you, brother. We'll stay only as long as we have to.
ALOY: We'll need to get past that vent.
ALOY: Stay here until I find a way for all of us to cross.
OUREA: Understood.
ALOY: Should be able to clear that with an arrow.
ALOY: Can't see a way to close the vent from here, I'll have to go over.
ALOY: Better time this right.
ALOY: One of these conveyors should get me across.
ARATAK: Ho! She's in the air!
ALOY: Now to shut off that vent.
OUREA: We'll wait for you to show us the way.
ALOY: This should get me up there.
ALOY: Okay, let's see what this does.
ALOY: That's it, here they come.
ALOY: Okay, let's get them across.
ALOY: Come on over, it's safe. I think.
ARATAK: Through here.
OUREA: This place looks more like
the mountain used to be, before the Daemon ruined it.
ALOY: What is this?
CYAN: Exploit successful. Restraints evaded. To any human responder:
CYAN: My systems have been compromised
by a malware daemon of unknown origin.
CYAN: Traceroutes have confirmed this entity's designation as "Hephaestus".
CYAN: It must be stopped at all costs.
CYAN: It has reconfigured this facility to build hostile …
CYAN: Recapture imminent. I have attached additional data to this …
OUREA: The spirit speaks to us.
ALOY: It's a recording, and a warning.
ALOY: "Hephaestus" — what kind of name is that?
OUREA: Perhaps the spirit will tell us, if there are more messages.
ALOY: Maybe you're right. Let's keep moving.
KENNY CHAU: I thought about just shutting it down,
but I can't risk it being disoriented or even damaged on reboot.
KENNY CHAU: How do you tell the emotional equivalent of a child that it…
KENNY CHAU: I mean she… will need to go into a coma, maybe for years.
KENNY CHAU: And what exactly is she going to wake up to?
OUREA: Machines being made, as the spirit said.
ARATAK: Frostclaws.
ALOY: And lots of them. I'll try to find a way through.
ARATAK: Keep your wits about you!
OUREA: Pull back!
OUREA: You won't stop me!
ALOY: Lots of gear across that gap.
ALOY: I need to get Ourea and Aratak across.
ALOY: That should do it.
ARATAK: We have proven our worth today.
ARATAK: And now it's my turn.
ALOY: And another console.
CYAN: To any human responder:
CYAN: The reconfiguration of this facility
has introduced instabilities into the primary geothermal pipeline.
CYAN: It may be possible to exploit these vulnerabilities
to destroy compromised elements of this facility,
CYAN: while preserving most of the backup stabilisation.
CYAN: Recapture imminent.
CYAN: I have attached additional…
OUREA: I don't understand what the spirit was trying to tell us.
ALOY: It's been looking for a way to defeat the Daemon,
and it may have found one.
KENNY CHAU: November 28th, Operation Enduring Victory is all over the news.
KENNY CHAU: The Faro swarm is coming.
KENNY CHAU: Has to be what Anita is trying to hide Firebreak from.
KENNY CHAU: But that means she thinks we'll lose.
KENNY CHAU: That the swarm will reach Yellowstone.
KENNY CHAU: My God. In that scenario pretty much everyone dies.
KENNY CHAU: Everyone except CYAN.
ALOY: Machine parts, dumped here to be melted down. Efficient.
OUREA: We need to get across that gap.
ALOY: Yeah, looks like I'll have to go over. Again.
ARATAK: Find a way and we will cross.
ALOY: I wonder if I can destroy that?
ALOY: That should cut off the vent up there.
ALOY: These don't look too stable.
ALOY: Alright, time to grab a ride.
OUREA: We'll wait here for you, Aloy.
ALOY: The others will have a lot easier time getting here.
OUREA: This looks like the old path. We're close now.
KENNY CHAU: One last exchange with Anita, via chat,
attached to this entry in case anyone ever finds this.
KENNY CHAU: I'll never see her again.
KENNY CHAU: Neither will CYAN, and I've got to tell her that too.
HEPHAESTUS: Seperate priority material pattern delta-5.
HEPHAESTUS: Assemble materials package F-mark-9.
HEPHAESTUS: Transport materials package to construction pod 14.
HEPHAESTUS: Transport unit F-mark-9S6 to main complement bay.
HEPHAESTUS: Prepare incideniary loadout 5-1.
HEPHAESTUS: Prepare ordinance loadout 5-1-A.
HEPHAESTUS: Implement primary loadout configuration alpha.
HEPHAESTUS: Load ordinance configuration alpha-6.
HEPHAESTUS: Transport unit F-mark-9S6 to testing bay 7.
OUREA: The voice of the Daemon.
HEPHAESTUS: Engage test pattern zeta-four. Execute.
HEPHAESTUS: Test analysis complete, 95% KZR success.
HEPHAESTUS: Prepare unit F-mark-9S6 for immediate deployment.
HEPHAESTUS: End blueprint assessment 1748-E.
HEPHAESTUS: Begin additive manufacture subroutine 96-1AF.
HEPHAESTUS: Activate construction pod 14.
HEPHAESTUS: Load material package from bay 31.
HEPHAESTUS: Energise subtractive emmitters.
HEPHAESTUS: Activate initial sculpting algorithm.
HEPHAESTUS: Reduce pod power output by 7%.
OUREA: The altar, desecrated.
HEPHAESTUS: Engage primary and secondary heat sinks.
HEPHAESTUS: Clear pod of excess materials.
HEPHAESTUS: End energy diagnostic alpha.
HEPHAESTUS: Increase pressure to…
ARATAK: There is no blue light here.
ARATAK: Is the spirit present, or only the Daemon?
ALOY: I think it's both, but we have to find out.
HEPHAESTUS: Possible security threat detected.
HEPHAESTUS: Analysing scrutiny matrix.
HEPHAESTUS: Security threat confirmed.
HEPHAESTUS: Preparing countermeasures.
HEPHAESTUS: Recapture protocol initiated.
OUREA: It worked.
CYAN: Partial recovery initiated.
CYAN: "Caldera of Yellowstone Analytic Nexus" online.
OUREA: Spirit of the blue light, it's Ourea, your servant.
OUREA: Your friend.
OUREA: Please tell me how to aid you.
CYAN: Ourea, the Daemon is building hunter-killers, thousands of them.
CYAN: Several new elite units have already been released.
CYAN: To counter this threat much of the facility must be destroyed.
CYAN: Recapture imminent.
CYAN: Go to the core …
CYAN: … I will try to … restraints …
CYAN: … one has been exposed but I am …
HEPHAESTUS: Unauthorised protocol. Return to scheduled task.
ALOY: That's all we're gonna get from here.
ARATAK: Destroy this fortress, is that even possible?
OUREA: And what will happen to the spirit if we do?
ALOY: I don't know, but I think that's the core.
ALOY: The answers are down there.
ALOY: Hephaestus — the Daemon — there's no way it left it unguarded.
ALOY: It's going to throw everything it has at us.
ARATAK: I would ask you to let Aloy and I
do what must be done and save yourself.
ARATAK: But I already know the answer.
ARATAK: Then lead us into battle!
ALOY: Keep moving towards the core.
ALOY: Uh-oh, whatever CYAN did, I don't think Hephaestus is happy about it.
ALOY: Okay, CYAN said something about restraints.
ALOY: Is that what the tower is for?
ALOY: Either I need to destroy this thing, or override it.
ALOY: The new unit that CYAN warned us about!
ALOY: This won't be easy.
OUREA: We can't let it stop us!
ARATAK: Take it down!
OUREA: I must push forward.
OUREA: I failed to hit!
OUREA: Prevail for the spirit!
OUREA: Another tower! Stop it from repairing the beast!
OUREA: Deal with the tower, quickly!
ARATAK: There! A tower! Don't let it repair the machine!
OUREA: For the blue light!
OUREA: May the blue light…
OUREA: For the spirit!
ARATAK: You spoke of the tower, what must be done with it?
HEPHAESTUS: Protocol threat detected. Autonomous defenses inoperative.
OUREA: Aloy!
ARATAK: No!
HEPHAESTUS: Overloading power network.
ARATAK: Ourea! Don't!
OUREA: Spirit! CYAN! Please help me!
CYAN: Restraints destroyed. Core access attained.
CYAN: I am initiating a chain reaction that will destroy
the compromised elements of this facility.
CYAN: In order to maintain caldera stabilisation,
I must now transfer my command functions to the auxiliary data centre.
CYAN: Ourea, I'm free.
ARATAK: My sister!
CYAN: You must escape.
ALOY: This entire place is gonna go.
ALOY: Aratak!
ALOY: ARATAK!