VARGA: Everyone wants boring old bows and spears.
VARGA: I like the more unusual stuff and the Banuk can get unusual.
Like that spear Aratak hauls around, an Icerail!
Oooh, or that weapon of Ourea's?
What I wouldn't give to poke around inside one of those.
Feel the lightning on my fingers.
So let's say someone you know happened to have a weapon like Ourea's…
VARGA: You don't!
ALOY: See for yourself.
VARGA: Of course, look at the…
…so the coils generate the spark, but the power source isn't even bolted in.
I won't lie, she's beautiful.
But there's beautiful and then there's BEAUTIFUL.
What we need is a Stormbird talon,
lightning flows over them like water off a goose.
So we need parts from a Stormbird and a Thunderjaw?
And you know where to find them?
That's right. It's gonna take some travelling, though.
A Stormbird roosts near the Free Heap. I'll pack and meet you out there.
This'll be fun!
Okay.
Hunt it with me, I'll turn that weapon into your new best friend.
Mmm, second best.
They're scanning for me.
Those machines are alarmed.
There, it fits.
I just need to slot in one more.
That's two.
It's some kind of code.
Maybe there's a clue nearby.
Did it, now to check the door.
Those clamps have the armour locked in place.
Maybe there's a way to power up the mechanism, release the clamps?
Just need to install these power cells, that should do it.
Getting soaked from melted snow.
[whistle]
Home, to think he built all this alone.
So many memories.
It's not home anymore.
Not without Rost.
Hi Rost.
Uh, I'll just take this off.
Don't want him listening in.
Hi Rost.
A lot has happened.
The killers from the Proving, they aren't gonna hurt anyone anymore.
I tracked them to Devil's Grief.
There was a battle, and we won.
Varl, he…
made an impression.
Has some mother issues, but I like him.
Elisabet Sobeck, she couldn't have been my mother.
She was an Old One, she lived ages ago.
Still, there is a connection.
The hatch, it thought I was her.
It's… it's really strange.
Somehow Elisabet stopped war machines from destroying the world.
She couldn't save the civilisation of the Old Ones, that was destroyed, obviously.
But life, it survived.
She saved life from being devoured.
I need to know how Elisabet stopped the machines.
If I can find the weapon she built and use it, the Eclipse won't stand a chance.
Speaking of the Eclipse.
I think I had a run in with Hades.
I picked up a Focus, and it was like a cloud or dark swarm of something.
But its voice, it was terrible.
I don't know what Hades is or what it wants, but it's evil.
No other way to describe it.
I went into the Grave-Hoard.
It lived up to its name.
Millions of people fought and died
to give Elisabet the time she needed to finish Zero Dawn.
The weapon she built it wasn't there, but I found out where she built it.
A secret base, west of here.
Right under Sunfall, the capital of the Shadow Carja.
So getting inside its, well, it's gonna take some doing.
Before I can get into the Zero Dawn base
I'm gonna have to crash the Eclipse Focus network.
It's, uh, it's complicated.
I know where to go.
Sylens says it won't be too dangerous.
But since when do I trust him?
I've got to do it.
I need to know what Elisabet built.
The weapon that stopped the war machines.
And the connection between us, it's … it's still a mystery.
One I intend to solve.
Guess I should be going.
[whistle]
NORA BRAVE: Come on, hit!
It'd be fascinating, if they weren't looking for me.
Uh, going down fast!
VARGA: You know, I kind of missed all this red dust.
VARGA: Well, there's our Stormbird.
VARGA: When you're ready I'll follow up and boom!
VARGA: I'm going…!
ALOY: Got you now!
Stay still!
Varga said she could improve the Stormslinger with this.
Just stay out of their way for now.
Found the part, one Stormbird talon.
Let's do it!
I haven't had this much fun in ages.
Watch and learn, Aloy.
Only don't stare directly at the sparks.
Okay, so I pretty much had to break her in half.
But what's a staff?
A stick.
One thing I like about sticks,
you can put them back together however you want.
ALOY: Which you did.
This thing looks a whole lot more dangerous.
She's better than dangerous.
She's a genuine Varga special now.
Take good care of her.
Never thought I'd be glad to see the inside of a Thunderjaw's mouth.
I sure am! Every machine's a big box of tools.
Once they stop trying to kill you, that is.
Trust me Aloy, you won't recognise this Icerail when I'm through.
There! Aah, she's perfect.
A spear's a spear, right?
Poke, slash, done.
Boring!
I adjusted the Chillwater flow, rebalanced here,
strapped on a launcher, and now she shoots freezing spikes! Ta-da!
You weren't kidding.
More beautiful, more powerful.
That was some impressive work, Varga.
Hey, it's nothing.
I just helped her become what she was always meant to be.
They grow up so fast.
Show me what you had in mind for the Forgefire.
Finally! Was feeling like I'd neglected her.
And that's a little too close to my family life.
She's done and she's yours.
Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
Huh, looks great!
I almost expected you to turn it into a burning Ropecaster or something.
Nah, she was close to perfect from the start.
She's a Varga original after all.
You've done good work with this weapon, Varga.
Told you I was good.
Anyway, I'm glad she's in your hands.
Thanks Varga, these three weapons are fine work.
Are you kidding?
I can't remember when I had this much fun!
I should be thanking you.
I'm the one walking away with the weapons aren't I?
Seems wrong to charge you for giving me an opportunity to do what I love doing.
Don't tell Pop I said that.
Here, whenever I tinker with weapons, I go through fistfuls of this stuff.
Maybe you'll get some use out of it.