ALOY: I see the module.
SYLENS: Good. Now be quick.
ALOY: This … this is Hades?
SYLENS: Aloy, this is not the time.
ALOY: It's a Metal Devil.
SYLENS: Open the module's casing, now.
SYLENS: ALOY! Do as I say, or all is lost!
HADES: Entity has come here?
HADES: Entity miscalculated.
HADES: Entity cannot destroy me, I am beyond its reach.
ALOY: Maybe you are, but this isn't!
HADES: Destroy the entity!
SYLENS: Rough going, but you survived.
You knew Hades was there and you send me to him!
I won't deny I risked your life.
But it was the only way.
Now, with the Focus network down we can both get what we want.
Access to the secrets of Zero Dawn.
I'm past trusting you with secrets.
Good, that means you're wising up.
Trust is for fools.
It shifts and crumbles like sand, a poor foundation for any partnership.
But mutual self-interest?
Now that is a solid bedrock upon which you and I
might build a new science of understanding.
We both need answers Aloy.
And thanks to you we're on the verge of grasping them.
At Sunfall we'll speak again.
You miserable…! Damn him!
If I could toss this Focus and be rid of you Sylens, I would.
But we both know I need it.
Sunfall it is, and Zero Dawn.
Keep quiet now.
Can stop tensing up.
Come on then!
BANDIT: Here we are!
Right on target.
That's it, nothing to see here.
Not this time, little one.
My Focus is receiving another signal.
There it is, another Tallneck.
Calm, calm.
Okay, I need to get up to the Tallneck's head.
Got their attention!
This storm's gonna back down before I do.
They're scanning for me.
SHADOW CARJA: Not making this easy…
SHADOW CARJA: They've scurried away, watch me.
ALOY: This might even the odds.
SHADOW CARJA: None will stand against us!
ALOY: Another hit in.
Passed the test.
So much for being careful!
I should be able to jump onto the Tallneck from here.
Made it! Now to climb up to its head.
Alright, got what I need.
Scrabbling a bit.
Sorry to spoil your fun!
Huh, nice.
Dust storm blowing in, moves like water.
SYLENS, THROUGH FOCUS: Sunfall. The mad King Jiran's summer palace.
SYLENS: A bulwark of Carja might against the howling Forbidden West.
ALOY: Thanks for the history lesson.
SYLENS: But they have no idea what lies beneath.
SYLENS: We will learn much from this, Aloy.
ALOY: That's what I'm hoping.
SHADOW CARJA: The old warriors have stories about
how calm the machines used to be, must've been nice.
SHADOW CARJA: The ceasefire is baffling. How can we just decide not to strike back against the usurpers?
SHADOW CARJA: I know we're here for a reason, but I just miss feeling useful.
SHADOW CARJA: He's always been a righteous man.
I never would've thought Uthid capable of abandoning us like this.
MERCHANT: Buy what you need, leave the rest.
MERCHANT: Don't pass up these goods.
MERCHANT: Would you like to buy something today?
MERCHANT: You won't find better wares!
MERCHANT: I got all the best goods here.
MERCHANT: Take a look at these wares.
SYLENS: The Sun Ring. A proud tradition of the Carja.
ALOY: It's not like this in Meridian. At least, not any more.
SYLENS: Give them time, I'm sure they'll miss it.
SYLENS: Now we get to see if your attack
on their Focus network was entirely successful.
ALOY: What are you talking about? Did I crash the network or not?
SYLENS: In theory, all should be well.
ALOY: Hmph.
SYLENS: Success! Welcome to the Citadel, Aloy.
SYLENS: I'll check back with you in a moment.
SYLENS: In the meantime, circulate.
CRIER: Outlanders! If you want to hear about today's bounties,
head for the throne room.
CRIER: You're not going to make any shards by standing out here.
CRIER: Filthy mercenary bottom feeders.
ELKEND: I'll take the shards, even if it means having to listen to Bahavas.
MERCENARY: I hear the Shadow Carja are looking for one of their own.
Should pay well.
SHADOW CARJA: …cease fire, let's be generous, a month.
BAHAVAS: By the glory of the Sun revealed!
Behold, Radiant Itamen! The one true Sun-King.
The light in shadow, whose will is light and whose light is law!
I command Lucent Bahavas to speak on my behalf.
By the will of Radiant Itamen does the Sun
glare down mercilessly upon the traitor Uthid.
BAHAVAS: To the hunter who brings his head to us,
shall go a bounty of 500 shards.
VANASHA: More prisoners than royalty, don't you think?
BAHAVAS: The crimes of the traitor Uthid are many and so…
VANASHA: Hmm, love your hair.
BAHAVAS: …provoke the ire of the Sun in full blaze!
Not only did the wretch conspire to…
VANASHA: You and I need to chat, little huntress.
BAHAVAS: …infiltrate the Citadel and assassinate…
VANASHA: The green tent down in Shadowside, I'll be waiting.
BAHAVAS: …the one true king, but he refused to surrender when…
ALOY: Uh, kinda busy.
BAHAVAS: …discovered and fled…
BAHAVAS: …and in doing so demonstrated wanton disregard for…
VANASHA: We both know you're no killer for hire.
BAHAVAS:  …the safety of the king's subjects.
VANASHA: Uthid is innocent.
VANASHA: So come see me while there's still time to save him.
BAHAVAS: Go forth then, outlanders, and do the will of the Sun!
SYLENS: So, the way in I spoke of his right behind you.
ALOY: You've gotta be kidding.
SYLENS: Not at all.
ODUND: Got to see the Sun Ring from on high!
ELKEND: But the Kestrels…?
ODUND: They want us to see this, boy. It makes quite an impression.
SHADOW CARJA: Another savage? At least it's not as bad as Meridian.
Nora, you have the mark of a Seeker.
It's more complicated than that.
I'm an outcast, like you.
Yes. I'm Yun, these are The Shunned.
We'll take any job, but hunting our hated tribe? That's for free.
Keep that in mind.
Why did they cast you out?
Murder, you?
Mmm, birth.
Huh.
SHADOW CARJA: Outlanders are idiots. But perhaps they're useful idiots.
You're not known to Kikuk's Killers.
Have any songs been written about you?
Uuh, maybe. How about you?
Only laments. We're the enders of songs.
Machine speared or man's spark.
We stop them all.
Ah, charming.
Warmth is for weakness.
SHADOW CARJA: Word is that the outlanders
are only here to weed out traitors, so at least I'm safe.
SHADOW CARJA: I tell you for a little more food,
I'd do whatever work these outlanders are doing and more.
SHADOW CARJA: Strange, I used to walk by
the same old man every morning, but I haven't seen him today.
ODUND: If you're gonna watch some slaughter, this is the place to do it!
ELKEND: I don't like heights.
ODUND: You worry me, boy, you worry me.
ELKEND: If you've got a problem with me talk to Odund, if you can stand his breath.
Another man hunt. How many men and women can one tribe lose?
Odund, leader of Odund's Marvels.
You've a fresh face.
When you're less and eye or an ear or two you'll fit right in.
First impressions make the sale, except in this snakepit.
They'll take whoever shows up.
This isn't your first job for the Shadow Carja?
Scared of their own shadows Carja more like.
They spit on me, but the shards are good.
Look at those nobles.
I say noble, but you can't dress a rat in silk and call it a Rat King, can you?
Sunfall is a house of clay, if you were to stamp your foot it would all crumble.
Shouldn't you all be setting out to hunt Uthid?
Have you never done this before?
Whoever goes first just leads the others.
Just take a load off and avail yourself
of some Carja booze until someone sniffs out the trail.
Then watch us seek out our prey, straight as a Ravager's shot. Zip!
Are you sure you're gonna be able to walk in a straight line?
W–w–what are you getting at?
Do you think Uthid did what they're accusing him of?
I hope so, it'll make him more dangerous.
My advice? It's best not to overthink such things.
Uh, overthink whether he's guilty or innocent?
Haha, you let all these thoughts in your head, you'll never make it as a mercenary.
Only thing that matters is dead or alive.
If they say alive, bring a rag to stuff in its mouth.
But these days, no one wants alive.
Farewell Odund.
Good hunting!
If I should have cause to kill you, you won't suffer.
Oh, thanks.
SHADOW CARJA: Sun in shadow, if you can't trust Uthid, who can you trust?
SHADOW CARJA: Is the cease fire gonna put
more food on our table? I very much doubt it.
SHADOW CARJA: Nice to have a break. Work's been hard lately.
SHADOW CARJA: I saw a kestrel talking—
The food is from Dowager Queen Nasadi little ones.
Her Highness knows times are hard and helps when she can.
Eat, but bring some home for your families, if you have one.
I've heard whispers about you.
Rides machines, fancy spear, delightful freckles.
Some even say you have a conscience, how extraordinary!
Who are you? You're obviously not one of the Shadow Carja.
My name is Vanasha.
For now, all you need to know is that
I'm a whisper of reason in this howling pit of insanity.
Stop being evasive and tell me who you really are.
Stop being evasive? You might as well tell me to stop being charming.
It's impossible, but I like you so I'll tell you a secret.
I have friends in Meridian and I like to do favours for them when I can.
Uthid might be of use to them.
He's a good man, so naturally the Shadow Carja wanna murder him.
I've done some digging and I think he's headed for the Greenclimb.
It won't take those mercenaries long to find him.
He could use some help if you're so inclined.
What makes you think he's on the Greenclimb?
He knows he'll be pursued.
So he needs a hideout that's both familiar and defensible.
He once single-handedly held off an entire bandit clan in those foothills.
My guess is that he'll fall back on what worked before.
How do you know Uthid is innocent?
I'm excellent at making enquiries.
Look, he feeds orphans from his own rations
and personally punishes anyone who hurts the old or infirm.
The idea that he would try to kill Itamen is ridiculous.
He must have found something that can embarrass the priesthood.
Otherwise Bahavas wouldn't risk marking such a well-regarded man for death.
I'll do what I can for Uthid, but what about you?
What about me, what?
What will you do while I risk my life?
Useful things, little huntress.
Look for three dead trees south of Sunfall.
They mark the start of the Greenclimb. Good luck.
It'd be fascinating, if they weren't looking for me.
Three dead trees, just like Vanasha said.
Let's see if Uthid came through here.
The tracks stop here, time to climb.
Alright, made it. Where did you go Uthid?
Food scraps. I'll bet Uthid stopped to see if he was being followed.
He must have kept going, I've got to catch up.