ALOY: Somehow Elisabet stopped war machines from destroying the world.
ALOY: She couldn't save the civilisation of the Old Ones, that was destroyed obviously.
But life, it survived.
She saved life from being devoured.
I need to know how Elisabet stopped the machines.
If I can find the weapon she built and use it, the Eclipse won't stand a chance.
I went into the Grave-Hoard. It lived up to its name.
Millions of people fought and died to give Elisabet
the time she needed to finish Zero Dawn.
The weapon she built it wasn't there, but I found out where she built it.
A secret base west of here.
Right under Sunfall, the capital of the Shadow Carja.
I see you've been here before.
SYLENS, THROUGH FOCUS: Obviously.
SYLENS: I've spent a lifetime trying to uncover the secrets of this world.
ALOY: I'm heading down.
SYLENS: A lifetime of failure.
SYLENS: I hit walls I could not break, doors I could never breach.
SYLENS: Until a Nora huntress marched out of the savage east.
SYLENS: For her all the deepest secrets of the earth were laid bare.
ALOY: Hello.
SYLENS: I suspect you will have an easier time
with this door than I did years ago.
COMPUTER: Hold for Identiscan.
COMPUTER: Genetic profile confirmed. Entry authorised.
COMPUTER: Malfunction. Malfunction. Malfunction. Malfunction.
ALOY: Are you kidding me!
SYLENS: You don't hear me laughing.
ALOY: Shut up! There's got to be another way.
Hey! Elisabet Sobeck here, requesting access!
COMPUTER: Request acknowledged. Command functions available.
COMPUTER: Do you wish to proceed?
ALOY: I do, get me through this door!
COMPUTER: Analysing. Primary access inoperable due to mechanical failure.
COMPUTER: Emergency venting procedure likely to circumvent blockage.
COMPUTER: Do you wish to proceed?
Yes.
COMPUTER: Emergency venting authorised.
SYLENS: I underestimated you. You'd think by now, I—
ALOY: Guess you can't have everything.
SYLENS: That will draw attention.
SYLENS: We won't have this place to ourselves for long now.
ALOY: "We"? Last I checked, I was the one risking my life down here.
SYLENS: Yes, fine. Now will you please get moving?
SYLENS: There's so much to learn and less time than I'd hoped.
COMPUTER: Welcome to Project Zero Dawn.
ALOY: Zero Dawn, we found it!
SYLENS: Are you really so surprised?
COMPUTER: Facility diagnostics detect multiple failures. Attempting repair.
ALOY: So what was this room?
SYLENS: An Entrance hall perhaps. Have a look around.
COMPUTER: Please take a seat and wait for your name to be called.
COMPUTER: A selection of beverages and snacks are available.
ALOY: A smaller room.
COMPUTER: Please proceed into Viewing Room 1
for an important message regarding the purpose of your visit.
ALOY: What… what was this place?
SYLENS: A holographic theatre.
COMPUTER: ZD01 data intact. Initiating playback.
Welcome to Project Zero Dawn.
I am General Herres, chairman of
the Joint Chiefs of Staff of the United States of America.
I'm sure you've heard the rumours.
That Zero Dawn is a top secret superweapons programme.
The technological miracle that will save us from the Faro plague.
If Operation Enduring Victory can hold off the robots long enough.
The reason that I'm sure you've heard the rumours
is that I'm the one who spread them.
And they are all lies.
Zero Dawn is not a superweapons programme and it will not save us.
Nothing will save us.
And here's why.
By the time the glitch was noticed, it was already too late.
Nothing could stop the Faro plague. Nothing can.
Its robots will continue to replicate and devour the biosphere.
Life on Earth will be destroyed.
Our planet reduced to a barren sphere.
Global extinction is inevitable.
No matter how many we kill, the robots just keep exponentially making more.
If we had their deactivation codes
we could shut them all down, the entire swarm.
But since their cryptographic protocols used polyphasic
entangled waveforms, cracking a codeset would take half a century.
At best we've got sixteen months.
Not exactly what you'd call a survival option.
The destruction of a biosphere is not the sort of apocalypse
you can wait out in a fallout shelter or space station.
There will be no Earth left to reclaim.
Just a lifeless toxic rock with several million Faro robots on it.
Hibernating, waiting for something to eat.
This is the horrible truth behind the lies of Operation Enduring Victory.
My lies, lies designed to inspire
millions of innocents to sacrifice themselves in battle.
Why? One reason.
To buy time for you and the work you will do here.
Zero Day, the day that life on Earth ceases to exist, is coming fast.
It cannot be stopped.
The hope of Zero Dawn is that something new might come after.
But I will leave it to Elisabet Sobeck
to shine that thin ray of light into the darkness.
Herres out.
ALOY: That doesn't make sense.
ALOY: Life on Earth didn't cease to exist.
SYLENS: He said it could not be stopped.
ALOY: But it was! Somehow… somehow Elisabet saved us.
ALOY: I've got to keep looking. Find out how she did it.
ALOY: Kestrels. They got in, through the vents.
SYLENS: Let nothing stop you from learning the truth.
ECLIPSE: Spread out! If it moves kill it!
ECLIPSE: What is this place? A tomb?
ALOY: Spotted!
SYLENS: We're too close to let tribal primitives stop us now.
SYLENS: The datapoints, what do they contain?
COUNSELOR: —ing with Susanne Alpert, environmental scientist. Doctor?
SUSANNE ALPERT: I'm sorry? I wasn't, er…
COUNSELOR: Just stating your name. What were you thinking about, doctor?
SUSANNE ALPERT: Nothing the general said, not really.
SUSANNE ALPERT: I was on the Syzygy East Response Team in 2051,
just after the second earthquake compromised the reactor.
SUSANNE ALPERT: I still dream about it after all these years.
SUSANNE ALPERT: The red zone spreading on the imaging
slowly, so slowly, like a hand opening its fingers.
COUNSELOR: Your involvement in that event is why you were asked for by name.
SUSANNE ALPERT: Really? That's interesting because nothing worked.
SUSANNE ALPERT: Nothing could grow there again.
SUSANNE ALPERT: It was a catastrophic failure.
SUSANNE ALPERT: But the red zone is a blip
compared to global scale biomass reduction.
SUSANNE ALPERT: The biosphere and hydrosphere will collapse,
render the Earth uninhabitable long before the robots finish us.
SUSANNE ALPERT: Enduring Victory can't buy time against that.
SUSANNE ALPERT: So you'd better show me what Zero Dawn really is.
COUNSELOR: I'm sure you now understand
the urgency of why we brought you here Ms Okilo?
CPT. OKILO: Captain Okilo. Are you trying to thank me for not resisting?
COUNSELOR: I believe we couldn't negotiate a diplomatic solution.
CPT. OKILO: When it came to my country's lithium
it was always a swarm that would be sent to negotiate.
CPT. OKILO: Metallurgic International, US Robot Command,
the markings changed, but the robots were the same.
COUNSELOR: You have had considerable experience in human-robot conflict.
CPT. OKILO: Yes, and I've got the prosthetic limbs to show it.
CPT. OKILO: Yet I continue
to face this horror even though the challenge was great.
CPT. OKILO: Cyber warfare. I thought Zero Dawn
would be a–a Manhattan Project to generate the deactivation codes.
CPT. OKILO: With the resources I had
I estimated codebreaking to be a hopeless endeavour.
CPT. OKILO: I was almost looking forward to being proved wrong.
COUNSELOR: Unfortunately, your estimation was correct.
CPT. OKILO: As your General Herres said.
CPT. OKILO: So then. You didn't bring me here to commiserate, what is left?
RON FELDER: Look, let's cut the mystery.
RON FELDER: You're building a colony ship, it's obvious.
RON FELDER: And it's not gonna fly. I mean, literally.
RON FELDER: Remember the Odyssey, that multinational
heap of space junk that's been in graveyard orbit since '57?
RON FELDER: That went nowhere real slow,
and you have to get somewhere real fast.
RON FELDER: Do you have any idea
the immensity of the challenge to prep a new colony ship in time?
COUNSELOR: To be clear, I'm not a worker on the project.
RON FELDER: Do you even understand how few people it could save?
RON FELDER: The whole generation ship concept is… is not gonna happen.
RON FELDER: It's the first thing you'd abandon in favour of embryonics.
RON FELDER: For that kind of storage we're talking
a lot of bulk, a lot of power, a lot of resources.
RON FELDER: So even if you do it, even if you build it
and point it at Sirius X, there's no room for people on that thing, alright?
COUNSELOR: If you could try to remain calm…
RON FELDER: You people are crazy if you think
you're getting off this rock, no-one's getting off!
COUNSELOR: Medical!
DR. HSU-VHEY: There is some mistake.
DR. HSU-VHEY: I don't understand why I was brought here.
DR. HSU-VHEY: Why would you show me these things?
COUNSELOR: I know that there's already a lot to take in.
DR. HSU-VHEY: In the waiting area I was seated with
a Nobel laureate in biophysics and a monk, I think.
DR. HSU-VHEY: He spoke neither English nor Mandarin.
DR. HSU-VHEY: It is very strange.
DR. HSU-VHEY: And General Herres, what was he talking about?
DR. HSU-VHEY: The robot swarm, the Faro plague?
DR. HSU-VHEY: I understand it is terrible, but it really cannot be stopped?
DR. HSU-VHEY: Why tell us this?
DR. HSU-VHEY: There are people in Shanghai, my friends, my family.
DR. HSU-VHEY: They have joined Operation Enduring Victory already.
DR. HSU-VHEY: It is for nothing? We will all die?
COUNSELOR: We're going to be able to answer some of these questions.
DR. HSU-VHEY: I just want to know why I am here.
DR. HSU-VHEY: It doesn't make sense to me.
COUNSELOR: You were brought here because of your skill set.
DR. HSU-VHEY: No, that can't be right.
DR. HSU-VHEY: I am an art historian.
DR. HSU-VHEY: I know Dutch masters, Japanese calligraphy, Gerhard Richter.
DR. HSU-VHEY: What does that matter now?
COUNSELOR: —that is accurate, yes.
TOM PAECH: So these mechanical monstrosities
they don't just kill people, they feed off them?
COUNSELOR: Not just people, all organic matter.
TOM PAECH: Every living thing dissolved into nutrients.
TOM PAECH: Millennia of evolution liquefied.
TOM PAECH: The miracle of life reduced to bloody biofuel?!
COUNSELOR: In a word, yes.
TOM PAECH: Who did this? Faro? That arsehole, is he here?
COUNSELOR: No, Doctor, please…
TOM PAECH: Tell him Tom Paech wants a word!
[sounds of struggling]
TOM PAECH: Nah, get off, get off!
COUNSELOR: Doc, please!
TOM PAECH: You get Ted Faro in here!
COUNSELOR: —want to discuss?
TRAVIS TATE: Whoof. So Mama, she was right.
COUNSELOR: Pardon?
TRAVIS TATE: My mother. She took her Bible real serious.
TRAVIS TATE: Not just Texas Bubble serious, Pentecostal serious.
TRAVIS TATE: Favourite chapter? Revelations.
TRAVIS TATE: Now, I didn't always understand her
on account of all that speaking in tongues and such, but…
TRAVIS TATE: When she did use her words, it was always
"end times" this and "the lake of fire" that on account of sinful lifestyles.
TRAVIS TATE: Speaking of which, mind if I smoke?
COUNSELOR: A tobacco cigarette?
TRAVIS TATE: Sorry, darlin'. My tastes run classic.
TRAVIS TATE: Compliments to your team tracked me down.
TRAVIS TATE: Been a price on my head eighteen months now.
TRAVIS TATE: Sterling-Malkeet was me, don't mind admitting.
TRAVIS TATE: Been plenty of snakesters chasing the bounty too.
TRAVIS TATE: But I kept the zigging to their zag.
TRAVIS TATE: How'd you finger me?
COUNSELOR: I believe Dr Sobeck listed you as an Alpha candidate.
COUNSELOR: Priority snatch and grab.
TRAVIS TATE: Always suspected she had a little thing for me.
TRAVIS TATE: Hey, I don't suppose you got real coffee in this place?
TRAVIS TATE: You know, blood coffee? Conflict cappuccinos?
COUNSELOR: Mr. Tate, I'm clearing you to proceed. Just … go.
COUNSELOR: You previously worked for Faro Automated Systems.
BRAD ANDAC: On the Chariot line self-replication routines.
BRAD ANDAC: I–I came here thinking this was a–a rendition?
BRAD ANDAC: When your people took me, I thought "about time".
BRAD ANDAC: I've been trying to swallow the guilt every day since…
BRAD ANDAC: …since, uh…
COUNSELOR: Would you like to take a moment?
BRAD ANDAC: No, no, no, I just…
BRAD ANDAC: I really hoped Zero Dawn was a way to undo it all.
BRAD ANDAC: My work.
BRAD ANDAC: I'm sorry to say I was ever proud of it,
but Ted could really sell a concept.
BRAD ANDAC: And–and–and in the labs,
in the light of creation, that first test run.
BRAD ANDAC: When–when you saw they understood their own structures,
could rebuild themselves from memory and light?
BRAD ANDAC: There were no limits!
BRAD ANDAC: God, there were no limits.
COMPUTER: ZD02 data intact. Initiating playback.
Elisabet Sobeck.
You've heard the bad news and it's all true.
The Faro plague is devouring the biosphere.
Life itself will cease to exist.
But does that have to be the end?
What if we could give life a future?
What if we could build a kind of seed
from which, on a dead planet, life could blossom anew?
This is the aim, the hope, of Project Zero Dawn.
To create a super-intelligent, fully automated
terraforming system and bring life back from lifelessness.
What would such a system require?
At its core it would need a true AI fully capable of making
the trillions of decisions necessary to reconstitute the biosphere.
An immortal guardian devoted to the reflourishing of life.
We call it GAIA.
Mother Nature as an AI.
But that's just the core of the system.
She will need to be surrounded and empowered
by a comprehensive suite of subordinate functions.
Think of them as extensions of GAIA's mind.
Each dedicated to a specific purpose.
Now these aren't AIs, but make no mistake.
Each presents an engineering challenge more profound
than anything the human species has ever before attempted.
Hardware that preserves and then gestates
the billions of seeds and embryos from which life will be reborn.
The construction of underground facilities to hold it all.
And that's just the start.
We don't have to build the entire system.
The beauty of a fully automated terraforming system is that it can build itself.
Now over the days to come, you'll learn how all these functions,
all these pieces that you'll be working on fit together.
How we'll race the clock to execute our harvest initiatives,
write the software, build the tech, and the facilities.
How we'll lock it down and seal it up before the inevitable occurs.
But even more important, you'll know how it doesn't end here.
How GAIA will generate those deactivation codes General Herres talked about.
And build the transmission arrays to broadcast them,
shutting down the Faro robots for good.
How GAIA will not just build but imagine
any conceivable robot it needs to do its work across centuries.
From detoxifying the Earth's ravaged atmosphere and poisoned seas.
To the regreening of the Earth from cryopreserved seed stocks.
To rewilding the Earth with animal life.
And then, when all that is done, how a new generation of human beings
spawned at cradle facilities around the globe will partake of Apollo.
The vast archive of human knowledge and cultural achievement
from which they will learn of us, our world.
And most important, how not to repeat our mistakes.
It's not an impossible dream.
It is within our grasp if we worked tirelessly and stop at nothing to achieve it.
We can't stop life from ending.
But if you will help me, help GAIA, we can give it a future.
Join me and help make that future real.
ALOY: The whole Earth destroyed, but then remade?
SYLENS: Yes, by a machine. A machine of creation.
ALOY: Elisabet did this for life, for us.
ALOY: But why Hades then?
ALOY: If it was part of GAIA, how'd it end up in the wreckage of a Faro robot?
ALOY: And why does it want to kill me?
ALOY: And Apollo, the archive of knowledge, what happened to that?
SYLENS: And Hephaestus taking over CYAN.
SYLENS: I'm as confused as you are.
SYLENS: Maybe the answers lie ahead.
BRAD ANDAC: Of course I'll do it.
BRAD ANDAC: To be given the opportunity to rebuild what I, uh, d-d-damaged?
BRAD ANDAC: Well, I-I don't feel worthy of it, but I will do it absolutely.
COUNSELLOR: I want to stress that this was never about your culpability.
BRAD ANDAC: Uh, i-i-it is to me.
BRAD ANDAC: Doctor Sobeck, Margo,
they were smart to get out of Faro when they did.
BRAD ANDAC: But-but not one of us took it as a warning sign.
BRAD ANDAC: We just told ourselves they weren't cut out for the BTRI cabals.
BRAD ANDAC: That's the "Better Than Rapid Innovation".
BRAD ANDAC: Better at competing,
better than the next guy, a better killing machine.
BRAD ANDAC: Isn't it just amazing how century and half of science-fiction
did nothing to swerve our species from the path of doom?
BRAD ANDAC: I mean, I'm… I'm done with that life.
BRAD ANDAC: I mean, I will work hard, twice as hard to earn this.
BRAD ANDAC: For my family to have a place in Elysium.
BRAD ANDAC: I never thought I… that there could be atonement.
COUNSELLOR: –if you're still nauseous…?
SUSANNE ALPERT: No, the inhibitors have kicked in.
SUSANNE ALPERT: I can't feel the back of my tongue.
SUSANNE ALPERT: I wish I could tell you I'd believe in this.
SUSANNE ALPERT: But the damage is too great, too extensive, too complete.
SUSANNE ALPERT: With all respect to Dr Sobeck's work at Miriam?
SUSANNE ALPERT: No, no! Life doesn't always find a way to keep going.
SUSANNE ALPERT: Sometimes it never comes back.
SUSANNE ALPERT: Like Syzygy East, like the Congo, like Timor, like us.
SUSANNE ALPERT: That's our reward?
A buried city full of terminal patients waiting out the clock?
COUNSELLOR: You'd grow old together with your loved ones in safety.
SUSANNE ALPERT: I don't have loved ones. I suppose I could start a family?
COUNSELLOR: I'm afraid not, all inhabitants of Elysium will be medically sterilised.
SUSANNE ALPERT: [exasperation noises]
COUNSELLOR: A habitat capable of sustaining a starting base of
two thousand individuals for up to a hundred years is a huge challenge Dr Alpert.
COUNSELLOR: If the population grows instead of diminishes,
everyone will be dead inside thirty years.
SUSANNE ALPERT: I knew it. I just couldn't bring myself to say the words.
COUNSELLOR: I'm sorry?
SUSANNE ALPERT: Finish it. Medical euthanasia.
SUSANNE ALPERT: I want no part of this. I just want it over.
COUNSELLOR: I see.
COUNSELLOR: Protocols require a 48-hour waiting period after which—
RON FELDER: Is he to make sure I behave this time?
COUNSELLOR: Security, for your protection.
COUNSELLOR: Would you like to discuss how you're feeling?
RON FELDER: Sure, I'll tell you.
RON FELDER: Surprised. No, flabbergasted.
RON FELDER: Like my old man would say, flabbergasted.
RON FELDER: That vein pumping in his forehead. I'd thought…
RON FELDER: I'd thought you people were
just completely under-prepared for a spaceflight project.
RON FELDER: But now I can see it's worse, much worse.
RON FELDER: Sobeck is a total fantasist, a dangerous fantasist.
RON FELDER: This kind of blue-skying i-i-its … Jesus!
RON FELDER: I'm sorry we wasted each other's time.
RON FELDER: I'm ready to leave now.
COUNSELLOR: I'm afraid that's not possible.
RON FELDER: Ha! Everything you're talking about here isn't possible!
COUNSELOR: I recommend you read the documents regarding your options.
RON FELDER: I've seen enough. I'm getting out of here.
RON FELDER: What are you…? You don't…! Get your hands off me!
COMPUTER: Alert. Medical wing inaccessible.
ECLIPSE: Intruder! Get her!
SYLENS: Whatever you do, don't die now!
ECLIPSE: Bleed before the shadow!
ECLIPSE: Close in!
ECLIPSE: Guide me—
ECLIPSE: Let this strike upon—
ECLIPSE: —not make it.
ECLIPSE: To destroy the unworthy!
ECLIPSE: What else you got?!
ECLIPSE: Face the Sun's judgement!
ECLIPSE: I'll feel that tomorrow. That hurt!
TOM PAECH: I hashed it out with them.
TOM PAECH: What the point of Artemis was.
TOM PAECH: I made it clear I wasn't on board for a global zoo.
TOM PAECH: We haven't exactly proved ourselves
to be great custodians in the past few thousand years.
TOM PAECH: So the idea of a reconstituted biosphere…
TOM PAECH: Well, it's horrifying, isn't it?
TOM PAECH: A complete horror show.
TOM PAECH: We have no right to take a best guess at this stuff.
TOM PAECH: But the alternative? Nothingness.
TOM PAECH: For there to have been all this and then… nothing.
TOM PAECH: And with Charles Ronson running the show?
TOM PAECH: I respect him. He's got a passion to him, he's hot-blooded.
TOM PAECH: So I said I'll do it. I'll put my all into this, literally.
TOM PAECH: When the project is done I'll take the medical option, thank you.
TOM PAECH: Counsellor said I might change my mind.
TOM PAECH: I told him that he didn't know me very well, then.
TOM PAECH: For life's sake I'll do the dirty work.
TOM PAECH: But I want no part of this pathetic attenuated future on offer.
TOM PAECH: I'm an outdoors man.
TOM PAECH: Never did like the feel of solid-state lighting on my skin.
TOM PAECH: And a wee bit of a claustrophobe anyway.
DR. HSU-VHEY: Zero Dawn. It is art, in a way.
DR. HSU-VHEY: An expression on the grandest scale.
DR. HSU-VHEY: But there is so much unfairness.
DR. HSU-VHEY: Why was I chosen?
DR. HSU-VHEY: Was it decided by committee, by algorithm?
DR. HSU-VHEY: My family will be saved
because I happen to graduate in art history?
DR. HSU-VHEY: Is this right?
MALE VOICE: Dr Hsu-Vhey? Christina Hsu-Vhey?
DR. HSU-VHEY: Yes?
[recording interrupted]
DR. HSU-VHEY: I met a man, another historian.
DR. HSU-VHEY: His fields are Bauhaus and the New Materialists.
DR. HSU-VHEY: But he once attended one of my talks.
DR. HSU-VHEY: Another unfair chance.
DR. HSU-VHEY: Of all the many people
in that auditorium, that we should both be here now?
DR. HSU-VHEY: And yet I feel more accepting of my fate.
DR. HSU-VHEY: No, it is not fair, not at all.
DR. HSU-VHEY: But for the sake of my family, for the sake of art…
DR. HSU-VHEY: Art is alive!
DR. HSU-VHEY: It must be able
to speak from beyond history and echo in the future.
DR. HSU-VHEY: Not perish into oblivion.
DR. HSU-VHEY: This opportunity? I must do this.
TRAVIS TATE: Now, those lame FBI black hats at Mockingbird back in the day?
TRAVIS TATE: I enjoyed schooling them.
TRAVIS TATE: But maybe I went in too hard on this poor counsellor.
TRAVIS TATE: She was cute, and just going down a checklist after all.
TRAVIS TATE: Couldn't expect her to see how ridiculous Zero D's ambitions are.
TRAVIS TATE: God's own budget thrown at a kid playing with a hologram sculptor?
TRAVIS TATE: Palms up, honey, I'm just calling it like it is.
TRAVIS TATE: "Hey look Mom, I'm making nature!"
TRAVIS TATE: Now if nature is so important, why not let nature take its course?
TRAVIS TATE: Extinction? That's natural. Zero Dawn? No ma'am, that ain't.
TRAVIS TATE: Heck, it's so unnatural it'd be called
an abomination back home and you know it.
TRAVIS TATE: That's why you're hiding it.
TRAVIS TATE: Meanwhile, my little honey of a counsellor,
she's munching the inside of her cheek.
TRAVIS TATE: Bad habit. She chewed one of her nails too, just one.
TRAVIS TATE: Not your day was it little sweet pea?
TRAVIS TATE: Saw her quota slipping away.
TRAVIS TATE: Said "I assume you intend to decline the assignment, Mr Tate?"
TRAVIS TATE: [laugh] Are you kidding me?
TRAVIS TATE: Eighteen months hard labour in exchange
for thirty years lounging around Elysium watching porn?
TRAVIS TATE: Sign me up!
ALOY: Power's down.
SYLENS: Is there another route?
ALOY: I've done this before, just need my Focus.
ALOY: Here we go, another one of these.
ALOY: I need to find the right configuration.
ALOY: Done, I should check the door nearby.
ALOY: Found one, looks intact.
ALOY: That should do the trick.
ALOY: Now let's get that door open.
PARKER: Hey, I'm done with Brett's incompetence, okay?
PARKER: Somehow he managed to install an H-emitter node backwards.
PARKER: Everything's in reverse.
PARKER: I don't get paid to clean up Brett's messes.
PARKER: If you want it fixed, send him up to storage for a new emitter, not me.
PARKER: Parker out.
ALOY: That did it, door should have power.
SYLENS: Now to see what lies beyond it.
ALOY: Eclipse, they're here.
SYLENS: Avoid contact!