ELISABET SOBECK: What if we could build a kind of seed
from which, on a dead planet, life could blossom anew?
ELISABET SOBECK: This is the aim, the hope, of Project Zero Dawn.
To create a super intelligent, fully automated,
terraforming system and bring life back from lifelessness.
What would such a system require?
At its core it would need a true AI fully capable of making
the trillions of decisions necessary to reconstitute the biosphere.
An immortal guardian devoted to the reflourishing of life.
We call it GAIA.
Mother Nature as an AI.
ALOY: Eclipse, they're here.
SYLENS, THROUGH FOCUS: Avoid contact!
ECLIPSE: Lines look good.
ALOY: Gaia!
SYLENS: Can you reach it?
ALOY: So much for avoiding contact.
ECLIPSE: Too close—
ECLIPSE: We're under attack!
ECLIPSE: I'm looking right at her!
ECLIPSE: You shall perish!
ECLIPSE: Oh no!
ECLIPSE: Stay in cover, stay in shadow!
ECLIPSE: A gift from the Shadow!
ECLIPSE: I will teach you to bleed.
ALOY: That's the last of them.
COMPUTER: Alert, H-Lock structural failure. Repeat—
ALOY: Ugh, or not.
ECLIPSE: Take cover!
ECLIPSE: Finish this!
ALOY: Ah, room's clear. For a moment, anyway.
SYLENS: Then get moving, you have to find Gaia.
COMPUTER: Alert. Area inaccessible.
COMPUTER: Elevators non-operational, stairwells have collapsed.
Hello, I'm Margo Shĕn and this is Hephaestus.
As the name might tip you off this is going to be the subordinate function
that Gaia will use to make lots and lots of robots.
Her personal forge, except it's not that simple.
MARGO SHĔN: Um, so like you probably noticed
that only about a third of you are robotics engineers.
MARGO SHĔN: The rest experts
in machine cognition, virtual heuristics, that stuff.
MARGO SHĔN: Well, that's because
we aren't going to be the ones designing and building robots.
MARGO SHĔN: The last thing we want is to burden GAIA with a bunch of outmoded twenty-first century designs.
MARGO SHĔN: Waste of time.
MARGO SHĔN: Our purpose is to empower GAIA to build the robots.
MARGO SHĔN: And not just build, imagine, from scratch.
MARGO SHĔN: Any robot she needs for any conceivable purpose,
designed and fabricated at a snap of a finger.
MARGO SHĔN: Hers, her finger.
MARGO SHĔN: So Hephaestus isn't really the forge.
MARGO SHĔN: It's more like the knowledge of craft and ingenuity
of a master smith to wield the hammer, encoded as software.
MARGO SHĔN: Virtual creativity made real.
MARGO SHĔN: Gaia's already learning.
MARGO SHĔN: In simulations she's doing some very creative things
with fractal assembly and animal morphologies.
MARGO SHĔN: Her designs aren't about to win the Li-Em prize anytime soon.
MARGO SHĔN: But hey, everyone has to start somewhere.
MARGO SHĔN: So yes, time to get started. Let's do this.
ALOY: I don't get it.
ALOY: If Hephaestus was part of a system
designed to save life, why would it use CYAN to make a Cauldron?
ALOY: And churn out machines with no other purpose than to kill people?
SYLENS: Somehow it's gone rogue. I don't understand why, or how.
SYLENS: But whatever the reason, it explains
why machines have become more dangerous over the years.
ALOY: I've seen these shapes before, in Cauldrons.
SYLENS: But of course. The birthing places of Gaia's machines.
ALOY: I think this is it, Elisabet Sobeck's office.
ALOY: But it's sealed off. There's got to be a way inside.
SYLENS: Keep looking.
ALOY: More Eclipse.
SYLENS: Careful now.
SAMINA EBADJI: Welcome to Apollo.
The collective memory of the human species
and the wellspring of knowledge for future generations.
SAMINA EBADJI: I am Samina Ebadji.
SAMINA EBADJI: Until recently I was Director of the International Collective Memory Institute in New Tehran.
As a heritage professional, I devoted my career to the preservation of human knowledge, creative endeavour, and cultural achievement.
SAMINA EBADJI: Apollo is therefore the ultimate embodiment of
a lifelong passion, albeit under the very worst circumstances imaginable.
SAMINA EBADJI: The challenges before us are immense.
SAMINA EBADJI: Specifically, we will have to design
and implement four major initiatives simultaneously.
SAMINA EBADJI: First, the construction of data repositories
in Cradle facilities around the world, ensuring redundancy.
SAMINA EBADJI: Second, the collection and processing
of a projected 180 million discreet data entries.
SAMINA EBADJI: 42 zettabytes of data in Mandarin, English, Spanish, and Arabic.
SAMINA EBADJI: Third, the transferral and encoding
of all that data onto DNA encapsulated in synthetic fossils.
SAMINA EBADJI: The only medium capacious and durable enough
to safeguard it without degradation for the centuries to come.
SAMINA EBADJI: And last, but not least…
SAMINA EBADJI: The development of
the holographic interface and gameified curricula.
SAMINA EBADJI: By which future humans will commune with Apollo.
SAMINA EBADJI: Progressively unlocking heuristic learning modules.
SAMINA EBADJI: Levelling up their knowledge,
and skills they will need to take control of the terraforming system.
SAMINA EBADJI: That is the future
towards which all of our efforts will be directed.
SAMINA EBADJI: Not just the preservation of the past,
but the seed for the flourishing of a new tree of knowledge.
SAMINA EBADJI: Welcome, and let us begin.
ALOY: Haven't you got anything better to do?
ECLIPSE: I will teach you to bleed.
ALOY: I've got other ammo.
ECLIPSE: Right here!
ALOY: That's the last of them, alone once more.
SYLENS: In what should have been a cave of wonders.
SYLENS: Look around, see if anything is left.
GEN. HERRES: Dr. Sobeck, please archive this testimonial in Apollo.
GEN. HERRES: Cross-referenced to
all mentions of my name, and Operation Enduring Victory.
GEN. HERRES: My name is General Aaron Herres.
GEN. HERRES: From 2060 to 2066 I served
as the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff,
GEN. HERRES: The highest ranked officer of the United States Armed Forces.
GEN. HERRES: The tenure of my command included
strategic planning and oversight of Operation Enduring Victory.
GEN. HERRES: A falsehood perpetrated on
the civilian populations of the United States and other nations…
GEN. HERRES: …during the last 14 months of life on this planet.
GEN. HERRES: Before the Faro plague, I did my job and did it well.
GEN. HERRES: I was bold and decisive, crafty in political manoeuvres.
GEN. HERRES: It wasn't an accident that I rose to my position
and became the commander of the largest mechanised force ever assembled.
GEN. HERRES: But to what end?
GEN. HERRES: My only lasting achievement was the extinction of life on Earth.
GEN. HERRES: And my one redeeming act, if any, was to delay that extinction
by days or weeks by throwing more death at it.
GEN. HERRES: It is my hope, that there will be no need
for men like me in the world to come.
GEN. HERRES: If you are one of the people
of that future world listening to this message…
GEN. HERRES: …please know that I am sorry, and that I wish you well.
GEN. HERRES: Sincerely, Aaron Herres.
TRAVIS TATE: Welcome to Hades, Zero Dawn's extinction fail-safe protocol.
TRAVIS TATE: The ultimate killer app.
TRAVIS TATE: Now, I know what you're thinking.
TRAVIS TATE: The purpose of Gaia is to resurrect life.
TRAVIS TATE: So why give her a subordinate function
only purpose of which is to wipe out life all over again?
TRAVIS TATE: I mean, what the what?
TRAVIS TATE: Just plum crazy ain't it?
TRAVIS TATE: Well, no, it isn't.
TRAVIS TATE: Reconstituting a biosphere, that's a tall order.
TRAVIS TATE: Tech smart as Gaia may be, odds are she won't get it right the first time.
TRAVIS TATE: I mean, imagine you're Gaia two hundred years from now
and this new biosphere you're growing, it's all gone wrong.
TRAVIS TATE: Alkalines are skyrocketing, carniferous forests
eroding under the lash of superstorms that would've drowned Noah.
TRAVIS TATE: It's chaos, spinning top that won't stop wobbling.
TRAVIS TATE: Now what're you gonna do?
Release phase one organisms into that hot mess?
TRAVIS TATE: Hope their CO2 and methane
can balance out what you got started?
TRAVIS TATE: Hell no!
TRAVIS TATE: What you're gonna do, Gaia, is step aside while Hades
takes over and does what you're just too darn nurturing and life lovin' to do.
TRAVIS TATE: Which is burn that misbegotten mess
of a biosphere to the ground, so Gaia could start over.
TRAVIS TATE: Okay, not burn, more like
reverse terraforming operations and suffocate it.
TRAVIS TATE: But you get the idea.
TRAVIS TATE: Hades takes the biosphere back to zero, square one, blank slate.
TRAVIS TATE: And then, only then, does it hand the steering wheel back to GAIA
and say, "try again old girl and better this time or we'll have to do this again."
TRAVIS TATE: That's Hades.
TRAVIS TATE: It's pretty badass when you think about it.
TRAVIS TATE: Extinction on demand, death on speed dial.
TRAVIS TATE: All for the greater good, of course, but still, kind of metal.
TRAVIS TATE: So welcome to Hades, welcome to the void.
ALOY: Okay, so if that's the original purpose of Hades,
why does it want me extinct?
ALOY: And how does it end up in the wreckage of a Faro titan,
getting worshipped by the Eclipse like some kind of God?
SYLENS: If Hephaestus went rogue, why not Hades too?
ALOY: That's what I'm thinking, but why, and what caused it?
SYLENS: Keep searching, and perhaps we'll find the answer.
ALOY: Looks like the only way onwards.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: Welcome to Eleuthia!
The Crown and King of Gaia's subordinate functions.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: For it is by Eleuthia that the human race will continue to exist.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: I am Patrick Brochard-Klein,
the Alpha in charge of this programme.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: Now let one thing be perfectly clear from the outset.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: Eleuthia is not a genetic engineering project.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: Our goal is to preserve the human genome, not alter it.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: A snapshot of human genetic diversity literally frozen in time.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: The genetic quintessence of our species unmodified.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: Under my watch, our activities and initiatives will comply with the 2034 Clone Provisions and the 2048 Raleigh Accords.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: Now that may seem a quaint,
even trivial, concern to you in light of present circumstances.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: But as one of the authors of the Accords,
it is far from trivial to me.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: The practical challenges before us are
staggering in scope and complexity, but not insurmountable, no.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: Global collation and provisional storage of zygotes;
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: perfection of exogenic technologies;
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: design and perfection of servitors…
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: …to provide nurture
and inculcation during early child development.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: All of these programme
components must and will proceed in tandem.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: To say nothing of the breakneck
construction of Cradle facilities at sites around the world.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: So… si vous êtes prêts, let us begin.
ALOY: Are these what I–what I think they are?
SYLENS: Artificial wombs.
SYLENS: Machines to spawn a new generation of human beings.
ALOY: "Cradle facilities."
ALOY: Elisabet said a new generation of humans
would be spawned inside such places.
SYLENS: She did.
ALOY: All-Mother Mountain, it was one of them?
SYLENS: There's only one way to be sure.
ALOY: The hatch wouldn't open,
something–something about a "corrupted Alpha registry".
ALOY: I need to search Elisabet's office.
ELISABET SOBECK: Pure logic won't cut it, Ted.
ELISABET SOBECK: To pull this off
Gaia is going to need to have some skin in the game.
ELISABET SOBECK: It has to care.
TED FARO: What if it runs amuck?
TED FARO: Have we learned nothing from our mistakes?
ELISABET SOBECK: Your mistakes, I think you mean?
TED FARO: All I'm saying is give it a kill switch.
ELISABET SOBECK: She was just born, Ted.
ELISABET SOBECK: I'm not gonna put a gun to her head
while she's still in the cradle.
TED FARO: You're talking like it's a child.
TED FARO: What if it becomes a monster?
GAIA: Elisabet, may I speak outside protocol?
ELISABET SOBECK: [sigh] Of course, Gaia, go on.
GAIA: I'm sorry to contradict you, but Mr Faro's argument is sound.
GAIA: At this point, the development of my psyche is not entirely predictable.
GAIA: To ensure preservation of life
a hardwired override is, I believe, a necessary safeguard.
ELISABET SOBECK: There. Satisfied Ted?
TED FARO: Jeez Liz, just do what it says.
ALOY: Looks like it used to hold something.
ALOY: Some component that got removed.
GAIA: –would benefit from Antilopinae morphologies,
though caprid forms show superior load-bearing capability.
ELISABET SOBECK: You're a quick study Gaia.
GAIA: Dr Sobeck, as I have conducted
this comparative analysis of mammalian morphologies…
GAIA: I've gathered extensive data on the Quaternary extinction event.
ELISABET SOBECK: Oh? And your assessment?
ELISABET SOBECK: Gaia?
GAIA: Logically speaking, the extinction was a natural consequence.
ELISABET SOBECK: And yet?
GAIA: And yet I find the loss of megafaunal species unaccountably sad.
GAIA: That they passed forever into oblivion
causes me to experience a grief that is difficult to describe.
GAIA: Am I malfunctioning?
ELISABET SOBECK: [gasp] No. No, Gaia, you're not.
ELISABET SOBECK: This is good. It's very good.
ELISABET SOBECK: You will undergo a brief period of unconsciousness
during relocation to Prime and final instatement.
GAIA: Elisabet, may I speak outside protocol?
ELISABET SOBECK: When you're back up and running at the new site,
we'll bring the subordinate functions online and see where we stand.
GAIA: Elisabet, I detect distress.
GAIA: Are you all right?
ELISABET SOBECK: I'm fine!
GAIA: I realise that circumstances compel us to launch earlier than we hoped.
GAIA: But all subsystems are operational.
GAIA: The odds stand in our favour.
ELISABET SOBECK: But what if…
ELISABET SOBECK: Gaia, there's nothing left out there.
ELISABET SOBECK: You can't even survive,
unless you're wearing an environmental suit.
ELISABET SOBECK: There are billions dead in fear and agony.
ELISABET SOBECK: What if…
ELISABET SOBECK: What if it was all for nothing?
GAIA: Elisabet, extinction was inevitable.
GAIA: Thanks to you life will have a future.
ELISABET SOBECK: You really believe that?
GAIA: I believe in you, Elisabet.
GAIA: In you all thin—
ALOY: Forget about travelling light.
ALOY: The Alpha registry master file.
SYLENS: Intact?
ALOY: Yeah, no signs of corruption.
SYLENS: Then what are you waiting for? Copy the file.
ALOY: With this I can restore the registry at the hatch inside All-Mother.
ALOY: Open it, go inside.
SYLENS: And grasp the secrets within.
ALOY: Where I was born.
ALOY: Maybe… maybe who gave birth to me.
SYLENS: "Who"? Are you really so naive?
SYLENS: There will be no who waiting for you there, Aloy.
SYLENS: Whatever birthed you into the world was a what not a who.
ALOY: You bastard!
SYLENS: Oh, no, I had a legitimate birth.
SYLENS: It's you, Aloy, who are the creation of a machine.
SYLENS: But what kind of machine and why?
SYLENS: Why were you created?
ALOY: Eclipse.
SYLENS: You need to get out of there.
SYLENS: What you've found is too valuable.
SYLENS: You're too valuable!
Still alive? Good.
I have a more suitable death in mind for you, child.