GAIA: Go to the ruins of Gaia Prime,
find the control room, and within it the master override.
This will give you the power to purge Hades so long as you find a way to wield it.
Do not attempt repair of the system core until Hades is eradicated.
Hades must be destroyed.
That is all.
I only wish that I could hear your voice again.
Snow. It's not getting any warmer out here.
This old place, I haven't been here in years.
Wonder what I can find?
You're a question waiting for an answer.
That area back there, I wonder if I can find a way into it now that I'm older?
SKYLAR RIVERA: Director Evans.
SKYLAR RIVERA: Flash traffic from USRC, black quartz encryption.
SKYLAR RIVERA: I've routed the message to your hologrid for viewing.
Another power cell.
I only need one more to get to that ancient armour I found.
No space.
Need them soon enough.
It's okay, don't kick.
Those machines are alert.
I'll find a use for you.
Calm, calm.
Saving these for the trail.
Hoping they'd miss me.
Just stay out of their way for now.
Well, here I am.
BANDIT: Give us what you got!
OSERAM: By the forge, I believe I've earned a drink or two!
OSERAM: —like an opportunity—
OSERAM: Girl, what are you doing to that machine? It's not a toy!
Keep quiet now.
SYLENS, THROUGH FOCUS: The way to the mountain will be hard.
SYLENS: Ferocious machines prowl every step of the climb.
ALOY: More corrupted?
SYLENS: Not corrupted, but they will not tolerate humans.
ALOY: So what else is new?
[whistle]
ALOY: Stalkers in the open, Watchers on the other side.
ALOY: This will help.
ALOY: Do they think they're guarding Gaia?
SYLENS: I doubt they think all.
SYLENS: More like an instinct, gathering them to her grave.
ALOY: Now I know what they're guarding.
ALOY: More than equipped to take you on!
ALOY: My turn.
ALOY: Down you go!
ALOY: Guessing that I'm almost there.
SYLENS: Correct.
ALOY: Here they come.
ALOY: That one held!
ALOY: I can get out of this.
ALOY: Here they come.
ALOY: It's too weak.
ALOY: That'd better have been the biggest guard you've got, Gaia.
ALOY: This fluid's powerful. Burns at my fingers, but not like the corruption does.
ALOY: I'll tuck that away.
ALOY: It's cold.