I have to tell Avad that the Eclipse are ready to strike.
After what happened with Dervahl, I know he'll defend the city.
But the Spire?
Quick way down.
Save these for the trail.
Pain's drawing back.
Can't be too prepared.
I can still get the upper hand.
Stay down!
Keep quiet now.
Uhhh maybe I've spent too much time with you.
I can almost feel the lightning in this.
A-a-and the taste, huh?!
Metal striking sparks along a sharpening stone, lingering…
Here, touch it to your tongue and—
No, that's your thing, not mine.
You look startled, are you okay?
I…
I must leave, you should too.
Without a story? I brought down a Stormbird.
You did, you're very able, and you're right, owed is owed.
But no more stories of the past, all told, all done.
Future stories.
I saw an onrushing storm.
The future comes hungry, for man and machine.
It will catch me I expect, catch us all.
So enough hunts, enough visions.
I'll run, chase that teasing sun to the Forbidden West.
I–I don't understand, I mean not that I ever understand, but…
Are you saying we should fear what's coming?
Ohhh yes! Jungle on fire!
Machine blue light dying out in the eddies of ashes.
You, fallen, pale as snow-flash, eyes staring open.
The Metal World, but not the one I sought.
The future is a frightful dream, huntress.
My name is Aloy.
I grew fond of you, your curiosities and disbeliefs, Aloy.
If you weather this storm, look for me.
I'd like that.
Where? In the west? In the storm?
In dreams, yes.
Those machines are alert.
They're scanning for me.
Handy.
Stocking up.
Let's see you catch us!
Always watching.
It'd be fascinating, if they weren't looking for me.
Those clamps have the armour locked in place.
Maybe there's a way to power up the mechanism, release the clamps?
Only two more.
Just one more.
There we go, the last one.
All powered up. Now to get the dials in position.
These numbers, they must be related to segments of a circle.
Did it.
Let's have a look at that armour inside.
Alright, now let's see what we can do with this material.
Save that for later.
Hi Rost.
A lot has happened.
So I… I went inside the mountain.
Do you remember the night before the Proving?
The final lesson you taught me?
You said I needed to serve a purpose bigger than myself.
Well, it couldn't get much bigger.
It's the same purpose that drove Elisabet and Gaia.
One they were willing to die for.
So yeah, I'll do it.
Give myself to that, for Elisabet, and Gaia, and for you.
I've got what I need to destroy Hades.
The master override.
Now all I have to do is drive it into Hades' skull, so no problem there.
The final battle will be fought at Meridian.
Hades will come for the Spire and I'll be ready.
I found out how Elisabet died.
She sacrificed herself, as you might expect.
Said something about going home.
I wonder where that was for her.
If I ever find out, I'd like to go there, see it myself.
Assuming I actually survive the battle at Meridian, of course.
Which, let's face it, is… well, who knows?
Well, I'll um, try to come back if I can, but…
I guess this…
This might be it.
Thank you, Rost.
Thank you for everything.
Now they're hunting me.
Getting soaked from melted snow.
Low and quiet does it.