SYLENS: When I found Hades,
the first thing it wanted to know about was the Spire.
SYLENS: Not Meridian, the Spire.
Now why would that be?
The Spire was created by Gaia.
Which part of Gaia?
Minerva, its code breaking module.
Gaia built spires to transmit the codes that deactivated the Faro robots.
Shut down their biomatter conversion systems.
Hades wants to send a new transmission!
To wake the machines so they can devour the world all over again!
Yes, based on what we've learned, that's my conclusion as well.
So the Eclipse, the robots they've resurrected, they're just a means to an end.
An army to capture the Spire!
Yes, so Hades can exterminate life all over again.
No more ammo, this isn't good.
Look at this!
GUARD: Don't ask me where to go if you're lost, I'm a guard not the town crier.
GUARD: Now that you've rescued Prince Itamen,
perhaps the Sun-King will end the civil war once and for all.
CARJA: Waste of time; show was better last week.
CARJA: Wish I could feel a moment like this every day—
CARJA: Eh, I've seen better.
CARJA: I've seen this four times already.
GUARD: Can't imagine living anywhere else.
GUARD: The Oseram have gone too far this time.
Dervahl should die for his crimes.
GUARD: It's always the ones you least expect that cause you trouble.
GUARD: [yawns] No, I'm awake and alert.
GUARD: Always stay bright, always stay alert, that's what I say.
Aloy!
What brings you to Meridian?
A threat.
Helis commands a legion of fanatics called the Eclipse.
They will attack soon, from the West, with an army of ancient war machines.
But that's not the worst of it.
They'll bring a mind with them.
God, demon, machine, whatever you want to call it.
It's called Hades and it doesn't want Meridian at all.
It wants the Spire.
And if it gets there, it will send out a call
waking more ancient machines, more than we could ever defeat.
All will be lost.
We can't let that happen.
I'm trying to understand, but my responsibility lies with Meridian.
Meridian isn't the target Avad.
You have to defend the Spire.
Perhaps the Vanguard, Your Radiance.
Yes, send them to the Spire.
Erend knows Aloy, he won't question it.
And have the city guard fortify the western ridge.
There they can be seen to protect Meridian and the Alight where the Spire rests.
Aloy, allow me to apologise for my behaviour before.
After everything that happened with Ersa, I was confused.
If we're to fight together on the brink of life and death,
I'd prefer to do so with your forgiveness.
Then you have it.
As long as you don't confuse me with her again.
Even a king can learn his lesson.
Good then, I'm glad that's behind us.
Now, it will take time to prepare our defences.
Please tell me what you know of our enemies, everything.
I don't know about everything, but I'll tell you what I can.
Have you spoken to blameless Marad?
Not yet, but I will.
He wishes to speak to you, defensive preparations are his responsibility.
MARAD: Quietly does it.
MARAD: Panic in the city will only create another enemy.
MARAD: And do keep me appraised of each new arrival.
Ah, Aloy.
Preparations are underway on the ridge of defences and at the Spire.
Word was sent to every corner of the Sundom.
Our allies offered their steel.
Some came for Meridian, others for shards.
But many came for you, by name.
For me?
Don't be so humble.
I suppose all we can do is wait for the attack.
Exactly, it's not a feeling I cherish, but our spotters
at Evening Sign report there's still no movement in the west.
The ridge will be the front line, that's where the city guard are holding?
Yes, bolstered by some of the irregulars.
The Oseram cannons that thundered Meridians walls in the liberation will now defend us.
You're welcome to tour the defences.
And the Spire, Erend and the Vanguard are there?
Indeed, clashing breastplates together
and testing out their battle cries I suppose.
A number of the Nora have also arrived at the Spire.
They have resisted the offer of a royal audience.
Perhaps you could parley with them?
I will.
So, if there's more you need to do elsewhere sieze this time to do it.
Otherwise, I've made the apartment of Olin Delverson available to you.
You can sleep there, if sleep comes.
GUARD: Has the enemy reached the main gate?
GUARD: Gather bows and spears, don't let them take the city without a fight.
MERCHANT: Could you spare a moment to speak of the finer things?
MERCHANT: These aren't goods, they're necessities!
CARJA: Don't watch, hide!
OSERAM: Here's to Avad, eh? He may dress like a—
GUARD: By the Sun, a woman now leads the Hunters Lodge.
What's next? A woman as king?
VANASHA: Have you just polished that armour, Uthid?
UTHID: Of course.
VANASHA: Isn't that a little…?
UTHID: What?
VANASHA: Nothing.
UTHID: Out with a woman.
VANASHA: Forget I said anything, you look very dignified.
UTHID: Thank you.
VANASHA: And shiny. Very shiny.
Aloy! I told you I'd be here.
You did Teb, but have your wounds even had time to heal?
Honestly, if I fought, I'd probably come undone.
But don't worry, I'll leave that to the other Nora at the Spire.
I brought supplies instead.
These Carja have made me "an honorary quartermaster", whatever that means.
It sounds impressive!
I could get used to it.
We'll be setting up caches of arms and medicine under these banners.
Look for them when the fighting starts.
Aloy?
When you went into the mountain, did the Goddess tell you our chances?
She didn't need to, I know we can do this, Teb.
Maybe we can.
TEB: This place, really couldn't be more different to the Sacred Land could it?
GUARD: We all have our place in the order of things.
TEB: There are materials like I've never seen in the markets above.
TEB: I tried to explain Stitchers and Makers to these Carja.
You'd think that wouldn't take much explaining.
Little Huntress, you called so here I am.
Ready to fight?
Fight?
I thought you just wanted tea and conversation.
Is there a battle coming, I wasn't informed.
Well, that can't be true, you're always informed.
Oh, so I am.
We've only met a few times and yet you know me so well.
I don't think I know you at all, but I'd like to.
Hmm, when I hear that line it usually means something else.
Can I tell you a secret?
Of course.
I've been waiting for this fight my whole life.
The enemy we face today is the same that turned Meridian
into a slave pit and Sunfall into a blood bath.
Fanatics who torture and murder mothers, fathers,
families, children, and say it's the will of the Sun.
I hate them, Aloy.
I've got the scars of their whips on my back to prove it.
And today we can get rid of them once and for all.
I said I came for you, but that was only half the truth.
I came for them.
This time they're not getting away.
I'm with you, Vanasha. We'll fight them together.
And I won't forget it, little Huntress.
Tomorrow may the Sun rise on a better world.
VANASHA: I only fight when I have to, but by the time I have to, I usually want to.
VANASHA: I've put something special on the tips of my arrows for the Eclipse.
VANASHA: It's too bad Bahavas isn't here to see his little friends crushed.
Aloy.
Um, at ease, Uthid.
Meridian will be glad to have you on its side, and I am too.
The honour is mine.
You saved my epitaph from being "A fine soldier but a fool of a man".
I'm hoping you won't need any kind of epitaph just yet.
As the Sun wills.
When you found me, I was trying to eke out a glorious death.
But now a glorious life seems more preferable.
To watch Itamen playing the low gardens again…
…still surrounded by a dozen guards, but…
What you did Aloy, it was done well.
Although I can't shake this rogue, Vanasha.
She delights in goading me, like brazen colours waved before a Behemoth.
Do you want me to ask her to stop?
No, I accept it.
Well then, Meridian shall stand and shadows shall fall, I swear it.
Here's to that, Uthid.
UTHID: The Sun is my armour, this other armour I wear is a safeguard.
UTHID: Always for a Sun-King, always for Meridian.
UTHID: Every battle we hope to make the last, for the other side.
VANASHA: How many men do you think you'll kill in the battle, Uthid?
UTHID: As many as I have to.
VANASHA: I love it when you say things like that, it's so…
UTHID: What?!
VANASHA: Cheerful!
UTHID: Grrr.
Elida, I'm pleased to see you, but what are you doing here?
I'm helping prepare for the battle.
If Atral were here, we would have fought together, I know it.
So I'm doing everything I can.
Digging battlements, collecting herbs, anything that makes a difference.
I can't take his place, nothing can take his place.
But I'm here for him, for both of us.
I understand what it was he saw in you.
He'll always be with me.
Sun and shadow still meet for a moment, every dawn and dusk.
I should give you this, to help in the battle.
By the Sun, I hope you don't need it.
Thank you, Elida. Be safe.
ELIDA: Father understood that I couldn't just stand by in my garden.
ELIDA: Maybe this battle can finally end the war between the Carja.
ELIDA: I should finish up here before the fighting starts.
VANASHA: That's a nice spear, Uthid.
UTHID: Thank you.
VANASHA: I like the way you grip it.
UTHID: Enough, woman.
Nakoa, you came to fight.
How could I not?
During the Red Raids, there was only one
Carja butcher the Nora feared more than Zaid.
Helis.
I would stand against any army he leads, no matter how strong.
For the Nora he terrorised, for myself, and for my father.
We'll stop him, you have my word.
Your word means a lot, especially now.
Because of you, I hear the Sacred Land is opened.
If we win, I can go home.
It'll be good to see Yan again.
I'm with you, Aloy, until the end.
NAKOA: Like you said, we'll stop Helis cold, together.
NAKOA: I hear they call you "the anointed" now.
NAKOA: The Matriarchs and their rituals!
NAKOA: Yan's probably eating it up.
NAKOA: It's strange to fight alongside the Carja, but I guess they're like any tribe.
NAKOA: Some kind, some vicious.
Janeva, they called you back to duty?
So you're the one behind all this commotion.
Who made Sun-King Avad finally show his sword arm from behind those robes.
A king can be fierce and fair, Janeva, he's a good man.
A smart man too.
He had Marad offer all my prisoners a royal pardon if they'd fight for Meridian.
The whole motley lot of them agreed.
Didn't take much convincing.
With your kind of convincing, I don't doubt it.
Ha! This time I went easy on them.
Those who commit the crime of attacking Meridian,
they'll see less of my lenient side.
May the Sun blaze at your back, Aloy.
JANEVA: Can't fault my prisoners' discipline.
JANEVA: All those dawn drills have served them well.
JANEVA: After it's all over I might be
the only one going back to the rock, how'd you like that?
JANEVA: I've waited two years for this war to break, I can wait a little longer.
GUARD 1: Isn't that him, from the battle of the Daunt?
GUARD 2: Can't be. Cinnabar Sands was before that, and there were no survivors.
NIL: Well, I don't like to boast…
GUARD 1: O Sun, keep the shadow from falling upon me.
NIL: Killed anyone lately you'd like to talk about?
Nil?!
Aloy, they told me your name.
I said "hair like a splash of blood, tenacious as a Scrapper's jaws".
I've thought about what you said.
Every time the wound you gave me caught in my ribs.
But I didn't wound you.
Not by metal, still, I forgive.
A duel is such a fleeting joy.
If one of us had ended the other, we'd have missed all this.
The wait before blood is shed, like the scrape of a blade across your teeth.
Nil, you're making it difficult to be glad to see you.
But you're needed, the battle will be hard.
Hard? I was assured the odds would be near impossible.
And you signed up anyway?
Impossible odds, fine company, killing without consequence, how could I resist?
NIL: I don't care for fighting machines,
but I hear these ones are demons, that's exciting.
NIL: Trouble with a battle is it can be hard to find killing to call your own.
ALOY: Petra!
Here she is, the guest of honour!
I knew there was something about you.
Hammered from the stuff they make leaders out of.
And I don't say that to every Nora girl who blows through my town.
That happens to you a lot?
Ha! Had to build a wall to fend them off.
Good thing I'm persistent then.
Ha, I've missed our little talks.
Marad asked me to look over the city arsenal.
These guns have aged well.
That runs in the Oseram, no?
They were the pride of the Mainspring forges.
So I've taken greater pride in improving them.
Can I try one?
Everybody wants a turn, have at it then!
The targets should put up a little less of a fight than those bandit raiders did.
PETRA: Range is good, try the next.
PETRA: With these, I think we could hold off an army.
PETRA: See? That'll knock a machine on it's ass, ancient or no.
PETRA: No need to aim it like a bow.
You know that I appreciate your help, Petra.
This battle, I…
I don't know what's gonna happen.
We'll see each other again, I know it.
Next time could be the time I'll convince you to stick with the Free Heap.
Petra, you know I c—
PETRA: I don't make weapons for a living, it's more of a diversion.
PETRA: The city always ground my gears but I'd miss it if it were gone.
PETRA: You take care, of yourself and the cannons.
ALOY: Aratak?
I didn't expect you to come all this way.
It's true I am a stranger in this green and snowless land.
Ourea forgave the Carja, but I never did.
Still, I was compelled to come for my once chieftain.
It's good to see you leading again.
ARATAK: This one, of no werak, he may have taken too many blows to the head.
ARATAK: But he's a good fighter and strong.
ARATAK: This young icehunter seeks to prove herself also.
ARATAK: Her spark reminds me of Ourea's in our youth.
And I'm proud to take my place behind you on this hunt.
A great challenge.
Survive and prevail, right?
There is no other way.
ARATAK: Did we not fight back machine demons before?
ARATAK: You, my sister, and I?
ARATAK: The battle looms, but every day brings a fresh battle.
ARATAK: CYAN says she could not predict the outcome.
ARATAK: If she had, I would have chosen not to hear it.
Have you come to defend my honour, Inatut?
I know you don't need any help with that,
but from all I've heard you've found yourself a good fight here.
So I'll stand this ground with you.
You won't have ever seen a fight like this.
And we only get one shot at it.
I've been told I'm in over my head before, Nora girl.
You know what I say?
I'm always in over my head.
INATUT: That icehunter doesn't talk much, except to herself.
INATUT: I'm ready! You wanna punch my guts to see how ready I am? No?
INATUT: I choose my own battles now, and I choose this one.
You are the hunter from the Banuk grove.
I remember you also, Nora.
The machines shook free of their slumber after you arrived, raged and fought.
Uh, well, that–that wasn't my fault.
No, I'm thanking you!
That night I decided I would not go back to Ban-Ur.
I would take my hunt into these lands.
So many machines, even demons,
spidery, skittering, without the blue light in them.
Dead things that must be killed again.
Our enemy's dug up an army of them.
An army? Yes! That's why I came.
Good, I'll wait.
ALUKI: From their metal bones I'll make my armour and my song.
ALUKI: My spear is sharp, my will is like the oldest ice.
ALUKI: If I live, or die, they'll call my name down glacier cracks.
Talanah, why are you here?
I'm your Hawk, where else would I be?
Defending Meridian with Avad?
I leave that to the rest of the Lodge.
I will not stand aside while one of mine fights alone.
Not again.
Are you sure, you—
You're risking your life for all of us.
You can't ask me to stand by and watch.
Not when I have the power to change it.
Then I won't ask you.
It's settled, I will fight by your side.
My only request…
Name it.
Leave the biggest machine for me.
No promises.
TALANAH: When you need me, I'll follow your lead.
TALANAH: I came prepared, I have arrows enough to take down five armies.
TALANAH: Hawk and Thrush ready for the battle to start.
BRAVE 1: It rises taller than the highest tree.
BRAVE 2: These Carja in their frilled armour look like turkeys.
BRAVE 3: But there are so many, and now we are so few.
BRAVE 1: They are not our foe, not this time.
SONA: Quiet now, she comes.
BRAVE 3: The Anointed!
ALOY: War Chief Sona.
War Chief, you… you seem uncomfortable.
The Nora do not belong here, I do not belong here.
I will fight the Metal Devil that threatens us all
but my place is in the Sacred Land.
The wrongness here jags at me like an arrowhead.
I'm sorry to put you through this.
Do not be sorry.
This will be ended. My spear, my word.
SONA: The Carja do not impress me.
SONA: To build so tall is to invite the fate of the ancients.
SONA: We will stand tall for we are the strength of the Nora!
SONA: Your fight is ours, you know it to be so.
NAMMAN: O Great Sun, how does your gaze fall?
NAMMAN: In approval or reproach?
NAMMAN: Turn our heads with your daily pilgrimage,
from the east where we came, to the west where only you may go.
NAMMAN: You grant cold metal the warmth of life
and let the machines bask in Your great shining.
NAMMAN: For You the shadows shrink and part
and gather again only at Your allowance, without form.
NAMMAN: Your eyes the day,
your ears the priests, your lips the Radiant Sun-King.
NAMMAN: As there was before and will be again, Your Light.
ALOY: Namman.
I should have known if there was gonna be a Sun Priest here it would be you.
And if the Sun-King had allowed outlanders
to set foot upon the Alight, this "Aloy" could only be you.
I wish the circumstances were different,
or that the Psalms of the Sun could give you peace of mind.
But if you allow me one pontification…?
Go ahead.
You've shown strength and compassion, our enemies only a desperate hate.
Both sides claim the blessing of the Sun, but the Sun that I pray to?
He would bestow it upon yours.
You know, Namman, I'm already under
some pretty heavy divine pressure, but I'll try to live up to it.
The tribes united against shadow, how could that not be the Sun's will?
NAMMAN: From what I could gather
the Nora believe their Goddess chose them for a fated battle.
BRAVE: It is an honour.
VARL: Greetings, Aloy.
Don't.
You don't need to bow, The Anointed doesn't like it.
She doesn't much like being called anointed either.
It means a lot to have you here, Varl.
I gave my word.
So, Meridian, what do you think?
I've seen many new things since I first met you.
I should thank you.
Varl, what's wrong?
You really want to know?
Alright.
I'm in a foreign land, a tainted land, defending a faithless city
that looks like nothing I've seen, from something I can't imagine.
And you, after all that's happened, all you've done…
I feel like I should drop to my knees and worship you.
But I know you don't want that.
Boy, things are pretty tough for you, huh?
Thanks for telling the other Nora not to bow.
It's the last thing I need.
[laughs] Don't be too hard on them.
They only joined this fight because The Anointed bid it so.
Is that why you came?
No.
I would have come just to see you one more time.
And we must fight a Metal Devil because the Goddess says, or because you say.
I think the Goddess and I are in agreement, we're both glad you're here.
So am I.
VARL: Your friend, the Vanguard keeps looking over.
VARL: Up here I'm not sure if the world has grown bigger, or I've grown smaller.
VARL: I apologise for the War Chief, she is hating this.
VANGUARD 2: So who are these guys?
EREND: They call themselves the Eclipse.
VANGUARD 2: What does that even mean?
EREND: It's when the moon gets in front of the sun, idiot.
VANGUARD 2: Is that supposed to sound scary or something?
VANGUARD 1: I don't know, they used to be Carja.
VANGUARD 1: Carja are always yammering about sun and shade.
VANGUARD 2: Well, if they used to be Carja, how tough can they be?
VANGUARD 3: Yeah, their best guys dress like birds.
We'll rip their little feathers off.
EREND: Let's not get cocky, boys.
EREND: Aloy, so here we are again, gearing up for a fight.
Only this time it sounds like the bad guys have a lot more firepower.
What are we up against, really?
I'm not sure, but there's gonna be a lot of them and they'll have machines.
And if they get past us, it's not just Meridian that will fall.
The rest of the world will go with it.
That's … big.
It sounds like our kind of fight, right guys?
Where do they put the Vanguard?
At the front of the line!
And why?
Steel before iron!
And what are we gonna do?
Hit 'em like a hammer 'til they can't hit back!
Damn right!
You hear that?
Nobody's getting past the Vanguard.
We're here from Meridian.
And we're here for you.
Thank you, Erend.
Ersa would be proud.
Only if we win.
VANGUARD 2: We gonna fight soon? I'm getting hungry.
VANGUARD 1: You're always hungry.
EREND: Feasts on me after we win.
VANGUARD 2: Beer too?
EREND: Beer too.
EREND: You just can't leave me alone, can you?
VANGUARD 2: I think she likes you.
VANGUARD 1: You gonna kiss her, Captain?
EREND: Shut up! Now!
EREND: We'll just pretend that never happened.
GUARD: —day, citizen.
GUARD: Don't ask me where to go if you're lost, I'm a guard, not the town crier.
CARJA: —not let Meridian fall without a fight.
CARJA: Rally Carja! Do not let Meridian fall!
OSERAM: Tell you what I like, the sound of a hammer on steel.
[singing from the Sun Ring]
GUARD: Get to cover, let the soldiers do their jobs.
MERCHANT: Fine goods for a fair price.
[singing from the Sun Ring]
MERCHANT: Check out these wares!
MERCHANT: Fine goods for a fair price.
[singing from the Sun Ring]
GUARD: Get to safety, the battle begins.
CARJA: Who leads the attack? Is it Helis? Damn him, and the Carja in Shadow!
[singing from the Sun Ring]
ALOY: Olin's apartment.
ALOY: Feels … empty.
ALOY: Should I sleep?
ALOY: Did I leave anything unfinished?
How could you sleep Elisabet, with a weight like this pressing on you?
How did you Rost, after you lost your family?
Sylens? Are you there?
Guess I shouldn't ask ghosts for advice.