My name is Desmond Miles.
I'm a prisoner of war.
A war I never knew existed.
Waged by two groups I never thought were real, Templars and Assassins.
The Animus showed me the truth.
The things I've seen, the things I've been.
A thousand years of history flowing
through my veins brought to life by this machine.
They're using using it, using me to search for something.
They call it The Apple.
It's an artefact, one of many so called Pieces of Eden.
Templars collect them, it's how they stay in power.
And if the Templars get their hands on another one everything will change.
They want to make us all their slaves.
When they first brought me here,
I was afraid of what would happen if I tried to fight back.
Now?
Now I'm afraid of what will happen if I don't.
But I can't do it alone.
And maybe I don't have to.
I met someone.
Her name is Lucy.
I think she's on my side.
She's gone now.
Taken away by that bastard Warren Vidic and his Templar masters.
I don't know what will happen to her.
Or what will happen to me.
All I know is I need to get out of here, and I need to do it soon.
My name is Desmond Miles and this is my story.
We have to go.
Lucy, where have you been? Why did they–
Now!
LUCY: Desmond.
Get in.
What's with the blood? Are you okay?
Look, we have maybe ten minutes, maybe, before they figure out what I've done.
If we're not out of here and on the road before, then…
Wait, we're leaving?
Desmond, I promise I'll answer all of your questions later.
But right now, I need you to just shut up and do what I say.
So please, get in the Animus.
Alright.
LUCY: Hurry up!
AAAH! [pants]
Spingi (Push)! Spingi!
Di nuovo (Again)!
AAAAH!
NURSE: Si, si, brava (Yes, yes, good)!
It is a boy.
Oh my love! My dispiace (I'm sorry)!
I was at the bank when they told me.
Did I miss it? Am I too late?
Give him here.
Giovanni…
GIOVANNI: Ssh my love, it will be alright.
Tu sei un Auditore (You are an Auditore).
Sei un combettente (You are a fighter).
Perciò combatti (So fight)!
Listen to him! A fine set of lungs!
What shall we call him, my love?
Ezio. Ezio Auditore da Firenze!
Get up, let's go.
Yeah, well, I'm gonna need a second.
There isn't time Desmond, we have to leave.
LUCY: Come on, Desmond!
DESMOND: Ah, really getting out of here, huh?
LUCY: Stay close.
DESMOND: Nice walls, fancy.
LUCY: We need to move!
DESMOND: Coming, I'm coming!
GUARD 1: Hey! You're not supposed to be up here!
GUARD 1: Open this door!
GUARD 2: I'm calling it in.
GUARD 2: We have a breach in the research wing.
DESMOND: Wait up!
GUARD 2: I repeat, there's been a breach in the research wing.
LUCY: Desmond, over here.
GUARD 2: Requesting backup from all available security personnel.
GUARD 2: Subjects appear to be armed.
LUCY: Hurry up!
GUARD: There they are, don't let them get away!
DESMOND: Holy shit!
LUCY: Come on, we need to keep moving.
DESMOND: Look at this place.
LUCY: Come on Desmond, let's go.
DESMOND: What about the cameras?
LUCY: I rigged them to loop old footage.
LUCY: How do you think I managed to hide all your
night time snooping from Abstergo?
DESMOND: You're good.
LUCY: So I've been told.
LUCY: But they're onto us now.
LUCY: We need to hurry.
LUCY: Careful.
LUCY: We need to get to that elevator on the other side of the room.
LUCY: Follow my lead, but keep an eye out for security.
LUCY: I'd rather avoid a fight.
DESMOND: Boy, these must be a bitch to clean.
LUCY: Do you want us to get caught?
DESMOND: Is that an Animus?
LUCY: Stay close.
DESMOND: What the…?!
DESMOND: How many of them are there?
LUCY: Stay close.
DESMOND: Is it Animuses or Animii?
LUCY: Stay back!
DESMOND: What do you think, Lucy? Lucy?!
DESMOND: What do they need with all of them?
LUCY: Desmond, shut the fuck up. Please.
Fuck! I thought this card would work.
It must be on a separate system, and I don't have the code.
Wait.
DESMOND: Shit!
DESMOND: Come on!
How did you do that?
I don't know.
Let's go.
LUCY: It's always something.
DESMOND: What was that in the Animus?
DESMOND: Subject 16?
DESMOND: Ezio Audi… Audisomething.
LUCY: I think we've been wrong all along.
LUCY: That's why we need to get out of here.
LUCY: Vidic and the Templars, they're only part of the problem.
DESMOND: What do you mean?
LUCY: I'll explain when we get there.
DESMOND: Get where?
Get in.
You're joking.
It's for your own protection.
DESMOND: Oh man.
We're almost there.
DESMOND: Thanks for that, it was great.
DESMOND: Being shoved in the trunk, bouncing around. Loved it.
LUCY: This way.
DESMOND: So, gonna tell me what's going on now?
LUCY: There was a reason for the escape, Desmond.
DESMOND: Figures.
LUCY: We need your help.
DESMOND: For what? Another treasure hunt through time?
LUCY: Abstergo's gonna replace their Apple of Eden.
LUCY: The map your ancestor found guarantees it.
LUCY: The other Assassins they'll do what they can where they can, but…
DESMOND: What? What is it?
LUCY: We're losing this war, Desmond.
LUCY: The Templars are too powerful, and every day more of us die.
DESMOND: I still don't see how I fit into things.
LUCY: We're going to train you, turn you into one of us.
DESMOND: What?
DESMOND: No, no, you've seen me in action. I'm no good at this.
DESMOND: And even if I was, it would take months, years even.
LUCY: No, not with the Animus, not with the bleeding effect.
DESMOND: But I'm just one guy.
LUCY: Sometimes that's all you need.
DESMOND: So that's why you found him, my ancestor.
DESMOND: What was his name? Ezio?
LUCY: If you can follow in his footsteps,
you'll learn everything he did, just like he did.
LUCY: Years of training absorbed in a matter of days.
DESMOND: You broke me out of Abstergo
and brought me here just to make me an Assassin?
Look, there's more to it than that, but it'll have to wait.
Trust me, okay?
Alright, I'm in. Tell me what you need.
Really? You're sure?
I thought you'd be happy about this.
Sorry, I'm just a little surprised.
I spent the whole ride over here figuring out
how I was gonna convince you to do this.
Save it.
After what those Templar bastards put me through I'm ready, willing and able.
Thank you.
Lucy! You made it.
God, it's been so long.
Seven years, can you believe it?
SHAUN: Indeed, welcome back.
SHAUN: Ah, so this must be the infamous Subject 17.
SHAUN: Desmond Miles was it?
DESMOND: Who are you?
I'm sorry, where are my manners?
I'm Shaun Hastings. This is Rebecca Crane.
Nice to meet you, Desmond.
SHAUN: Right, well, it's been lovely chatting,
but if you don't mind Desmond, it's best we get straight to work.
Time is precious. Doubly so, these days.
REBECCA: We've got everything set up and ready, Lucy.
Just say the word and we'll get going.
Here, I brought you something.
A parting gift from Abstergo.
Whoa! Their memory core!
This is amazing!
With their data, things are go go a lot faster.
REBECCA: I'll get to work on merging the code.
DESMOND: Hey, listen, I just wanted to say thank you and that I'm sorry.
Sorry?
Yeah, you know, before. Everything at Abstergo.
It was just… I wasn't ready.
It's okay.
No, going through all that,
knowing that the Templars still exist, what they're planning…
What's done is done, Desmond.
You're here now and that's what matters.
Hey Desmond, what's up?
Just wondering what your role is in all this?
I take care of Baby.
It's my job to keep her up and running.
"Baby"? You mean the Animus?
Actually, I prefer Animus 2.0.
Since Baby's twice as awesome as anything you'll find at Abstergo.
The Templars might have deeper pockets than us,
but they've got no ambition, no passion, no competitive edge!
That's why even with all their resources,
anything they can do I can do better. Faster, too.
Anyway, take a seat when you're ready and we can get started.
I just need to make a few more adjustments.
DESMOND: What's all this stuff for?
"This stuff" Desmond?
Oh "this stuff" is nothing special, really.
"This stuff" is just the "stuff" that keeps
our entire operation from falling apart, really.
It requires a great deal of concentration to keep it all moving.
So you'll forgive me if I don't have time to play meet and greet.
REBECCA: Shaun's in charge of maintaining our knowledge archives.
REBECCA: It's like a digital library.
He'll be riding shotgun with me while you're in the Animus.
So if you come across anything of note people, places, events, et cetera.
He'll create database entries you can consult for additional information.
SHAUN: Yeah, it's not just databases, though.
SHAUN: I also provide tactical support for the other Assassins.
You know Desmond, the ones who are out there
actually doing stuff, risking their lives, little things like that.
Lucy, I've been seeing things.
Symbols in my bedroom, the code on the keypad, just like Altaïr.
It's from the bleeding effect.
You're taking on more than your ancestor's memories.
You're taking on their skills too.
In this case, Eagle Vision.
Skills?
LUCY: You're more receptive now.
So if all goes well, everything Ezio learns in the Animus, you'll learn too.
You really think this will work? That I'll become an Assassin?
LUCY: You already are an Assassin.
You'll just be better at it.
SHAUN: Yeah, hopefully much better at it.
SHAUN: I mean, seriously, I saw the tapes from Abstergo.
SHAUN: You didn't even try an escape.
DESMOND: What a dick.
LUCY: Sorry Desmond, I've got some stuff to take care of. We can talk more later.
So how does this work?
DESMOND: Of course.
Deep breath.
Aaah!
SHAUN: Oh what are you, a tiny child?
Shaun!
DESMOND: Well!
REBECCA: Here we go.
Insieme per la vittoria (We stand together for victory)!
CROWD: Insieme! Insieme!
Silenzio (silence), my friends, silenzio!
Grazie (Thank you).
Do you know what brings us here tonight?
Honour.
Vieri de' Pazzi slanders my family's name
and forces his own miseries upon us. If we—
VIERI: Enough of your nonsense, grullo (idiot)!
Buona sera (good evening) Vieri. We were just talking about you.
I'm surprised to see you here.
I thought the Pazzi hired others to do their dirty work.
It's your family that cries for guards when there's trouble, codardo (coward)!
Afraid to handle things yourself?
Your sister seemed quite satisfied with the handling I gave her earlier.
Uccidetelo (Kill him)!
Ehi (Hey)! Behind you!
Federico! What are you doing here?
I wanted to see if baby brother had finally learned how to fight.
And?
Heh, you have style. But endurance is what counts.
Let's see how many of them you can ruin before they get the best of you.
Fall back! Fall back!
Hold on.
What? We've almost won this!
FEDERICO: Your lip.
Just a scratch.
Let the doctor decide.
It's not necessary.
Besides, I have no money for this doctor of yours.
Heh, wasted it on women and wine, uh?
I'd hardly call it wasted.
Lend me some florins then. Or have you done the same?
[laughs]
Search them, there's bound to be something in their pockets.
Va bene (Alright). That should be enough.
Let's get out of here before the guards arrive.
Hurry Ezio, the sooner we're done with the doctor, the sooner we can sleep.
DOCTOR: Do you require medical assistance?
FEDERICO: Ben trovato (Good to see you), doctor.
DOCTOR: Mmm, fratelli Auditore (Auditore brothers).
DOCTOR: Why am I not surprised?
DOCTOR: You made quite a mess of yourself, young man.
EZIO: It's nothing, really.
You must help him, that pretty face is his only asset.
Fottiti (Go fuck yourself)!
DOCTOR: There we are, now get out of here.
EZIO: Grazie.
FEDERICO: This way.
FEDERICO: Quite a night.
EZIO: Indeed. I only wish they were all as much fun.
EZIO: Oh, wait, they are!
[laughter]
FEDERICO: We should head home, Ezio.
FEDERICO: Father's sure to be wondering where we've gone.
EZIO: Yes, and I'd rather avoid a lecture.
FEDERICO: Up for a little race then?
EZIO: To where?
FEDERICO: Uhh... roof of that church.
FEDERICO: On the count of three. Uno. Due. Tre!
FEDERICO: Baby brother still has much to learn.
FEDERICO: Come on, tartaruga (turtle)!
FEDERICO: Come on, tartaruga!
Come on, then. This way.
Where are you going?
FEDERICO: You'll see.
FEDERICO: It is a good life we lead, brother.
EZIO: The best. May it never change.
FEDERICO: And may it never change us.
Alright, enough of that. We really should head home. Let's go.
Wait.
What?
Ezio, let Cristina sleep.
There will be time enough for that… later.
Ehhh.
Cazzo (Fuck), it's Vieri, I'd better hide.
Keep looking! He couldn't have gotten far!
EZIO: Cristina! Cristina!
CRISTINA: Who's there?
EZIO: Me.
Oh, Ezio, I should have known.
EZIO: May I come in?
CRISTINA: Fine, but only for a minute.
EZIO: A minute is all I need.
CRISTINA: Indeed.
EZIO: W–wait, that came out wrong.
Come here.
Oh.
Oh Ezio.
Oh Ezio!
ANTONIO: Christina! Christina!
ANTONIO: Sveglia (Wake up)! Your tutor will be here soon!
ANTONIO: Come, my daughter... Is it really so terrible tha–
ANTONIO: Figlio d'un cane (Son of a bitch)! What is this?!
EZIO: Perdonate, Messere (Forgive me sir)! Chiedo venia (I beg your pardon)!
I'll kill you!
Now, now, that's not necessary.
ANTONIO: Guards! Guards! Voglio la sua testa (Bring me his head)!
EZIO: There's really no need for violence.
EZIO: You have me confused with someone else.
EZIO: She needed some help with… some things.
EZIO: I'm mostly innocent.
EZIO: Good morning, Father.
Come with me.
EZIO: Is something wrong?
Do you think me blind and deaf, son?
I know all about your fight with Vieri de' Pazzi last night.
And then this little visit to Cristina.
GIOVANNI: Your behaviour is unacceptable.
It…
It reminds me of myself when I was your age!
GIOVANNI: I assume these misadventures won't interfere with your work today?
No, padre (father). Avete la mia parola (You have my word).
I've prepared some documents here for Lorenzo de' Medici to review.
I need them delivered to him.
With haste, father.
Return to me when it's done.
BOETIO: Ah, Ezio, ben trovato (well met)! How are you?
EZIO:Come sempre (Same as ever). I have a letter for Messer Lorenzo.
BOETIO: I'll see that he receives it when he returns.
EZIO: Returns?
BOETIO: They've gone to Villa Careggi, I'm afraid.
And not expected back for at least another day.
EZIO: I'll let my father know.
FEDERICO: Keep up the good work.
EZIO: Bischero (Penis)!
INSIDE: You worry too much, Giovanni.
INSIDE: Francesco de' Pazzi is in prison.
INSIDE: The threat is ended.
Ah, hello son.
You remember my friend Uberto?
Good morning, Gonfalonieri Alberti.
To you as well, young man.
I trust you delivered the message.
Si, padre (Yes, father), but it seems Lorenzo is out of town.
Hmm, I did not anticipate this.
UBERTO: What does it matter?
So you wait another day or two.
Listen, your mother and sister have been looking for you.
I'll need you again in a little while.
But for now, see if you can't help them.
Are you sure?
Yes, now if you'll excuse us.
Good to see you Ezio.
Ehi Claudia, how are you?
Bene (Okay).
You shouldn't keep things from me.
It's Duccio.
What of him?
I think he's been unfaithful.
EZIO: Who told you this?
The other girls.
I thought they were my friends.
Harpies, you're better off without them.
I loved him.
No, Claudia, you only thought you did.
He should suffer for what he's done.
Wait here, I'll go have a word with him.
Oh Duccio! It's beautiful!
Nothing but the best for you amore mio (my love).
But what of Claudia? I thought you'd been promised to her?
Father said I could do much better than an Auditore.
Oh birbante (naughty)! Come, let us walk a bit.
Walk? I had something else in mind.
Oh Duccio!
EZIO: Ehi, lurido porco (dirty pig)!
Ezio, my friend!
Ma che ti piglia (What the hell)?!
You insult my sister parading around with this puttana (whore).
DUCCIO: W–w–w–what are you talking about?
I saw the gift you gave her, heard the things you said.
Maybe your sister shouldn't be so stingy with her virtù (virtue).
You broke her heart.
Ha! And now I'm going to break your face!
DUCCIO: You Auditores all talk big, but when it comes time for action, hah!
EZIO: You'll regret ever opening your mouth.
DUCCIO: I could have taught your sister a great many things.
EZIO: Bastardo!
DUCCIO: Basta (Stop)! Mi arrendo (I yield)!
EZIO: Stay away from my sister!
Ehi Ezio!
What are you doing out here, Petruccio? You should be in bed.
I want those feathers.
EZIO: What for?
It's a secret!
If I get them for you, will you go back inside?
Yes, I promise.
Here, as promised.
Grazie, brother.
You still haven't told me why you want these.
I will. In time.
Buon giorno (good morning), Ezio.
Buon giorno a voi, madre (Good morning to you, mother).
Come state (How are you)?
Sto bene (I'm good), and you?
MARIA: Still recovering from last night?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Of course not.
Anyway, I have an errand to run.
I'd like you to join.
Con piacere (With pleasure).
Come, it's not far from here.
MARIA: I know about your fight with Vieri.
EZIO: What fight?
MARIA: Per piacere (please), let's not play this game.
EZIO: He spoke ill of us.
EZIO: I could not allow him to continue.
MARIA: I'm sure he's having a hard time
dealing with the accusations against his father.
MARIA: Francesco de' Pazzi is many things, and none of them good.
MARIA: But even I never suspected he'd be capable of murder.
EZIO: What will happen to him?
MARIA: I imagine there will be a trial.
EZIO: Will Father speak at it?
MARIA: He'll have to, he's the one with the evidence.
EZIO: Still, I wish there was another way.
MARIA: You have nothing to fear.
MARIA: Everyone wants justice done.
MARIA: It is an unfortunate state of affairs, but it will pass.
MARIA: Here we are.
Hello, Leonardo.
Madonna Maria!
This is my son, Ezio.
Molto onorato (I am honoured).
L'onore è mio. (The honour is mine.)
Let me go and fetch the paintings. I'll be right back.
He's very talented.
EZIO: Immagino (I guess).
Self expression is vital to understanding and enjoying life.
You should find an outlet.
I have plenty of outlets.
I meant besides vaginas.
Mother!
Back to your house, then.
Si, si.
Ezio, help Leonardo, will you?
LEONARDO: So Ezio, what do you do?
MARIA: He's been working for his father.
LEONARDO: Ah, you're to be a banker.
EZIO: For now. And you, art was it?
LEONARDO: Truth be told, it's been difficult for me to settle.
LEONARDO: Painting is nice, but I often feel like my work lacks…
LEONARDO: I don't know, a purpose, does that make sense?
LEONARDO: I'd rather contribute more practically, more directly.
LEONARDO: Architecture, perhaps, or anatomy.
LEONARDO: I'm not content merely to capture the world.
LEONARDO: I want to change it.
MARIA: Oh Leonardo, I have no doubt you'll go on to do great things.
LEONARDO: Vi ringrazio (I thank you), Madonna. That's kind of you.
MARIA: Thank you for your help, son.
MARIA: Don't let me keep you from your other duties.
LEONARDO: It was nice to meet you Ezio, I hope our paths cross again.
EZIO: Anch'io (Me too).