Ezio, come in son.
I need these packages delivered to associates of mine in the city.
I also need you to retrieve a message for me
from a pigeon coop not too far from here.
Va bene (alright), I'll get it done.
Come back here when you're finished.
There are some things we need to discuss.
And please, my son, stay out of trouble hmm?
You Giovanni's kid?
No idiota (idiot), he just happens to look exactly like the man.
Give it here.
Don't worry boy, we're not contagious.
Least I'm not.
MERCENARY: Here, over here.
EZIO: I have a delivery from—
Giovanni Auditore?
Yes.
MERCENARY: Were you followed?
EZIO: No. Why would I be followed?
Give me the package.
Tell your father that they're moving tonight. He should as well.
EZIO: Who's moving? What's going on here?
Wait, come back, explain yourself!
Father? Federico?
Oh! Ser Ezio, thank God.
What happened, where is everyone?
They took your father and brothers to the Palazzo della Signoria, to prison!
And my mother? My sister?
CLAUDIA: Ezio!
EZIO: Claudia!
EZIO: Are you all right?
CLAUDIA: Yes, but mother…
ANNETTA: She's in shock.They… when she resisted…
It's not safe here.
Is there some place you can take them?
Yes, yes! To my sister's.
Good, do that. In the meantime, I'll go see my father.
Be careful, Messer Ezio. The guards were looking for you as well.
GIOVANNI: Ezio.
Father, what's happened?
GIOVANNI: Took a bit of a beating, but I'm alright.
What of your mother and sister?
Safe now.
GIOVANNI: Annetta took them?
Yes… wait! You knew this would happen?
Not the way it did, and not this soon.
It doesn't matter now.
What do you mean, explain?
There's no time, listen closely.
Return to the house. In my office is a hidden door.
Use your talent to find it.
Beyond lies a chest, take everything you find inside.
Much of it may seem strange to you, but all of it is important.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Good.
Among the contents is a letter and with it some documents.
I need you to take these documents to Messer Uberto.
GIOVANNI: He was with me in the office this morning.
The Gonfaloniere, I remember. Now, please, tell me what's happening.
Are the Pazzi behind this? There was a note for you at the pigeon coop, it said—
GIOVANNI: Go Ezio! Go now!
Hmm, father said there was a door here.
I need to bring this to Messer Uberto.
GUARD: Traditore (Traitor)!
EZIO: Hey, what's with the swords?
EZIO: Aren't you supposed to arrest me?
GUARD: No.
EZIO: What do you want then?
GUARD: For you to die!
EZIO: Well, that's not going to happen.
EZIO: So why don't we explore other options?
GUARD: There are no other options.
Ezio Auditore? What are you doing here at this hour?
It… I don't…
Wait, child. Take a breath. Collect your thoughts.
My father and brothers have been imprisoned. I was told to bring you this.
Ah, I see now. It's a misunderstanding Ezio.
UBERTO: I'll clear everything up.
EZIO: How?
UBERTO: The documents you've given me contain evidence
of a conspiracy against your family and against the city.
I'll present these papers at their hearing in the morning and they will be released.
Thank you, signore.
Of course, my child.
Do you need a place to stay? You're more than welcome here.
No grazie. I'll meet you at the piazza.
Don't worry, Ezio. Everything is going to be fine.
UBERTO: Giovanni Auditore!
UBERTO: You and your accomplices stand accused off the crime of treason!
UBERTO: Have you any evidence to counter this charge?
Yes, the documents that were delivered to you last night!
I'm afraid I know nothing of these documents.
He's lying! I need to get closer.
In the absence of any compelling evidence to the contrary,
I am bound to pronounce you guilty.
You and your collaborators are hereby sentenced to death.
You are a traitor, Uberto, and one of them!
You may take our lives this day, but we will have yours in return! I swear!
We will—
Father!
There! Grab the boy! He's one of them.
I'll kill you for what you done!
Guards, arrest him!
Abbattetelo (Put him down).
You'd better run boy, and fast!
SHAUN: I've got a little request for you.
SHAUN: I've identified several strange markings
that I've discovered right across Renaissance Italy.
SHAUN: Now, I don't know what they're doing there,
but I want you to help me find out.
SHAUN: Rebecca has marked their general location
in the database with an eye icon.
SHAUN: And she's made them glow as well. Keep an eye out.
ANNETTA: Ser Ezio, thank God. I've been looking everywhere for you.
EZIO: I couldn't stop them Annetta.
EZIO: I tried, I swear, but there were so many guards.
ANNETTA: Please, come with me. We need to get you off the streets.
EZIO: What of my mother and sister?
ANNETTA: They're safe. I'll bring you to them.
EZIO: No, it's too dangerous for us to travel together.
EZIO: Tell me where to go and I'll meet you there.
ANNETTA: My sister's house, just north of the Duomo.
EZIO: I'm on my way.
SHAUN: There's one of the symbols. What does it mean?
SHAUN: It must be there for a reason.
SHAUN: Can you take a closer look?
SHAUN: Hey, try using eagle vision. I've got all day.
REBECCA: Wait, That–that's not possible. This can't be!
REBECCA: Hold on, that's computer code.
REBECCA: Let me compile it.
REBECCA: Oh, shit. It's an encrypted file.
SHAUN: Upload it to my computer, I'm a master at decryption.
REBECCA: I can't, it's only compatible with the Animus itself.
SHAUN: Upload it to Desmond, then… can't believe this.
Hello? This is… er they–they call me Subject 16.
Listen, I don't have much time. There's something I have to show you.
We have been lied to this whole time.
Everything we know, everything we've been brought up to believe … it's wrong.
Okay, um, I've uploaded the evidence, the file that–that–that proves it all.
But I've split it into 20 pieces and locked each with a code.
Can't be too careful.
Queen Isabella… no, not her.
Uh, er, what century is it?
Uhh, never mind.
I've hidden the code to the first file inside this programme.
Find it, find them all.
And along the way, you'll begin to see the truth.
SHAUN: What the he—? How did this get inside our Animus?
LUCY: Oh. Oh! The memory core!
LUCY: We transferred Sixteen's memory data from Abstergo into the Animus 2.0.
LUCY: He must have hacked the machine
when Vidic left him alone between sessions.
DESMOND: Hold on, wait a second.
DESMOND: The signs on the walls in Abstergo, the ones written in blood.
DESMOND: Those were clues!
DESMOND: He was telling us to look for them inside the Animus!
I think we have the wrong building.
No, no, this is it.
It is a pleasure to make your acquaintance Messer Ezio.
Annetta speaks quite highly of you, I can see why.
I appreciate the kind words Madonna.
Ti prego (Please), call me Paola.
Thank you for offering your home to my family, Paola.
It was the least I could do.
You must be tired. Perhaps you'd l—
No, grazie. I can't stay.
PAOLA: Why, where are you going?
To kill Uberto Alberti.
I understand your desire for vengeance, but the Gonfaloniere is a powerful man.
You are not a killer, Ezio.
Spare me the lecture.
But I can make you one.
And why are you going to teach me how to kill?
I'm not. I'm going to teach you how to survive. Come.
PAOLA: Discretion is paramount in my profession.
PAOLA: We must walk the streets freely, seen but unseen.
PAOLA: You too must learn to blend like us
and become one with the city's crowds.
PAOLA: My girls will show you how.
COURTESAN: We'll take good care of you.
PAOLA: Bene. Now that you've learned to blend,
I'll show you how to use it for more than just moving around.
PAOLA: Let's teach you how to steal.
PAOLA: Once you've stolen from someone Ezio, you mustn't linger.
You can go now, girls.
Aww, do we have to?
So innocent.
He's cute!
Now that you have learned how to approach the enemy,
we need to find you a suitable weapon.
What would you have me use?
Ah, but you already have the answer.
Hey, my father's blade and bracer! How did you get them?
[laughs] By using the same skills I've just taught you.
It's not exactly in working condition.
I assume you're familiar with Leonardo da Vinci?
Si, but how does a painter factor into this?
He's far more than that. Bring him the pieces, you'll see.
Before I go, one last question, if I may?
Of course.
Why have you given your aid so readily to me, a stranger?
I too know betrayal.
Oh, Ezio Auditore!
I… I didn't expect to see you again, what with all that's happened.
Ah, where are my manners? Welcome back!
Now, how can I be of service?
I was hoping you could repair something of mine.
Of course! Come! This way.
Ah, che pasticcio (Oh, what a mess)…
Tutto il santo giorno che cerco (I've spent the whole day looking for)…
Let me clear a space.
Alright, let's see it.
Fascinating.
I don't know, Ezio.
Despite its age, the construction is rather advanced.
I've never seen anything quite like it.
I'm afraid there's not much I can do without the original plans.
Mi dispiace (I'm sorry).
Wait, wait, wait!
EZIO: What are you doing?
The contents of this page are encrypted.
But if my theory is correct, based on these sketches it may very well…
It may very well what?
Please sit.
Leonardo, I—
Ssh, ssh, ssh!
Remarkable!
LEONARDO: If we transpose the letters, and then select every third…
There, it's finished!
Huh? What's finished?
The blade.
I managed to decode that parchment of yours.
It showed me exactly what to do.
Now all that's left is to remove your ring finger.
Really?
LEONARDO: I'm sorry, but this is how it must be done.
The blade is designed to ensure the commitment of whoever wields it.
Bene, do it quickly.
Haha, I was only having fun, Ezio.
Though the blade once required a sacrifice, it's been modified.
You can keep your finger.
Incredible!
Yes, it is. Tell me, do you have other pages like this?
I'm sorry, only the one.
Listen, if you ever do happen across another one of these, please bring it to me.
You have my word. And thank you for fixing this.
OUTSIDE: By order of the Florentine guard, open this door!
Ehhh, just a moment.
Wait here.
GUARD: Are you Leonardo da Vinci?
LEONARDO: Si. How may I be of service?
GUARD: I need you to answer some questions.
LEONARDO: Certainly.
What seems to be the trouble?
A witness claims to have seen you consorting with an enemy of the city.
What? Me? Consorting? Preposterous!
When was the last time you saw or spoke with Ezio Auditore?
Who?
Non fare il finto tonto (Don't play dumb with me)!
We know you were close with the family.
Perhaps this will help to clear your head.
Ready to talk?
What about now?
GUARD: Tell me what I want to know and we can end this.
LEONARDO: Grazie Ezio.
EZIO: Sorry about that.
LEONARDO: Eh, I've grown accustomed to their abuses.
EZIO: What of the body?
LEONARDO: Bring it inside and put it with the others.
EZIO: Others?
LEONARDO: The city gives them to me, for research.
LEONARDO: Over there.
LEONARDO: See? Like it never happened.
EZIO: Thank you, Leonardo.
EZIO: For everything.
LEONARDO: Any time. And remember, if you find
more of those strange pages, bring them to me.
LEONARDO: Should they contain new designs I will upgrade your blade as well.
EZIO: Of course, now I really should be getting back to Paola.
LEONARDO: Porgile i miei omaggi (Send her my regards).