You were gone for quite a while.
Leonardo likes to talk.
PAOLA: That he does, but I trust he did more than talk.
PAOLA: Impressive.
I'm rather fond of it myself.
I've given you the skills, Leonardo's given you the blade.
All that remains is the deed.
Where can I find Uberto?
According to my girls, he'll be attending
an unveiling tonight of Verrocchio's latest work.
It will be held at the Santa Croce cloister.
Watch over my mother and sister while I'm away.
Of course, Ezio, as if they were my own.
UBERTO: Again with this?
LORENZO: You have overstepped your bounds Uberto.
UBERTO: Who are you to speak of bounds?
UBERTO: You who have crowned yourself Lorenzo de Medici,
Principe of Firenze (Prince of Florence).
I've done no such thing.
Of course not, ever innocent. How convenient.
At least now we see how far your reach extends, which is to say nowhere at all.
It has proved a valuable lesson for me and my allies.
Yes, your allies the Pazzi. Is that what this is about?
Be careful with your words, Lorenzo.
You might attract the wrong sort of attention.
GUEST 1: Good evening, Gonfalionere.
UBERTO: To you as well. I trust you're enjoying yourselves?
GUEST 1: Indeed, a nice distraction from
that nasty business with the Auditore family.
UBERTO: And to think I once thought of Giovanni as a brother.
GUEST 1: Don't blame yourself.
GUEST 1: How could you have known what evils he planned?
GUEST 2: I say we strike that traitor's name from the record books.
GUEST 2: Let history forget he ever even existed.
UBERTO: Hmm, yes. If you'll excuse me for a moment.
BEATRICE: Uberto, a moment of your time?
UBERTO: Anything for you, Beatrice.
BEATRICE: So tell us, how does it feel to be a hero?
UBERTO: Please, I am no such thing.
UBERTO: As Gonfaloniere it is my duty to ensure that
the city of Firenze remains a shining beacon of justice.
UBERTO: Corruption and its ilk shall find
no purchase here so long as I am in control.
BEATRICE: You are a treasure, Uberto. I hope Lorenzo recognises that.
UBERTO: Yes, our great leader Lorenzo. [coughs]
UBERTO: I will see you ladies later.
GUEST 3: Ah, Uberto, there you are.
GUEST 3: I was just telling the others about the execution.
GUEST 4: I mean no offence, but what if they did not act alone?
UBERTO: You can rest easy, friends.
UBERTO: I am confident that this treachery
began and ended with the Auditore family.
GUEST 5: What of the other son, Ezio was it?
UBERTO: The child poses no danger. Soft hands and an even softer head.
UBERTO: He'll be caught and executed before the week is out.
GUEST 3: Don't let us keep you, Uberto. We just wanted to say hello.
GUEST 4: Evening to you, Gonfaloniere.
UBERTO: Is everything to your satisfaction?
GUEST 4: Do you even need to ask? Of course!
GUEST 5: Accept our thanks, for this evening,
and for helping to keep Firenze safe.
GUEST 5: I always had my doubts about the Auditore.
GUEST 5: Where did the family even come from?
GUEST 5: To gain such wealth and–and prestige in just a single generation.
GUEST 4: And the children, with their odd names, always making trouble.
GUEST 5: No surprise given the company that father kept.
GUEST 5: Whores and thieves I swear it.
UBERTO: Indeed, it is clear now he sought to undermine the city.
UBERTO: To overturn all we've worked so hard to build.
GUEST 5: But thanks to you, that's over now.
UBERTO: You!
SHAUN: Uberto Alberti.
SHAUN: Trusted friend of the Auditore family.
SHAUN: According to the history books this guy was a saint.
SHAUN: He prosecuted murderers, rapists, the worst criminals.
SHAUN: One of the best lawyers in Italy, he won every case.
SHAUN: In spite of the fact that he was self-taught.
SHAUN: Now, I've found a back door into the Templars' database server.
SHAUN: I've been combing it for some kind of smoking gun.
SHAUN: I found it.
SHAUN: Apparently Uberto's family was evicted by the Medici Bank.
SHAUN: Uberto's been aching for revenge ever since.
SHAUN: And the Templars promised him support.
SHAUN: Ezio's father was standing in the way.
SHAUN: And Uberto was jealous of his influence over the Florentine government.
SHAUN: Two birds with one stone, isn't it?
SHAUN: It looks like Uberto used his election
to the Signoria as his opportunity to strike.
UBERTO: You would have done the same to save the ones you love.
Yes, I would. And I have!
The Auditore are not dead!
I'm still here! Me! Ezio! Ezio Auditore!
I think it's best I leave Firenze.
PAOLA: Where will you go?
My uncle Mario owns a villa near Monteriggioni.
You're still a wanted man, Ezio.
What would you have me do, then?
I've seen posters all across the district.
Tearing them down will help the city forget your face.
No doubt the heralds also incite the public.
Bribe them and they'll speak of other things.
Or you could hunt those who bear false witness against you.
They traded dignity for coin. Their loss would not be mourned.
Do any of these things and you should be free to leave.
REBECCA: I've added a program for tracking notoriety.
REBECCA: This little meter will help you know
how far you are between notorious and incognito.
REBECCA: This will help you know if you should watch your actions.
REBECCA: It'll also tell you if your notoriety level is part of Ezio's memory or not.
Bentornato (Welcome back) Ezio. Were you successful?
Yes.
Madre (Mother)?
CLAUDIA: Ezio! Where have you been? They wouldn't let us leave.
CLAUDIA: And mother, oh!
She hasn't spoken a single word since we left the house.
CLAUDIA: Father will need to sort things out.
CLAUDIA: Where is Father, and Federico, and Petruccio? Hmm?
Something's happened.
What do you mean?
No, it's impossible!
Claudia.
CLAUDIA: No! No, no, no, no!
I did everything I could, piccina (little one).
Listen! Right now, what matters is getting us all someplace safe.
But to do that, I need you to stay focused.
Do you understand?
Good, will you watch over mother for me?
Then we are ready. Thank you again for everything.
Stay safe, Ezio, stay vigilant.
I suspect the road ahead is yet long.
EZIO: On me.
CLAUDIA: How could this have happened to us?
EZIO: I don't know.
CLAUDIA: Will we ever be back?
CLAUDIA: What will happen to our house?
EZIO: I don't know!
CLAUDIA: Were they… Were they given a proper burial?
EZIO: Yes, they were.
EZIO: We should be close.
CLAUDIA: Grazie Dio (Thank God)!
Buongiorno, Ezio.
How could you leave Firenze without saying a proper goodbye?
CLAUDIA: Ezio!
What do you want, Vieri?
VIERI: So many things.
A larger palazzo, two new steeds, a prettier bride…
Oh, and yes, your life.
VIERI: My condolences for the—
VIERI: —loss of your father and brothers.
VIERI: What will happen now that there's no one left to help you?
VIERI: I have such wonderful things in store for your mother and sister.
I grow tired of this game.
Finish him, and do not spare the women!
What's sorcery is this?
VOICE: Ha ha ha ha ha! Not sorcery, boy, skill.
Show yourself!
VOICE: As you wish.
VOICE: Here, use this!
Kill them! Kill them all!
You have my thanks.
Keep the sword, Ezio.
Do I know you from somewhere?
Don't you recognise me? It's-a-me, Mario!
Uncle Mario?!
It's been too long, nipote (nephew), far too long.
I heard what happened in Firenze, terrible.
Come, let's get you all away from here.
MARIO: So, tell me everything.
EZIO: They executed father for treason.
EZIO: Federico and Petruccio too.
EZIO: Then they came for me.
MARIO: Do you know why?
EZIO: I have no answers uncle,
only a list of names taken from a man who wished me dead.
EZIO: I still can't believe they are gone.
MARIO: Don't worry, we will make sense of this.
EZIO: I wish I shared your optimism.
MARIO: I think you will find much to like in Monteriggioni.
EZIO: I thought Monteriggioni was an enemy of Firenze?
MARIO: For now. Next year it will be its friend.
MARIO: The year after, its enemy again, and on, and on.
MARIO: I cannot keep track, so I've stopped trying.
MARIO: These are honest, hardworking people.
MARIO: Our shops may only carry simple goods,
but they're well made and dependable.
MARIO: There's a chapel here too.
MARIO: The prete (priest) seems a nice enough fellow,
but I've never been much of a believer.
MARIO: Did you know the Villa Auditore is almost 200 years old?
MARIO: It was built by my great-grandfather,
a strange man who carried all kinds of secrets.
MARIO: Keep your eyes open and you might discover a few of them yourself.
MARIO: With all the fighting that's been going on,
this place has started to get a bit rough around the edges.
MARIO: I wish I could do something about it,
but I just don't have the time or money to fix things up.
MARIO: Guess that's life, huh?
MARIO: Here we are, casa dolce casa (home sweet home).
MARIO: So what do you think?
EZIO: It's most impressive, uncle.
MARIO: She's seen better days, I suppose.
MARIO: Believe me, I'd have her shining again if only I had the time.
MARIO: Now that you have had the tour nipote, you should go and outfit yourself.
MARIO: My men in the market are expecting you.
MARIO: Return here when you're finished and we'll begin.
EZIO: "Begin"? Begin what?
MARIO: I thought you'd come here to train.
EZIO: No, uncle, I came here to escape Firenze,
and I intend to take my family further still.
MARIO: But what about your father? He'd want you to finish his work.
EZIO: What work? My father was a banker.
MARIO: Wait, he did not tell you?
EZIO: I have no idea what you're talking about.
MARIO: Ma che mi combini (What were you thinking), Giovanni?!
MARIO: Where to even begin?
MARIO: Go and fetch the gear in the market, it will give me time to think.
EZIO: But–
MARIO: But that's that. We'll talk more later.
MARIO: Some spending money should you need it.
MARIO: And if you find yourself in need of rest,
I've prepared a room for you on the top floor of the villa.
SUBJECT 16: The past, a vast web of connections
and interconnections all ruled by chance. Or is it?
EZIO: Don't worry, we're only staying here for a little while.
CLAUDIA: I don't like it here, I want to go home.
EZIO: I know.
EZIO: Salute, uncle, I did as you asked.
MARIO: And quickly too, ben fatto (well done)!
MARIO: Now let's teach you how to fight.
EZIO: No, as I said we are leaving.
Ezio! You barely held your own against Vieri.
You won't survive a week on the road.
If you want to leave, so be it.
But at least do so armed with
the skills and knowledge necessary to defend yourself.
If not for me, for your mother and sister.
EZIO: Fine.
Ottimo (Very good)!
MARIO: You can swing a sword to be sure.
MARIO: But offence alone will not carry a battle.
MARIO: You must survive long enough to strike!
MARIO: I will teach you how to dodge.
EZIO: You said my father was more than just a banker.
MARIO: Ah, no use dancing around it I suppose.
MARIO: Your father was an Assassin, Ezio.
EZIO: I told you before, my father was a paper pusher.
MARIO: No, he was born and bred to kill.
EZIO: I find this difficult to believe.
MARIO: What of the list you carry?
MARIO: Do you think it's merely a catalogue of debts?
MARIO: It holds the names of those responsible for your father's murder.
MARIO: Bene, I've taught you how to avoid your enemy's attacks.
MARIO: Now you'll learn how to turn them to your advantage.
EZIO: All this talk of Assassins and Templars.
EZIO: It reeks of fantasy.
MARIO: Like something from an old parchment
covered in arcane writing, perhaps?
EZIO: How did you know?
MARIO: You have your father's blade.
MARIO: I figured you'd have the Codex page he was holding as well.
EZIO: "Codex"?
MARIO: Si, a guide to the inner workings of the order.
MARIO: Its origin, purpose, and techniques. Our creed, if you will.
MARIO: Your father believed the Codex contained a powerful secret.
MARIO: Something that would change the world.
MARIO: Perhaps it's why they came for him.
EZIO: Assassins, Templars, Codex pages, this is a lot to take in.
MARIO: You need to open your mind, Ezio.
MARIO: Always remember: nothing is true, everything is permitted.
MARIO: You're making fine progress, Ezio.
MARIO: Today, I'm going to teach you how to position yourself in battle.
MARIO: Where you stand and how you move can make all the difference.
MARIO: Don't think I haven't seen you picking apart my library.
MARIO: I trust you believe me now?
EZIO: Yes, my father was an Assassin.
EZIO: But why the need for such secrecy?
MARIO: Are you familiar with the Templars?
MARIO: One of several knightly orders formed during the Crusades.
MARIO: History teaches they were disbanded
nearly two hundred years ago in France.
MARIO: Only they weren't.
MARIO: Merely pushed underground where they continue their nefarious work.
EZIO: What work?
MARIO: The Templars seek dominion over man.
MARIO: And we, the Assassins, are sworn to stand against them.
EZIO: Was Uberto one of them?
MARIO: Yes.
EZIO: And the other names on my father's list?
MARIO: Templars as well.
EZIO: That means Vieri…
MARIO: Just like his father, Francesco.
MARIO: Likely the entire Pazzi family.
EZIO: Ehi, it would explain many things.
Well done, nipote (nephew). You've really come into your own.
Thank you, Uncle, for all you have given me.
You're family, such is my duty and my desire.
I'm glad you had me stay.
Good, you've reconsidered leaving?
We sail for Spain in three days.
MARIO: But nipote, I have given you the skills that
you might be better prepared to strike against our enemies.
And if they find me, I will.
MARIO: You want to leave Ezio?
To throw away everything your father fought and died for?
To deny your heritage? Fine!
Come vuoi (So be it). Arrivederci e buona fortuna (Goodbye and good luck).
Uncle, wait! Why is he so upset?
How can he not be?
Vieri has been harassing us ever since you first arrived.
To be expected, I suppose given his heritage.
Uncle!
EZIO: Where is everyone?
MERCENARY: They ride for San Gimignano to slay that snake Vieri.
EZIO: I wish to join them.
MERCENARY: You'll find what you need at the stables.
CLAUDIA: Ezio, look at her. I still can't get her to talk.
CLAUDIA: She spends all day and night
in front of those feathers Petruccio used to collect.
CLAUDIA: She can't let him go, I don't know what to do.
EZIO: Don't worry, she'll come back to us, I know it.