Ezio! What are you doing here?
EZIO: Taking responsibility. Vieri troubles you because of me.
Vieri troubles us because he's a Templar, and we are Assassins.
EZIO: Either way, I wish to help.
Va bene (Alright), then listen close.
First we must find a way inside the city, though it seems Vieri expects us.
He has sealed the gates and sent his men to guard them.
Fortunately for us, the city is larger than his host.
The Southern Gate suffers for it, so this is where we'll strike, pronti (ready)?
MARIO: Alright, Ezio, here's how it is going to work.
MARIO: My men and I will distract the guards.
MARIO: Once we have engaged them,
get yourself over the wall and find a way to open the gate.
MARIO: Take these throwing knives, use them to dispatch the archers.
EZIO: I'm ready when you are.
MARIO: Then let us begin.
MARIO: All'attacco (Charge)!
MARIO: Well done, Ezio, we are in!
MARIO: This way, men!
MARIO: I want you to distract those guards,
and keep them from raising the alarm.
MARIO: Hopefully it will buy me enough time to find and silence Vieri.
EZIO: Va bene.
MARIO: Wait, nipote, take a few of my men with you just to
be safe.
MARIO: Come join me once they're dealt with.
GUARD 1: What's Vieri up to now?
GUARD 2: No-one knows, but something has him on edge.
GUARD 2: How else to explain all the patrols?
EZIO: I'll signal again when you should follow.
GUARD 3: We're meant to be soldiers.
GUARD 3: Instead he's turned us into nursemaids. And why?
GUARD 2: Shooting his mouth off again, no doubt.
GUARD 2: Angering the wrong sorts of people. And so now we pay the price.
GUARD 1: Careful, or do you want us dragged before him like Bernardo was?
GUARD 2: Poor bastard, I heard Vieri took his eyes.
GUARD 1: I'd like to keep mine, so let's end this conversation.
MERCENARY: Ezio! Your uncle's under attack and needs help! Go to him!
MARIO: Ah nipote, there you are.
MARIO: It seems my plan has hit something of a snag.
MARIO: Vieri's men ambushed us, and now we've got our hands full.
MARIO: My brothers and I will deal with these guards.
MARIO: I want you to go on ahead and root out that snake!
MARIO: See that justice is served!
SPANIARD: It's settled. Vieri, you will remain here
to coordinate the mercenari (mercenaries).
SPANIARD: Francesco will organise our forces in the city,
and send word when it's time to strike.
SPANIARD: Jacopo, your job is to calm the citizens once the deed is done.
VIERI: What about that ubriacone (drunkard) Mario?
He continues to harrass my forces, and I fear he'll discover what we intend.
He's always been trouble, just like that bastardo brother of his.
Then let me reunite them, father.
SPANIARD: There will be plenty of time
to clean up the rifiuti (trash) when we're finished.
Now, is there anything else?
SPANIARD: Muy bien (Very well). May the Father of Understanding guide you.
ALL: May the Father of Understanding guide you.
GUARD: Comandante (Commander)! Comandante!
What?
Mario Auditore has invited the city! He comes for you!
He, he, he. Then let's not keep him waiting.
VIERI: Fear not, Ezio, I'll make sure your death comes quickly.
SHAUN: Vieri de' Pazzi.
SHAUN: The youngest member
of the second most notorious Florentine banking family.
SHAUN: This kid knew how to burn right through his father's money.
SHAUN: Outside of spending sprees involving weaponry,
exotic animals, and clothes, he was fiercely competitive.
SHAUN: Vieri hosted races of all kinds.
SHAUN: Boating, horseback riding, running.
SHAUN: All of them rigged, of course.
SHAUN: And get this.
SHAUN: If through some amazing stroke of luck he ever lost,
he'd invite the winner's entire family over for a victory dinner.
SHAUN: And serve them a meal to die for.
EZIO: What are you and your allies planning?
EZIO: Is this what my father discovered?
EZIO: Is this why he was killed?
VIERI: I'm sorry, were you hoping for a confession?
Pezzo di merda (Piece of shit)!
Vorrei solo che avessi sofferto di più (I only wish you'd suffered more)!
Hai avuto la fine che meritavi (You met the fate you deserved)!
Spero che bru– (I hope yo–)
MARIO: Enough, Ezio! Show some respect.
Respect? After all that's happened?
Do you think he would have shown either of us such kindness?
You are not Vieri. Do not become him.
Che la morte ti dia la pace che cercavi
(May death provide the peace you sought).
Requiescat in pace (Rest in peace).
Take this, read it when you have the time.
Our work here is finished.
Let us return to the villa.
MARIO: And here he is, our campione (champion) Ezio!
CROWD: All hail Ezio!
I see you've wasted no time starting the celebration.
And why not? You've done us a great service, nipote.
With Vieri dead, la Toscana (Tuscany) will grow quiet once more.
Do you know what that means?
Basta lavorare (No more work)!
Si passa tutto il giorno a bere (We can drink all day)!
E a puttane (And with whores)!
What? It's true!
CROWD: [laughs]
Come Ezio, walk with me.
Yes, uncle.
EZIO: The Pazzi answer to another, a Spaniard.
MARIO: He is Rodrigo Borgia.
MARIO: One of the most powerful men in all of Europe.
MARIO: And leader of the Templar Order.
EZIO: Which makes him responsible for the murder of my father and brothers.
MARIO: Yes, and he will kill you too, given the chance.
EZIO: Then I must stand against him if I wish to be free.
EZIO: But not until every other Templar has fallen to my blade.
EZIO: Father's list will guide me.
MARIO: Where will you go next?
EZIO: Firenze. Francesco de' Pazzi will share the fate of his son.
MARIO: A sensible next step.
MARIO: No doubt he intends evil for the city.
Alright, that's enough grim talk for one night.
I'll be in my study if you need me.
I shall read the letter my uncle gave me.
Look familiar?
Other Codex pages.
Yes, your father managed to find and translate a few before he…
Here.
This is not your father's work.
Someone else has translated it.
Leonardo da Vinci, a friend.
Do you see the way the words cross from one page to the next?
There is something underneath it all.
Some kind of map.
Where is it supposed to lead?
Your father and I managed to make out
bits of a prophecy scrawled across these pages.
It was written by an assassin like us, who long ago held a "Piece of Eden".
His name was Altaïr.
He spoke of something powerful and ancient, hidden beneath the land.
What is it?
What indeed?
Solving that little mystery is exactly why we collected these pages.
Then let me help.
It's time I take on my father's work.
All of it.
I'll start with the page I took from Vieri.
Leonardo will decode it for us.
Bene. Return here when time permits and we'll add it to the wall.
Salute, Claudia!
Our uncle is un mostro (a monster).
This is outrageous!
What's happened?
He's making me work.
If father was here, I'd never be stuck behind a desk like this.
And what are the terms of this supposed enslavement?
Since someone decided we're going to stay here.
Zio (Uncle) Mario suggested we try and find the money to repair the villa.
Problem is, there isn't any.
I bet I can bring in some money.
Oh, great, more work for me.
Well, belissimo (fine).
If you start paying for improvements to the town,
I'll keep track of them in this book.
And since I have nothing better to do,
I'll also make note of any objects you bring in from the outside.
If you actually get this place up and running,
travellers might visit and spend money.
Although I doubt anyone will want to come this far out of the city.
But if they do, I'll keep the money we make in this chest.
You're going to have to show up to take it to the bank yourself.
Because when it gets full, I'm just going to take the extra cash for myself.
Capito (Understand)?
Deal.
EZIO: Buongiorno. Is there something wrong?
ARCHITECT: Ser Mario hired me to deal with this mess.
ARCHITECT: But I'm an architetto (architect), not a miracle worker.
ARCHITECT: Without money I can't fix any of these buildings.
EZIO: And if someone brought you money?
ARCHITECT: Ehi, then we'd be in business.
ARCHITECT: You must be Ser Ezio, am I right?
EZIO: Uncle! I like this architetto!
MARIO: He gets very observant when he can smell money.
ARCHITECT: If you want to fix up this town, I'm going to need it.
ARCHITECT: I have a price list here for new shops and renovations.
ARCHITECT: Just bring me gold, make a choice, and I'll begin at once.
ARCHITECT: If I build you a shop, you, as the landlord,
can purchase goods there at lower rates.
ARCHITECT: If you investe more money in the shop,
you get an even greater discount.
ARCHITECT: As for renovations, well…
ARCHITECT: You'll be bringing the town and villa back to life.
ARCHITECT: As Ser Mario tells me that was
very important to your great-great-grandfather.
ARCHITECT: Plus, when you buy shops and renovations,
you'll be increasing the number of people who visit.
ARCHITECT: Causing your income to increase!
ARCHITECT: So let's take a look, shall we?
ARCHITECT: Buon viaggio (Safe journey)!
Ezio, my boy.
I think it's time I showed you something.
This is the Sanctuary.
It was built by my great grandfather to honour the memory
of the Assassin order and protect its secrets.
Look around.
These are the Assassins who guarded
the freedom of humanity when it was most threatened.
And this is the armour of Altaïr.
Little is known about Altaïr's life.
But his armour is light and very strong.
I'd give it to you, but I don't know how to retrieve it.
My great grandfather told me it would remain locked away
until all its protectors were made whole.
I heard rumours of crypts located throughout Italia.
Hidden tombs filled with treasure, where these six were moved centuries ago.
Maybe they have something to do with it.
In my younger days, I sought the six myself, with no success.
Perhaps you will have better luck.
REBECCA: In order to achieve
perfect synchronisation with Ezio, you have to get that armour.
Good to see you, Ezio. Care for a bit of practise?
TRAINER: Ha, such skill, such grace.
TRAINER: Well done, Ezio.
TRAINER: Let's see it another time.
TRAINER: Much better, one last time now.
TRAINER: Ha, such skill, such grace.
TRAINER: Yes, it's best we take a break.
Ezio! You're still alive.
Look at this place!
The past two years have been kind to you.
But you are not the same at all, are you?
I was hoping you might be able to help me with something.
Anything for you, my friend.
Ha ha! You found another one, how exciting!
This one is tricky to break.
Clever in its use of ancient languages.
Maybe if I just … oh! Ohhh.
It seems to be a manual of sorts.
For different assassination techniques.
May I see it?
Wait, What's that?
It's not so much a design this time, just a series of sketches.
Hmm, what to make of all this?
Ho ho, of course, and why not?
What an inspired idea.
Can you make it for me while I try what's in that manual fragment?
Take it, I'll have my assistant set up some dummies for you to practise with.
Ehi, Vincenzo!
I've done it! Come quickly, look!
Take it, try it.
Thank you, Leonardo.
Non c'è di che (Don't mention it).
There's someone I need to "see" while I'm here.
I can not approach him publicly.
Would you know a way?
La Volpe.
"The Fox"?
Sssh!
Capisco (I understand)…
But do you know where The Fox might roam?
Perhaps near the mercato (market) where the thieves dwell.
Sta attento, amico (Be safe, friend).
SUBJECT 16: Power doesn't die, it's passed on.
EZIO: What? My pouch, my money!
THIEF: Oh your money? I don't have your money! [laughs]
EZIO: Get back here!
THIEF: Make me!
EZIO: You're making a big mistake, my friend.
EZIO: Enough of this!
THIEF: Enough indeed, why don't you give up?
EZIO: Return what you've stolen!
THIEF: Would if I could, but I can't.
EZIO: I swear I'll run you through when I catch you!
THIEF: Now, where's the fun in that?
I really have no interest in hurting you.
So give me back my money and we'll call it even.
Not so fast.
What do you want? Who are you?
They called me many things.
Murderer. Tagliagole (Cutthroat). Thief.
But you may call me La Volpe.
At your service, Messer Ezio. [laughs]
How do you know my name?
It is my business to know everything in this city.
Isn't that why you're here?
Indeed, I need to find someone.
To know where he'll be before even he does.
Who?
Francesco de' Pazzi.
There's word on the street of a caravan just arrived from Roma.
A secret meeting at sunset tonight.
You can learn something of Francesco's whereabouts there.
Do you know where it is to be held?
Ma certo (Of course).
Let me know when you are ready and we'll go.
Ah, yes, [laughs] here is your money.
Follow me, but we must move fast.
Think you can keep up?
Nessun problema (No problem).
LA VOLPE: [laughs] What are you doing back there?
LA VOLPE: I said to keep up with me!
Here we are.
Francesco de' Pazzi is meeting his people inside that church.
EZIO: How do I join them?
There are catacombs that run under the city.
They will lead you to a place where you can eavesdrop on the meeting.
Grip that stone handle, turn it, then slide it down.
Thank you for all your help, Volpe.
Buona fortuna (Good luck).