Yeah.
Hey,
No.
Okay,
okay.
Yeah.
All right.
Yeah,
Yeah.
What?
Okay.
No.
How long do we have to stand here?
Survey area.
Its so called.
What do you want?
Ilario May said Patsy is paying us good money to watch the entrance, and the dead won't try to murder us.
I can't wait to go home to Ellen.
And how much gold we made?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Okay.
Yes,
but
right.
No,
thank you.
Okay.
What?
Yeah,
after the door.
Keep watch while I go.
Look,
it was supposed to be an easy job.
I told you we shouldn't have come here.
If I hear anything, I'm a running through the other guard post, so help me God.
Yeah,
I've seen him before,
sir.
Very.
Oh, I'll be back with the other guards
to find you're way off before it kills me.
Yes, yes.
I don't loathe.
Leave me alone.
Run faster.
Yeah.
No.
Wait.
He's not going to get me.
Thanks.
Leave me alone.
I'm being chased him.
No.
Okay.
Yeah.
You
get it.
Oh,
Dr.
Right.
Or like
no.
Yeah,
yeah.
Benedict, Your day in the portentous batteries That filly spirit to sank Shane, that super vos that money at
That's bad.
But now it's all here Sort staves, axes, armour bows Our men will want for nothing.
I take this gift to mean the pope consents.
He gave his blessing to the operation
as long as nobody skilled
We're all set for the warm or in the mornings and yawning.
Bate's been laid but it wasn't easy.
His full brother keeps changing his plans.
See, we need to be on hand to make sure Giuliana even gets out of bed for church tomorrow.
What is it?
Deductible?
Do you think they suspect something?
Impossible.
The Medici are two out again.
Too stupid to even notice.
Likely A bit of both.
Do not underestimate our enemies.
Francesco, Have you already forgotten how your son was murdered?
We'll suffer no such surprises this time.
Maestro, you have my word,
Multiple.
I should be off.
Have some other business to attend to before return to Rome.
Gentlemen, tomorrow a new sun rises over France.
May the father of understanding guide us
me.
Look at that statue.
It's identical to one in the villa out.
A Tory.
I think you've stumbled onto one of the assassins two's uncle mentioned.
Now that we know the way in, I'll tag the landmarks containing tombs in the database.
Yeah,
all right.
Oh,
what?
Yeah,
Okay.
Nowhere Francesco will be.
And when act.
What is it?
I overheard something.
They have weapons enough for a battalion.
Even the pope has given support typical of sisters.
But
what the hell are they planning?
I couldn't understand the specifics, but it involves the Medici, and it begins tomorrow morning at the drama.
The maid.
She will always be there for Sunday's service,
along with the rest of Fillon.
Say they're going to do it right in the middle of high Mass.
But it's also a chance for me to blend with the crowd, get close and stop this madness if they succeed, if we lose Lawrence.
Oh, and fear in, say, falls to the party will not come to that.
A promise.
I hope you are, right.
What?
No.
Oh,
yeah.
What?
Yeah.
Hey,
and I just see that
I must be working toe.
Well, please be careful.
What?
No.
Have you been?
Yeah.
Who?
You may be the big man wherever you come from, but here you're just a bit.
Sort the mail.
Amusing yourself in our first cities.
You're finished?
No.
But
you win today.
Yeah.
Um,
thank you.
Yeah.
What's wrong?
Uh,
the body.
Thank you.
Get up
the watch, do you?
Bizarre.
What's with him?
What?
But
go
straight back.
Oh,
run.
No.
Fine.
Yeah,
definitely.
I'm I've got to get out of here.
She's through.
This man is a brutal, cold hearted killer.
We must all work toward his apprehension.
What?
Not yet.
No,
yours.
Oh, my Christ.
Pomegranate and effective for Mama.
How rude you are
already,
gentlemen, is everything.
Everyone?
Everything.
They got a base of it.
What?
Yeah.
Okay.
Why go?
No.
Yes.
Lorenzo and his wife.
That's Juliana Angels.
Brother Francesco.
Stress.
Good.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Hey.
Yeah.
Good.
Oh, God.
Your entire family dies by my song.
Yeah,
I can't.
Right.
Yeah,
yeah.
No.
What?
Okay.
Yeah.
No.
Okay.
Oh,
all right.
No.
Yeah.
Oh, no.
You You saved my life.
It's nothing but the man who did He's still us to pay.
Not now.
I need help first.
To my home, people like to ask them.
Can you
save me
that?
Yeah.
I'm losing a lot of blood.
Hang on, Teo.
Moving as fast as I can.
Yeah,
I'm just
my wife.
My family from the city.
Wait.
Your energy will be delivering a course.
We're almost there.
Leave me alone!
Huh?
I'm more than capable of
No,
I hope that could be avoided.
I'm not
following,
huh?
I'm more than capable of I'm capable of.
So let's go.
What?
No, please don't kill me.
Oh, Soo,
I'm not.
Yeah, I'm capable of
I hope
more than capable.
Don't.
All right,
Doren.
Trust me.
Wounded a pretty Laporta.
What's the password?
Pulitzer opened the magnetic aboard the rice crate is coming quickly.
The city is at war.
Wait.
I am in your head.
It's me.
Why did you help me?
You are not the only one who lost a brother to the patsy.
My name is Ed Sewell Dettori, Huh?
Your job on the sun.
Your father was a good man.
He understood that on there.
Lawyers?
The party starts of storming the Palazzo Della Signoria way cannot hold them off much longer Now if they get inside their murder our supporters and put their own devils in power then my survival with me.
Nothing.
I have to
Francesco the Patsy!
Help save our seats!
The Audi Tony!
Kill him!
Me
seniority!
I saw Francesco Leader battalion around the back of the Palazzo Della Signoria.
I fear he may be seeking another way in Go before it's too late.
Do what you can.
No!
Oh,
yeah.
Wait.
With that, it's our ship.
No Arbour nor kindly thoughts for this hardened killer.
Yeah,
the citizens of Pisa.
I've had the most demonstration.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
One.
No.
Yeah.
Respect.
No,
thank you.
I'm making
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
just let me go
One!
Yeah.
Please just leave me alone.
Yeah, not days.
This is our just rewards in crusting our security to incompetent thoughts.
You again?
Why aren't you dead men slaughter him?
Yeah,
not you.
What?
Hey,
Yeah,
Boy digs himself a swordsman.
Will
you busy, Steve?
They're only delay your inevitable painful end.
What do you
servant to the dog, Lorenzo, That reward
I
Yeah.
Wait,
God,
no one's coming.
It's just us now.
Modern day job.
Deportee, stop being a long tunnel.
It's
No,
no,
no!
Yeah,
yeah!
Francesco!
Do Patsy brought up as a noble in a city captivated by the newly rich Medici family.
Francesca was taught to hate the middle class and its social climbers dismayed.
He watched as the Medici bank eclipsed his own and centuries of influence over the Florentine government slipped away.
It looks like the Spaniard offered him a solution.
Rather than compete in something as dirty as banking.
Francesco only had to do one thing for the Templars.
One thing to put the middle class in their place for good.
Kill the Medici Giovanni auditory.
Trying to stop Francesco by putting him in gaol.
But the Templars took care of that.
Now feeding say will judge you for what you've done.
It's over.
It's all over
in the U.
S.
And Philippine Sea in quest of it.
Yes, but there are several Naila Proxima
requiere.
Scott and Laci.
Yeah,
school.
Yeah!
God,
No.
Yeah.
When I was six years old, I fell into the army.
I soon found myself drifting down into darkness.
Certain my life was that name.
Instead, I woke to the sound of my mothers, weeping
at her sides to the stranger, soaking smiling at me.
My mother explained that he had saved me
and so began a long and prosperous relationship between two families.
Yours
on mine.
I am sorry.
I could not save your father and brothers.
You have knocked into apologise for
I believe yak about their party Played a part in their deaths.
Talk on you as well.
I need to find a coward Fled before we could arrest him.
If you any leads?
No.
They've hidden themselves Well.
Hey, Jacopo was not the only conspirator to escape.
If they work with Hackable, they will surely involved in the plot against my family as well.
Give me their names.
Antonio Maffei.
Archbishop Francesco.
Steph.
I know that
they're not gonna change.
I will go and see my uncle.
Yes, Men stationed in the countryside.
Wait before you go
called X page.
I took it from the files of Francesco Departs.
Seeing as he clearly no longer needs it.
I've always had an interest in things of any pity.
Did your flock It is meaningful to me as well.
Then consider it a gift
cave, Senor.
Did you?
Yeah.
What?
Two.
I've marched the Palazzo Medici on your mat in order to achieve 100%.
Sync with that CEO's life.
You should go explore.
You
stop.
Nice
you two.
Hey.
Yeah,
Go.
Yeah.
Stay back.
Thank you.
Oh,
no need to come forward.
That's better.
For now, prevention is the best cure.
I always say
it's you.
Thank God you're all right.
This madness with the Medici and the patsy is thiss Why you pursued Francesco?
Not exactly.
Well, whatever your reasons, the city safe again, thanks to you.
Now tell me, how may I be of service?
Ah, another page.
My?
Huh?
It's a similar Cypher to the last one.
This won't take long.
Interesting.
Yeah,
DD I see.
It's another blade design for delivering poison.
Can you build it?
See, it won't take very long.
I just need to find a way to hollow out the blade without sacrificing their
It's all right, Leonardo.
Just do what you need to do.
All done.
I feel your blade with a bit of poison to start with.
Should you run out?
Just visit a doctor Boyzone my doctor in high enough doses that which cures can kill.
I am in your debt once more, my friend.
Any time it's you.
Anytime.
Yeah,
Okay,
doesn't it?
No,
it's
Yeah.
Good.
No.
Okay.
Yes.
No,
no, No,
thank you.
No, no, no.
And they want to see the master.
Did this.
You
what
question
back?
Yeah.
Date of birth.
14.
49.
Profession.
Ruler of Florence simultaneously keeping the dream of the Florentine Republic alive while leaving the people with very little legitimate power.
Lorenzo de Medici definitely ruled Renaissance Florence.
During its golden age, Lorenzo's grandfather, Cosimo, built the Medici bank, creating one of the most powerful financial institutions in Europe and becoming fabulously rich in the process.
Considered the smartest of Kasim owes grandchildren.
Lorenzo was already being sent on diplomatic missions as a child.
Although his father was inept in sickly, his mother was a poet.
She introduced Lorenzo to many of the prominent artists of the day and stealing in him a love of art and culture.
In 14 69 when he was only 20 Lorenzo became the head of the Medici family, at which point he quickly gained control of the Florentine government through friends in the city, Council payoffs, strategic marriages and threats.
But Florence prospered with Lorenzo as its puppeteer.
A piece was made between the warring states of Italy and several masterpieces of Renaissance art by the likes of BOTTICELLI and Michelangelo were made under his care.
Ultimately, Lorenzo was happier writing poetry and shadow governing than directing his family's bank.
During his lifetime, several branches of the bank collapsed and the Medici assets were wasted on frivolities such as jousting tournaments.
Lorenzo died in 14 92.
Nearly broke, he was unable to prevent the popular backlash against his rich lifestyle and the mad monk Savonarola.
His rise to power.
Date of birth.
14 50 for profession, scholar, poet, somewhat of a prodigy.
Poland's Yano learned Latin and Greek at age 10 and by 18 had already become a published author.
Lorenzo de Medici hired him to act as the tutor for his Children and made sure he received a post at the studio Fiorentino.
Unfortunately, pullets Yano must not have been everyone's favourite instructor.
He died of arsenic poisoning in 14 94 probably murdered by Pierre of the Medici, his former student
Date of birth.
14 53.
Profession.
Noble, the playboy to his brother Lorenzo, statesman Giuliano de Medici was well known for his famous jousting tournaments, his handsome physique and his illegitimate child.
When Giuliano was killed in the pot, see conspiracy.
His son Giulio was considered legitimate due to a loophole in canon law that allowed marriages to occur privately between two people meeting that his parents could have agreed that they were actually married without telling anyone about it.
Watch out, Catholics.
Your mistresses have more power than you think.
Once legitimately a Medici, this child of a tradesman is daughter went on to become Pope Clement the seventh.
Get this Clement.
The seventh was Pope during the sack of Rome in 15 27 during which he was taken prisoner in the Costel Santangelo.
He escaped his captors disguised as a tradesman.
Son of a tradesman is daughter escapes poor pass to become pope on ly to become a tradesman once more.
Oh, the irony,
proclamations, local laws, news market days and advertisements were all called out by heralds.
Since many Renaissance Italians could not read, special laws had to be put in place to protect them from the crowd due to extreme displays of unhappiness following the announcement of tax increases.
Yeah.
Hey,
what?
Okay,