EZIO: Buon giorno.
ARCHITECT: Salute, Ser Ezio. Shall we take a look at the list?
ARCHITECT: Buon viaggio!
MARIO: Ezio! Ha, ha, come in, come in!
MARIO: To what do we owe the honour?
I have been sent from Firenze by El Magnifico
to attend to some unfinished business.
I'm looking for Jacopo de' Pazzi.
Ha! Who isn't?
We've been at it for days.
EZIO: Then perhaps what I carry will help up us both.
A list of his co-conspirators.
One of them will talk before he dies.
Excellent, these men are sure to lack Jacopo's resources.
Which means they will be easier to find.
I will put my scouts to it at once.
I appreciate the help, Uncle.
I've got something else for you as well, more Codex pages.
Ah, let's see what we can learn.
What is this?
What "prophet"?
EZIO: What did you find, Uncle?
Just another damn mystery.
The text here roughly translates to "Only the prophet may open it."
There's reference to two pieces of Eden.
But these pages offer no answers, nipote.
At least not on their own, you must find more.
We'll have to save it for another day, uncle.
I have a mission to attend to.
As you wish.
Now, if you hope to defeat these bastardi, I will need to teach you a few things.
Meet me on the practice field.
MARIO: Alright Ezio, you're familiar with counterattacking.
MARIO: But what happens when your enemy is as well?
EZIO: I don't usually give them the opportunity.
MARIO: Tough talk offers little protection against Templar steel.
EZIO: Then by all means maestro, teach me what to do.
MARIO: Now, dodge!
Magnifico (magnificent)!
Once again, you exceed my expectations.
Signore, we've found Jacopo's men, and await your word to strike!
MARIO: Relay the following.
MARIO: No man moves until they have spoken with Ezio, intesi (understand)?
MERCENARY: It will be done.
MARIO: Go Ezio, visit with my mercenaries in the countryside.
MARIO: See if Jacopo's lackeys won't lead you to him.
MARIO: But be careful, they will be expecting you.
Ezio, about time you got here, we've found Bernardo Baroncelli.
EZIO: Ottima notizia (This is good news)!
EZIO: Tell me where he is and I'll see that he's dealt with.
MERCENARY: That's the trouble, Lorenzo actually had him arrested days ago.
MERCENARY: After being returned to us from Constantinople, but he escaped.
MERCENARY: We believe him to be somewhere inside San Gimignano.
EZIO: Va bene, I'll see if I can't pin him down.
MERCENARY: How do you expect to succeed where the rest of us have failed?
EZIO: I have my ways.
BERNARDO: I just need to take things one day at a time.
BERNARDO: He'll get bored, and lost, confused, distracted, killed.
BERNARDO: It'll be okay.
BERNARDO: And if he does come, if it happens, I'll keep moving.
BERNARDO: Never in one place for long.
BERNARDO: Only … only how to sleep, when to sleep, where to sleep?
BERNARDO: The guard tower, perhaps?
BERNARDO: They'll think me mad, they don't know.
BERNARDO: I'll pay them, yes, then what will it matter?
BERNARDO: All they care about is coin.
BERNARDO: All anyone cares about is coin.
BERNARDO: Good for the brotherhood, good for me.
BERNARDO: Safer this way, yes.
BERNARDO: Yes, I'll ask and then…
BERNARDO: I will be protected.
BERNARDO: We'll meet when it's time and I'll leave this place.
BERNARDO: Free, in time, in time.
BERNARDO: Wait! What is that?
BERNARDO: I saw something!
BERNARDO: Another mercenario come to spy on me!
BERNARDO: No, no, just my nerves.
BERNARDO: Hard to stay calm, knowing that he seeks me.
BERNARDO: I must stay focused and soon this will be done, soon.
BERNARDO: I knew you would come.
EZIO: Where is Jacopo?
BERNARDO: So you can do to him what you've done to me?
EZIO: There is still time for you to clear your conscience.
BERNARDO: We gather at the church when a meeting is called.
EZIO: Mi duole dover giungere a tanto (I am sorry that it came to this).
EZIO: Requiescat in pace.
SUBJECT 16: It's getting easier and easier to hack into Abstergo's mainframe.
SUBJECT 16: It's like I know what data I'm looking for, I've already lived it.
SUBJECT 16: Do you see what's going on?
SUBJECT 16: Not yet, but you will.
Salute Ezio, Antonio Maffei has sought refuge atop the city's tallest structure.
Spouting scripture and arrows in equal measure.
The man has clearly lost his mind.
Making matters worse, he's posted archers all around him.
You would do well to clear them out before approaching.
EZIO: Grazie for the information.
SUBJECT 16: They were mostly heroes.
SUBJECT 16: See how the lineages disrupted it?
SUBJECT 16: The web of history traps the good.
SUBJECT 16: And the evil take what is not theirs!
SUBJECT 16: Behold! The mark of Cain.
ANTONIO: Citizens of San Gimignano, heed well my words!
ANTONIO: You must repent! Repent, and seek forgiveness!
ANTONIO: For your wicked ways have incurred the wrath of a demon!
ANTONIO: Summoned by your sins,
he now walks our world cloaked in shadow and darkness!
ANTONIO: And everywhere he treads death follows.
ANTONIO: Why you ask? Because you have strayed,
and sacrified your liberty to that wretch Lorenzo de' Medici!
ANTONIO: You are puppets, enslaved by purse strings!
ANTONIO: Won over by poisonous words!
ANTONIO: You have lost your virtue, you have lost your dignity!
ANTONIO: You have lost your faith, and this draws the demons in to feast!
ANTONIO: And feed they will, all whilst you wander lost in ignorance.
ANTONIO: Know that good men have died protecting you from his evil.
ANTONIO: Men who sought to save these lands, to purify them!
ANTONIO: Join me in prayer, my children.
ANTONIO: So that together we might stand against this darkness.
ANTONIO: Give ear O Heaven, and I will speak.
ANTONIO: And hear O Earth, the words of my mouth.
ANTONIO: Let my teaching drop as the rain, my speech distill as the dew.
ANTONIO: As raindrops on the tender herb and as showers on the grass.
ANTONIO: For I proclaim the name of the Lord, ascribe greatness to our God.
ANTONIO: He is the rock, His work is perfect.
ANTONIO: For all His ways are justice.
ANTONIO: A God of truth and without injustice.
ANTONIO: Righteous and upright is He.
ANTONIO: They have corrupted themselves.
ANTONIO: They are not His children because of their blemish.
ANTONIO: A perverse and crooked generation.
ANTONIO: Do you thus deal with the Lord, O foolish and unwise people?
ANTONIO: Is He not your father, who bought you?
ANTONIO: Has He not made you and established you?
ANTONIO: By the light of the Lord be cleansed!
EZIO: No grazie.
ANTONIO: I will put you on your knees, sinner.
EZIO: You would enjoy that, wouldn't you?
ANTONIO: Beg forgiveness!
EZIO: I have no need to.
ANTONIO: Give me strength, O Lord, that I might cast out this demon.
ANTONIO: It is not too late for you to turn away from evil!
ANTONIO: Repent, sinner, and you may yet be forgiven.
ANTONIO: I do God's work and it is good.
ANTONIO: Away with you, demon.
EZIO: Have some respect for death, my friend.
ANTONIO: I'll show you respect!
EZIO: No, I will.
EZIO: Che tu possa alfine trovare riposo nel corpo e nella mente
(May your body and mind at last be still).
EZIO: Requiescat in pace.
Ah, there you are. Listen, we've found Stefano da Bagnone.