Ah, there you are. Listen, we've found Stefano da Bagnone.
Just follow this road, and it'll bring you
to the abbey where he's taken refuge.
Wait, before you go take these.
You can use them to create a distraction.
EZIO: My thanks, friend.
MONK: Let us pray, brother.
STEFANO: Pray? Pray for what?
MONK: The Lord's protection.
STEFANO: If you think the Lord has any interest in our affairs,
you've another think coming.
STEFANO: But please, by all means,
continue to delude yourself if it helps to pass the time.
MONK: You speak blasphemy!
STEFANO: No, I speak truth.
MONK: But to deny His most exalted existence—
STEFANO: …is the only rational response when faced with the
declaration that there exists some invisible madman in the sky.
STEFANO: And believe me, if your precious Bible is anything
to go by, he's completely lost his mind.
MONK: How can you speak of such, you wear His vestments!
STEFANO: Only because they afforded me
the opportunity to get close to the Medici.
STEFANO: But you're right, I should look into replacing them
after the assassin is dealt with.
MONK: Oh! That unholy demon!
STEFANO: At least on this, we agree.
MONK: They say the devil has gifted him
with unnatural speed and strength.
STEFANO: The devil? No.
These are gifts he gave himself through training.
STEFANO: It is disturbing how unwilling
you are to credit people for their circumstances.
STEFANO: I think you'd make victims
out of the entire world if you could.
MONK: I forgive your lack of faith and forked tongue.
MONK: You are still one of His children.
STEFANO:  I told you… oh, what's the use?
STEFANO: Enough of this, it is like speaking to the wind.
MONK: I will pray for you.
STEFANO: As you wish, but do so quietly, I must keep watch.
STEFANO: Now I will see who was right.
EZIO: Where is Jacopo?
STEFANO: Nothing to fear, I suppose.
STEFANO: They meet in the shadow of the Roman gods.
EZIO: Ora sei libero dalla paura (Be free of your fear now).
EZIO: Requiescat in pace.
MERCENARY: Over here, Ezio.
We've found Archbishop Salviati.
He's barricaded himself inside that villa.
Take some of my men, use them to clear the fields.
Then find a way over the wall so you can open the gates.
EZIO: Ah, command over my own army.
EZIO: A nice change of pace
from the usual sneaking and stabbing.
EZIO: I like it.
SALVIATI: I see you there Assassin!
SALVIATI: These walls have stood for a hundred years,
and will stand for a hundred more.
SALVIATI: Stop wasting the lives of your men!
SALVIATI: Vattene (Get out)! Vattene via (Go away)!
SALVIATI: All that awaits you here is death, turn back!
SALVIATI: Men, prepare yourselves. The Assassin has arrived!
EZIO: I need to find a way to open the gates.
SALVIATI: I warned you to stay away, Assassin!
You should have listened.
SALVIATI: You're finished, Assassin. You hear me?
EZIO: You Templars, always singing the same song.
SALVIATI: You think a few mercenari will scare me? Ha!
EZIO: They should.
SALVIATI: Shall I send your remains
to that ubriacone (drunkard), Mario?
SALVIATI: Ha ha, what's the point?
There won't be anything left of you to recognise.
EZIO: It's quite a plan you have,
spouting nonsense while you send these other men to die.
SALVIATI: I am a reasonable man, what say you to this?
SALVIATI: Turn back now and I'll call off my men.
EZIO: Sorry, friend. You are on my list. Your fate is sealed.
SALVIATI: Tear him limb from limb, let us paint the—
EZIO: That is no way to treat a guest.
EZIO: Where is Jacopo?
SALVIATI: He knows you come for him.
SALVIATI: Emerging only in darkness to meet with the others.
EZIO: That answers when.
EZIO: La fede dovrebbe dare conforto, non pena.
(Faith should bring comfort, not pain.)
EZIO: Requiescat in pace.
If I can stay my blade long enough to follow him,
he'll lead me to his Templar brothers.
EZIO: I'll have more names for my list.
EZIO: What's going on here? Are they late?
They haven't seen me, this much I know.
EZIO: What are you and the others planning, Jacopo?
EZIO: Your letter mentioned Venezia.
Are there Templars there as well?
EZIO: How many men are responsible for my father's death?
JACOPO: I'm sorry maestro.
I did all I could but the Assassin proved too strong.
Clearly, else the others would be here with you.
To say nothing of the fact that Firenze remains in Medici hands.
It's Francesco's fault, his impatience made him reckless.
I–I tried to be the voice of reason.
More like the voice of cowardice.
You're one to talk, Signor Barbarigo.
Had you sent us quality weapons instead of
this garbage you Venetians call armament—
ENOUGH!
We put our faith in your family,
and you repay us with inaction and incompetence?!
Then when asked to account for your failures,
you make excuses and insult us?!
How do you expect me to respond?
I don't know.
It's alright, I do.
JACOPO: Aaah, no!
Please, d–d–don't!
Ha ha ha! Please don't what?
I can … fix this.
Spare me!
No!
What a mess.
So sorry to have claimed your prize, Assassin!
Did you honestly think I wouldn't expect you to follow?
That I didn't plan for it?
We've been at this a lot longer than you.
Kill him.
I know you're only doing as you're told,
so if you release me I will spare your lives.
Ha! Listen to this—
EZIO: Vai, amico, libero da fardelli e paure
(Go on, friend, unburdened and unafraid).
EZIO: Requiescat in pace.
The Pazzi are dead, every one of them.
I must admit, I've never before believed
I could desire the death of others so badly.
Nor I.
Ezio.
Thank you for the role you've played
in keeping this dream of mine alive a little longer.
L'onore è mio (The honour is mine), Signore.
What will you do now, figliolo (my boy)?
There are still others I must hunt, Signore.
They're already digging their claws into the heart of Venezia.
No! La Bella Venezia (beautiful Venice)…
Then that is where your journey must take you, Ezio.
Before you leave us, I have something for you. A gift.
This cape identifies you as a friend of the Medici.
As long as you wear it,
the city guards will be more tolerant of your actions.
But be warned, it will not grant you immunity from the law.
Che la fortuna favorisca la tua lama
(May fortune favour your blade).
Leonardo. Leonardo!
Mi dispiace, Messere (I am sorry, sir), but he is gone.
Maestro Leonardo was commissioned
by a Venetian noble to paint some portraits.
He paid for the maestro
to move his entire workshop to Venezia.
It's quite an opportunity.
Grazie mile (Thanks a lot), friend.
EZIO: Buon giorno.
ARCHITECT: Salute, Ser Ezio. Shall we take a look at the list?
ARCHITECT: Buon viaggio!
Leonardo!
Ezio? What luck! I er … have run into a bit of trouble.
EZIO: Let me see if I can help.
LEONARDO: I know how to fix it, but lack the means to do so.
LEONARDO: If you could just lift the wagon…
What is this thing?
LEONARDO: Eh?
It looks like a giant bat.
Oh nothing, just an idea I've been working on.
I could not leave it behind.
What is it for?
Well, I shouldn't really talk about it.
Ehi, al diavolo (the hell with it), I can't hold it in anymore!
Ezio, I think I figured out how to make a man fly!
[laughs] Come on, I'll drive.
LEONARDO: But I haven't even told you where I'm going?
Venezia, such a beautiful city, so many sources of inspiration.
Ponte de Rialto, Piazzo San Marco, L'Arsenale–
EZIO: Ssh!
LEONARDO: What's wrong?
We're not alone.
What's happening? Who are they?
Rodrigo Borgia's men.
Why, what do they want with us?
I think they want us dead.
Leonardo, hide!
EZIO: Hold on tight, it's going to be a little rough!
LEONARDO: Hold on, Ezio! We're almost there!
Go, Leonardo! They're here for me, not you.
I'll catch up with you later.