LEONARDO: Ezio! Here, over here!
Thank you, Ezio. You saved my life.
EZIO: I did what had to be done, you would have done the same.
I doubt it, bravery is not my strong suit.
I owe you a debt, brother.
EZIO: Di niente (It's nothing).
CAPTAIN: Tutti a bordo! Fra poco si salpa!
(All aboard! We're leaving soon!)
That's our traghetto (ferry), Venezia awaits.
CAPTAIN: Where's your pass?
EZIO: What pass?
LEONARDO: You don't have a pass?
CAPTAIN: You cannot enter Venezia without a pass.
CAPTAIN: Who invited you?
EZIO: Uh, nobody.
CAPTAIN: Basta (Stop)! No pass, no entrance.
EZIO: Don't worry Leonardo, I will come up with something.
WOMAN: Don't just stand there, I need help!
WOMAN: Aiuto! Qualcuno mi faccia scendere da quest' affare! Aiutatemi!
(Help! Someone get me off this thing! Help me!)
WOMAN: Dio del Cielo! Aiutatemi! (For Christ's sake! Help me!)
WOMAN: Aiuto! Qualcuno mi faccia scendere da quest' affare! Aiutatemi!
(Help! Someone get me off this thing! Help me!)
Madonna.
Oh, you are good, the ladies must like you.
EZIO: I wasn't looking to impress, only to help someone in distress.
WOMAN: Which is exactly why you impress.
WOMAN: And you are Messer…?
Auditore. But please, call me Ezio.
I'm Caterina.
CATERINA: Now, Ezio, we must find you suitable reward.
CATERINA: Do you have any suggestions?
EZIO: There is perhaps something you could help me with.
CATERINA: I'm all ears.
Yes Signora, whatever you say, Signora.
He won't trouble you any more.
I … took care of it.
Thank you, Caterina.
CATERINA: Perhaps we'll see each other again.
Should you ever find yourself in the city of Forlì,
it would be my … pleasure to welcome you.
I look forward to enjoying your hospitality.
CAPTAIN: Please accept my most humble apologies, Messere.
CAPTAIN: Had I known…
EZIO: It's quite alright, my friend.
LEONARDO: Be careful, Ezio. Do you know who that was?
EZIO: My next conquest.
LEONARDO: I don't think so, Ezio.
LEONARDO: That's Caterina Sforza,
daughter of the Duca di Milano. Her husband is—
EZIO: Husband?
LEONARDO: Si!
Her husband is the lord of Forlì.
That woman is as powerful and dangerous as she is young and beautiful.
EZIO: Sembra come una donna per me
(Sounds like my kind of lady).
DESMOND: Everything alright?
LUCY: Better than alright. You're making amazing progress.
SHAUN: "Amazing" is quite a strong word.
DESMOND: Then why are we stopping?
REBECCA: Prolonged exposure to the Animus can have … uh … side effects.
DESMOND: Huh, awesome!
LUCY: It's nothing to worry about.
You haven't shown any of the symptoms.
Symptoms? What symptoms?
REBECCA: Degradation of cognition, temporal hallucinations,
multiple awareness issues, overlapping realities, you know.
DESMOND: So what you're saying is…?
SHAUN: What we're saying, Desmond, is if you're not careful,
you may not need the animus to visit with your ancestors.
SHAUN: Which wouldn't be a bad thing, assuming you could control it.
SHAUN: Up until now, though, no-one has.
DESMOND: Subject 16.
LUCY: We have safeguards, Desmond.
LUCY: And they kept him in the Animus for way too long,
sometimes days at a time.
LUCY: We're being careful with you.
DESMOND: I hope so.
LUCY: Anyway, I was hoping we could test out your skill retention.
LUCY: See if you've picked up some of Ezio's abilities.
DESMOND: I'm game.
LUCY: Great. Meet me downstairs when you're ready.
DESMOND: What are you up to?
What am I—who are you, my mum?
I've been running traces on the Codex pages,
looking to see if any of them are still around.
And?
SHAUN: Nothing concrete.
Reports of one in the archives of the National Central Library in Florence.
SHAUN: Maybe a few in the hands of collectors, probably Templars.
I'd send someone to check it out, but we're very short on manpower.
How do you think the Codex wound up in Italy?
I mean, it seems so random.
Dante Alighieri by way of Marco Polo.
Seriously?
Something happened in 1321, yeah?
Now, I'm still working on making the connections, but from what I can tell,
Polo encountered the assassins while visiting Kublai Khan.
That's right, this must be when he obtained the Codex.
Now, when he returned to Italy, he passed it on to Dante.
Dante was close to him, if not an Assassin himself.
Now, I have no idea what brought the two of them together.
But I'll tell you what, I reckon we could find out.
DESMOND: I don't think Lucy wants us messing with the Animus.
Yeah, you're right, we've got enough to deal with.
I guess satisfying my curiosity will have to wait.
What could 16 have found that needs so much secrecy and security?
Oh , I don't know, do I?
Lucy thinks it's something about the Codex, but I'm not so sure.
I'm all ears if it's as life changing as 16 says.
Blimey, if I was allowed to use the Animus, I'd be the one in there finding out!
Instead, as usual, I'm forced to sit here on the sidelines.
DESMOND: How'd you get mixed up in all this?
Most Assassins, Desmond, are like you, yeah?
SHAUN: They're born into the Brotherhood.
Not me, though.
REBECCA: Ugh, here we go.
SHAUN: What?! He asked!
SHAUN: Anyway, I've always been a big fan of the unexplained.
SHAUN: There's something exciting there, you know?
A sense that life is more interesting, more mysterious
than we've been raised to believe.
DESMOND: So what, you just stumbled across the Assassins?
No, I found the Templars first, actually.
Abstergo is a big company.
It's too big, which means there were slipups.
You know, like that mess having right now with the flouride.
Only I was tracking this stuff years ago.
I must have been, what, 14? 15?
You knew Abstergo was a Templar company?
SHAUN: No, not at first.
I just knew they were up to no good,
and I figured maybe I could do something about it.
So I started digging up everything I could on the company.
Posting stuff to newsgroups, trying to spread the word,
looking for people who might have stories to tell.
You must have gotten Abstergo's attention.
Well, fortunately, I got Rebecca's first.
SHAUN: Otherwise, I'd probably be the bottom of a river.
REBECCA: You're welcome.
SHAUN: Yep, she tried to warn me.
SHAUN: Told me I was messing with the wrong kind of people.
REBECCA: And what did you do?
I thought you were mental.
REBECCA: But now you know better.
Yep, now I know you're just a bit mental.
Long story short, I saved his ass multiple times.
REBECCA: Should have dropped him and let Abstergo have their way.
Listen to you trying to be all badass.
So what happened?
I have a gift, Desmond.
I have a gift for seeing things, making connections.
Like your eagle vision, you know, only useful.
REBECCA: We offered him a place with us.
SHAUN: Yes you did, yeah. The alternative?
A life on the run from the most powerful organisation on the planet.
I decided to prolong my life, I'm eccentric like that.
So I signed up.
I've been doing research and analysis for them ever since.
Best part is: I love it.
SHAUN: I'm keeping tabs on the other teams.
DESMOND: Other teams?
SHAUN: The Templars have been hunting down the pieces of Eden
using the map they got from you at Abstergo.
SHAUN: Luckily, Lucy has provided us with a copy as well,
allowing us to pursue them.
DESMOND: And how's that working out?
SHAUN: So far, so good.
DESMOND: If they find even one of those pieces we're gonna have problems.
SHAUN: Oh, you're picking up on that, are you?
SHAUN: That is why we're training you.
SHAUN: Once you've acquired the necessary skills,
we'll be able to send you into the field.
DESMOND: And what about you? Why aren't you out there?
SHAUN: I'm not out there 'cause my expertise lies in other areas.
SHAUN: And to be honest, I prefer it that way.
SHAUN: But make no mistake, Desmond, I'm an assassin through and through.
SHAUN: I've killed before.
SHAUN: I expect to kill again.
SHAUN: It's just that I prefer not to.
Hey, Nice work today, you're a natural.
Thanks! It's definitely getting easier.
I got to say, after all the crap I went through at Abstergo,
it's nice to be with the good guys.
SHAUN: "Good guys"? Let's not get carried away.
What's that supposed to mean?
In case you've forgotten Rebecca, we're Assassins.
I could look it up for you, if you like.
Basically, it means we assassinate people.
Only when we have to.
SHAUN: It's a choice — you're choosing to kill.
I haven't killed anyone.
No, not yet, but what do you think all this is for, eh?
You think Lucy is giving you Ezio's abilities so you can
build schools in South America and deliver rice to starving Indonesians?
What are you, Desmond, a vegan?
You'd be the first vegan Assassin in history.
Look, it's not ideal, and taking a life is never easy.
But sometimes there's no other way.
REBECCA: Sometimes, Desmond, people have to die for things to change.
SHAUN: She's got a point, but don't fool yourself into thinking you have no say.
I mean, isn't that what we're all about here? Safeguarding free will?
REBECCA: Sorry, I didn't mean to make it into a whole big thing.
Ah, it's cool. So how is she treating you?
The translation software is still a bit laggy.
You're probably catching the odd bit of Italian, sorry about that.
No worries, Abstergo's machine wasn't perfect either.
So what's the plan?
We're going to see what you've managed to retain.
Come on!
LUCY: Abstergo's out there looking for us.
They're better funded and better equipped,
so it's only a matter of time before they find this place.
We need to be ready for them when they do.
LUCY: I want you to activate the warehouse's defence system.
LUCY: I'll let you figure out how to reach the sensors.
DESMOND: Oh, come on, not even a hint?
LUCY: Open your eyes, Desmond.
DESMOND: Uh, Lucy, I'm seeing things.
LUCY: Do the hallucinations last longer than 30 seconds?
DESMOND: No.
LUCY: Then it's nothing to be worried about, it'll pass.
DESMOND: So, how am I doing?
LUCY: You've picked up every single one of Ezio's skills.
LUCY: The adoption rate is fantastic.
LUCY: Another day or two and we'll be done.
DESMOND: Alright, you gotta tell me. Why Ezio, why Italy?
DESMOND: I mean, we could have just gone back to Altaïr again,
followed him during his early years.
LUCY: It started with 16.
DESMOND: Ah, good old Subject 16.
DESMOND: He repainted my room, you know. With his blood!
LUCY: I've been going through his files.
LUCY: Vidic flagged a couple of his Animus sessions.
LUCY: A bunch of different ancestors, different dates and locations…
LUCY: Ancient Africa, the Middle East…
LUCY: But towards the end, he became obsessed with Italy.
LUCY: I think he knew about the vault.
LUCY: A few of the records of his later Animus sessions are missing.
LUCY: And the sessions that are there…
LUCY: After everything the Templars put him through…
LUCY: After everything I put him through, it's all scrambled.
LUCY: If we hadn't pushed 16 so hard, we'd have the answers already.
LUCY: And maybe he'd still be alive.
DESMOND: So you're after the Codex and the vault.
LUCY: I knew you had an ancestor in Italy who was at the centre of all of this.
LUCY: Alright, I think we're done for the day.
You should get some rest.
Lucy, what happened to 16 wasn't your fault.
You were just as much a prisoner as I was.
Thanks.
Good night, Desmond.
I'm glad you're here.
DESMOND: What the hell?
What is this?
Where am I?
It's Acre.
Altaïr.
How the hell?
I'm not even in the Animus.
I must have passed out.
Just having some kind of weird dream.
Going without sleep for who knows how long.
Guess I shouldn't be surprised.
Hmm, that must be his target.
It's the woman from Acre.
What was her name?
Maria, yeah.
I wonder what he wants with her?
Whoa, alright, wasn't expecting that.
Wait a second, why aren't I following Altaïr?
I'm stuck here with Maria?
Oh, shit.
That must mean…
This is one weird dream.
REBECCA: Sorry to barge in on you like this, but it's getting late, and we were—
REBECCA: Hey, you okay?
DESMOND: Uh, yeah, yeah, all good.
DESMOND: Weird dreams, that's all.
REBECCA: Alright, I'll let you get ready. See you in a few.
SHAUN: Ah! Good of you to join us.
DESMOND: Sorry, long night.
SHAUN: What a professional. What a professional approach.
REBECCA: Leave him alone.
Well, you'll forgive me if I want to get some actual work done.
Ooh, madness, isn't it?
LUCY: Sean! Please, that's enough.
SHAUN: Alright.
DESMOND: Hey.
LUCY: [clears throat] Uh, hi.
You okay?
LUCY: Yeah, I'm fine.
Everything's fine.
DESMOND: You sure?
We lost two more teams last night.
That's eight more of us, just…
…gone.
DESMOND: I'm sorry.
I don't know what to do anymore.
It just keeps getting worse and worse.
Hey, remember what you told me? You gotta have faith.
DESMOND: And look, here we are safe and sound.
LUCY: Ha ha ha! For how long?
LUCY: And when they find us? Then what?
DESMOND: When that happens, if that happens, we'll deal with it.
DESMOND: I'll keep you safe.
LUCY: Anyway, enough with my little breakdown.
I should get back to work.
And so should you.
ALVISE: Messer da Vinci?
Yes?
Buongiorno e ben arrivato! I'm Alvise.
Il Signor Dona has asked that I escort you to the workshop.
Are you ready?
ALVISE: Ah, Venezia!
ALVISE: What other place is as beauiful, as stable, as perfect?
ALVISE: Come, I will show you her wonders.
ALVISE: Our first stop, the Rialto bridge.
ALVISE: Behold the elegance with which she spans the Grand Canal.
ALVISE: A symbol of Venetian unity and pride.
ALVISE: Let us continue.
ALVISE: Here we are, San Giacomo di Rialto.
ALVISE: Oldest church in Venezia. Isn't she beautiful?
ALVISE: And her clock tower? Magnifico!
ALVISE: Come, come, there's more to see.
ALVISE: No other city can match the size of Venezia's markets.
ALVISE: Be it spices or silk from near and far.
ALVISE: There is…
GUARD: You were told to stay home!
MERCHANT: But the rent is paid, I have every right to sell here.
GUARD: Emilio disagrees!
MERCHANT: No! Stop, stop!
ALVISE: Let us continue the tour… elsewhere.
Look, isn't it amazing?
Would you mind buying it for me? I, er, I left my money with my bags.
EZIO: Hey! Mind your step coglione (jerk)!
ALVISE: And here we have the Palazzo della Seta, home to Emilio Barbarigo.
ALVISE: Normally, I'd suggest a closer look, but the way things are now…
EZIO: Why, what's happened?
ALVISE: He is attempting to unify the merchants beneath a single banner.
ALVISE: There has been resistance, some of it violent.
EZIO: What kind of resistance?
ALVISE: They say they're fighting for the people.
ALVISE: For freedom or some such nonsense.
ALVISE: Baggianate (Nonsense), if you ask me.
They destroyed my stand, I demand compensation.
GUARD: Here you are, then.
MERCHANT: The Doge will know about this!
MERCHANT: I'll report you to the council!
GUARD 2: Good luck with that, my friend.
MERCHANT: What are you doing?
GUARD 3: You're under arrest for disrupting commerce.
MERCHANT: What? You just invented that! There's no such law.
GUARD 3: There is now.
MERCHANT: No! Stop!
And now I present to you your workshop, Ser da Vinci!
ALVISE: We spared no expense in its design.
You will see it is perfect, as if you never left Firenze.
I wish you great success and hope you enjoy Venezia
as much as she enjoys having you.
So here we are. Exciting isn't it?
Care to come in?
EZIO: Maybe later, I need to visit the Palazzo della Seta,
try and gain an audience with Emilio.
As you wish, but should you find yourself with free time,
or another Codex page, don't hesitate to visit.
My door is always open.
EZIO: Grazie, my friend.
Di nulla (It's nothing).
REBECCA: I found this awesome place for you to explore and practise your skills.
REBECCA: Santa Maria dei Frari. I've marked it on your map.
EZIO: How best to get inside?
EZIO: Scale the wall and … oh, that's not good.
EZIO: I'll never make that jump, I need to find another way.
EZIO: Hey, I remember you.
WOMAN: I need your help.
We need to go!
EZIO: You'll never did apologise for knocking me over.
NOW!
EZIO: Va bene. Where to?
The water!
EZIO: That doesn't exactly narrow it down!
WOMAN: Alright you bastards, who wants to die first?
WOMAN: Goddamn archers!
WOMAN: Quickly, they're getting closer!
WOMAN: Come any closer and I'll cut you to pieces!
WOMAN: What are you doing? Hurry up!
Yeah.
WOMAN: Aah! Cristo! My leg!
EZIO: Can you walk?
WOMAN: What do you think?
EZIO: I never did catch your name.
WOMAN: Rosa.
EZIO: Onorato Rosa, I'm Ezio.
ROSA: I know.
EZIO: What do you mean "I know"?
ROSA: Non ora (Not now). Now is not the time for small talk. Are you blind?
ROSA: Ugo!
What's this?
EZIO: Rosa's been wounded.
UGO: Pass her here, we'll go the rest of the way in the boat.
Careful.
Go! I'll deal with the guards.
He's dead, idiota!
Say a prayer later.
UGO: Porco demonio (Goddamnit)!
ROSA: I need to see…
I need to see Antonio, aaaaaa!
EZIO: Be careful! Let me do it. Go and find Antonio.
ROSA: Ugo, do what he says!
UGO: Qua l'ultimo arrivato da gli ordini!
(I can't believe I'm taking orders from this guy!)
ROSA: So tired.
EZIO: Hey! Wake up!
EZIO: We need help!
UGO: Where's Antonio?
UGO: Make yourselves useful! Clear a space for her.
UGO: Put her down there.
Where are we?
Home. They've sent for help.
Thank you.
Rosa! What's happened?
Just get this out of me.
Soon, soon, let's have a look first.
Clean entry and exit through the thigh, that's good.
Get it out!
Rosa, we must take care not to—
NOW!
Come vuoi (As you wish).
Tenetela (Hold it)!
ANTONIO: I'm sorry, piccola (sweetheart).
Sorry?! Ficcatelo nel culo your "sorry"!
(Shove your "sorry" up your ass!)
ANTONIO: Go fetch Bianca, and be quick!
ANTONIO: Help me with this.
EZIO: How?
ANTONIO: Take a clean piece of linen.
When I remove my hand, press the cloth into her wound.
ANTONIO: Are you ready? Now!
ANTONIO: Ben fatto, you work well under pressure
ANTONIO: She's spirited, this one.
ROSA: Porca puttana (son of a bitch)!
ANTONIO: Avanti (Come on)!
Get Rosa inside so that Bianca can close the wound.
You'll be alright, the worst is past.
ROSA: Ti venisse il cancro, brutto bastardo!
(I hope you catch plague, you ugly bastard!)
ROSA: A te e quella grandissima troia di tua madre!
(You and your whore mother!)
ANTONIO: Rosa is most dear to me. If I had lost her…
EZIO: I've always had a soft spot for women in distress.
ANTONIO: So I've heard.
Don't look so surprised, we know all about you Ser Ezio.
ANTONIO: Your work in Florence and the rest of Tuscany.
Good work too, if a little … unrefined.
EZIO: Then you know why I'm in Venezia?
ANTONIO: I can guess.
When you have a minute, come see me in my office.
There's something we should discuss.
ANTONIO: Ezio, prego (welcome).
ANTONIO: Can I offer you something? Biscotti? Un caffè?
What's caffè?
An interesting concoction brought to me by a Turk merchant.
Here, have a taste.
A little bitter if you ask me.
Just seems lacking somehow.
I don't know, have you considered adding sugar maybe, or latte?
I suppose it's something of an acquired taste.
Enough about that. Now, where were we?
Our failure at the Palazzo cost us dearly.
It will take time to recover.
No doubt Emilio will use this pause to strengthen his defences.
And continue his oppression of the district.
You may not share our motive, but I know you share our goal.
Why not gather your forces and try again?
To act in haste would only bring more losses.
No, we must resupply and draw new plans.
I can ill afford to sit around and wait.
Nor would I want you to.
Work with us instead.
Already my men begin to mend today's wounds.
Seek them out, they'll put you to work.
The sooner you aid them, the sooner we can strike.
Molto bene, Messere (Very well, sir). I accept.
It is the right decision.