EZIO: You seem to be healing well.
How are you finding Venezia?
It has it's charms.
But how do you deal with the smell? Che schifo (How disgusting)!
So what brings you to me?
I was hoping you could help me with something.
ROSA: And that would be…?
EZIO: I want to learn to climb the way you do.
Oh. Va bene, I can do that.
Well, I can't, but Franco can.
ROSA: Franco! Muovi il culo (move your ass)!
ROSA: Show Ezio how to reach the top of that scaffolding.
Begin in a hanging position.
ROSA: Then jump to the ledge above you.
ROSA: As you reach it, grab it with your hand and pull yourself up.
There, see how it works?
I think so.
Only one way to find out, try for yourself.
ROSA: Jump, Ezio!
ROSA: Grab the ledge at the height of your jump.
So? How did I do?
I've seen better.
Ah, you wound me with your cruel, cruel words.
Alright smargiasso (show off), let's put your skills to the test.
EZIO: I'm all ears.
ROSA: Meet me in front of the Frari!
Ah, Ezio, I was hoping you might return.
I want your advice on something.
EZIO: Of course. Tell me what troubles you.
Emilio has turned some of my own men against me.
Bribery and blackmail, is it?
Yes. And we cannot strike until the traitors are dealt with.
They're still somewhere in this district.
Keeping tabs on us and reporting back to Emilio.
Not for much longer, they're not.
SUBJECT 16: Without the staff, the Czar was powerless.
SUBJECT 16: He could no longer control his subjects.
SUBJECT 16: Revolution! Revolution!
SUBJECT 16: Three thefts, hidden by the murders.
SUBJECT 16: People only see what they're trained to see…
SUBJECT 16: What the organisation wants them to see.
SUBJECT 16: The wolves are out hunting.
SUBJECT 16: Where oh where has Jack gone?
ROSA: Climbing a bit of scaffolding is all well and good,
but let's see how you do out in the open.
EZIO: The top of that tower then?
EZIO: Torno fra un attimo (I'll be right back).
EZIO: So?
Looks like you've learned all I have to teach you.
I'll let Antonio know of your progress.
Finish your other tasks, we're almost there.
EZIO: Ben trovato (Good to see you), Ugo. What's the trouble?
You and Rosa managed to escape from Seta, but the others were not so lucky.
Emilio's captured them, and now they await execution.
EZIO: Do you know where they're being held?
I know they're still in the district, but beyond that, no.
You'll have to look for them.
EZIO: I'll have your brothers back here in no time.
THIEF: The markets belong to the people! Emilio says he seeks unity—
GUARD: Where's your—
THIEVES: Aaah! Ow!
GUARD 1: Ha ha ha ha, listen to them squeal!
GUARD 2: It's no wonder their master hides.
GUARD 3: Where is Emilio? I'd like to be rid of this trash.
I'm impressed, I didn't expect you to succeed so quickly.
EZIO: I am to please.
I'll let Antonio know about our progress.
Come find me later, I've got another job for you.
EZIO: What sort of job?
Meet me near the docks, and I'll explain.
EZIO: Molto bene.
EZIO: Leonardo!
Ezio, so good to see you.
How can I help you?
Ha ha, you found another one! How exciting!
If you transpose this word, and move this line to the left…
It's deciphered!
Rescuing my brothers was more than just an act of charity, Ezio.
The men you freed will play a vital role in the weeks to come.