Rescuing my brothers was more than just an act of charity, Ezio.
The men you've freed will play a vital role in the weeks to come.
Just ask for their help and they'll join you.
EZIO: And once I have my little band of thieves?
Send them towards a group of guards and they'll create a distraction.
EZIO: Opening the way for me, saves me from having to bloody my sword.
Exactly!
Now I'll tell you what to do with them.
Antonio's plan calls for a bit of deception.
We're to imitate his archers, which means we'll need the armour that they wear.
A shipment of this stuff has just been loaded into chests
and now awaits delivery to Seta.
Loot the chests and retrieve the outfits.
When that's finished, I'll need you to
fetch me a boat as well and bring it back here.
We'll use it to move our men into the Palazzo undetected.
EZIO: Consider it done.
UGO: Molto bene, Ezio, this is exactly what we needed.
UGO: I'll let Antonio know you've finished the job.
ANTONIO: Please enter.
Your good work has restored us to our former strength, Ezio.
We are ready to strike.
Just tell me what needs to be done, and I'll see that it is.
You'll approach from above under the cover of night.
Emilio has posted archers around the Palazzo. Kill them, but do so quietly.
As they fall, my men shall replace them.
EZIO: What about the guards?
When you've finished with the archers,
we will regroup in front of this building here and discuss next steps.
EZIO: Nessun problema. I'll take care of the archers and return to you.
Then it's settled. In bocca al lupo (Into the wolf's mouth [good luck])!
Crepi il lupo (May the wolf die)!
Well done, Ezio. Everything is going according to plan.
ANTONIO: As we speak, my men are replacing the archers you've removed.
ANTONIO: The way to The Palazzo is clear now.
EZIO: But not the building itself, Emilio's guards still patrol its border.
Use my men, they can distract the guards.
And when it comes time to storm the place, remember what I've taught you.
Sii cauto (Take care), Ezio. We await word of your success.
CARLO: Your little house of cards is crumbling, Emilio.
EMILIO: A minor setback, it will be dealt with.
This povero scemo (poor fool) Antonio and his thieves—
CARLO: Never mind them, it's the Assassin you should be worried about.
EMILIO: Why, is–is he in Venezia?
CARLO: He's been here for weeks! How could you be so blind?
EMILIO: Unlike you, I've been busy.
EMILIO: Someone had to provide the weapons to our brothers in Firenze.
CARLO: Yes, and we all saw what good that did..
EMILIO: Enough with the barbs! What is it you want, Carlo?
CARLO: Maestro has called a meeting, three days from now at Santo Stefano.
EMILIO: Very well, I'll be there.
CARLO: Assuming you still live.
CARLO: If you want my advice, I'd find a less conspicuous place to wait.
Seta is a target now.
EMILIO: Seta is a fortress!
CARLO: If you say so. Goodbye, Emilio.
EMILIO: Cazzo (Fuck), what if he's right?
EMILIO: You! Call for my boat, it should be close.
EMILIO: When it arrives load those crates and prepare to sail.
I'll be right back.
EMILIO: If Carlo speaks true, I must find a place to hide,
just until the meeting.
EMILIO: Then we'll deal with the Assassin.
EMILIO: He must be working with Antonio.
EMILIO: That means the attacks…
EMILIO: No! I've worked too hard for this.
EMILIO: Don't they understand?
EMILIO: There's so much less crime, the people have better lives!
EMILIO: So some must leave, it is the price of progress.
EMILIO: Why must the Assassins always interfere, like Giovanni?
EMILIO: If he had just left well enough alone.
EMILIO: Guardia! Guardia!
SHAUN: Emilio Barbarigo. Titan of Venetian industry, terror of the underworld.
SHAUN: Aided by his powerful family,
he cornered the market through smart business practises,
SHAUN: …such as edging out the competition and lobbying the government.
SHAUN: He funded the Venetian police force almost single-handedly.
SHAUN: Keeping the streets safe from crime and his finances tax free.
SHAUN: Emilio claims to be a supporter of the Republic.
SHAUN: The problem is, once you own the police force,
voting becomes, well… inefficient.
SHAUN: As does, you know, opposition.
EZIO: Do not be afraid.
EMILIO: I feel no fear, Assassin, only regret.
EMILIO: I sought unity, stability, order.
EZIO: At too great a cost.
EMILIO: Progress demands sacrifice.
EZIO: Non trovo alcuna gioia in questo, ma non c'e altro modo
(I take no joy in this, but I see no other way).
EZIO: Requiescat in pace.
Sorry, they couldn't resist.
Seta is fallen and Emilio is no more.
All thanks to you, Ezio.
Go! Tear down Emilio's banners.
Return what he has stolen from the people.
Tell me, Ezio, how can I repay you for your service?
EZIO: Money's always nice.
ANTONIO: Easy enough.
ANTONIO: What else?
Emilio was meeting with a man named Carlo.
He looked to be a government official. Do you know him?
Carlo Grimaldi. He sits on the Council of Ten.
Why do you ask, what are you up to?
I have a meeting to attend.
SILVIO: Where is Emilio?
CARLO: I told him to be here.
You told him yourself? In person?
Yes, myself in person.
I'm concerned that you don't trust me.
As am I.
Perhaps he'll arrive with the others.
Walk with me.
SILVIO: So, how go things in the palace?
CARLO: Honestly, it's difficult.
CARLO: Mocenigo keeps his circle close.
CARLO: I've tried to lay the groundwork, making suggestions,
but he has other voices at his ears.
SILVIO: Then you must work hard, you must become part of his inner circle.
CARLO: Si, I understand, but it's harder than I expected.
SILVIO: And why is that, Carlo?
CARLO: I don't know! He just…
CARLO: The Doge doesn't like me.
SILVIO: I wonder why.
CARLO: It's not my fault! I keep trying to please him.
CARLO: I learn what he craves and I have it delivered.
CARLO: The finest jams from the orchards of Sardinia.
CARLO: The newest fashions from Milano.
SILVIO: Yes, and that's called being a sycophant.
CARLO: A what? What did you call me?!
SILVIO: A doormat. A flatterer. A bootlicker!
CARLO: Need I go on?
CARLO: Bastardo! You don't know what it's like.
CARLO: You don't understand the pressure in there.
SILVIO: Oh, I don't understand pressure?!
CARLO: No, you have no idea!
CARLO: You are a government official!
CARLO: I am two steps from the Doge himself!
CARLO: I am beside him day and night!
CARLO: You wish you could be where I am!
SILVIO: Are you done?
CARLO: Hardly! You listen to me now.
CARLO: I am close. The Doge can be recruited to our cause, I am sure of it!
CARLO: I just… I need a little more time.
SILVIO: Time is not a thing we have in great supply.
CARLO: My feet are killing me! Can we sit down inside somewhere?
SILVIO: Do you know anywhere truly safe to discuss things such as these?
MARCO: Buon giorno (Good day), cousin. Signor Carlo.
We thought Emilio would be with you.
MARCO: Emilio is dead.
What?! How?
The Assassin! The same one who hunted down the Pazzi. He's here, in Venezia.
MARCO:  È così (It is so). Silvio, did you not know?
CARLO: He could be anywhere.
He could be here right now and we might not even know.
He struck Emilio inside his own palazzo.
And so, what of our plans?
There is no longer time for subtlety, my brothers. We must act now.
But Marco, I'm so close. A few more days. If I can just—
No! It happens this week.
DANTE: We should keep moving.
SILVIO: What does the Spaniard have to say to this change of plan?
MARCO: You can ask him yourself soon enough.
CARLO: He's here? From Roma?
MARCO: So I've heard.
SILVIO: Good, then perhaps he's made a decision.
MARCO: About what, cousin?
SILVIO: About which of us shall step into the role of the Doge.
MARCO: I didn't know there was a decision to be made.
MARCO: Surely the choice is obvious to all.
SILVIO: Obvious indeed. It should be the one who organised the entire operation.
SILVIO: The one who came up with the idea of how to save this city.
MARCO: There is no lack of value in tactical intelligence, good Silvio.
MARCO: But it is wisdom one needs to rule, do not think otherwise.
CARLO: Calma, calma, amici (calm, calm, friends). There is no need for this.
CARLO: You know it's not up to either of you.
CARLO: For all we know, he may not even choose a Barbarigo.
MARCO, SILVIO: [laugh]
CARLO: Why not me? I'm the one who's done all the hard work!
MARCO: Basta (Enough)! We wait for his arrival.
CARLO: Are you sure he's coming?
MARCO: Yes!
DANTE: Signori, we should move a little faster. I feel eyes on us.
MARCO: Thank you, Dante. We will move at your pace.
SILVIO: This guard's a good find, cousin. How much did you pay for him?
MARCO: Perhaps not as much as he deserves.
MARCO: He's saved my life on two occasions.
MARCO: Though he's not much of a conversationalist.
Enough with your inane prattle!
The choice of Doge was never up to any of you.
And you were never given permission to make plans.
Forgive us, Maestro, we wish only to serve.
The plan is this.
Doge Mocenigo will die tonight.
And once the deed's been done Marco shall take his place.
Vi ringrazio umilmente, Maestro
(I humbly thank you, Master).
Good! Messer Grimaldi…
RODRIGO: You are closest to Mocenigo, your work the most vital.
Serve us well and it won't be forgotten.
RODRIGO: Walk with me.
RODRIGO: I don't want any blood spilled, you understand?
RODRIGO: It must appear to all that he goes quietly.
CARLO: Certo (Of course), Maestro.
RODRIGO: When are you closest to him?
CARLO: I have full run of the palace.
CARLO: He may not care to hear what I have to say,
but he trusts me by now as one of his own.
RODRIGO: Bravo. Then I want you to infiltrate the kitchen and poison his meal.
CARLO: So be it.
RODRIGO: Marco, can you furnish us with a suitable toxin on short notice?
MARCO: I defer to my cousin. That is really his area of expertise.
RODRIGO: Silvio?
SILVIO: I am at your service, Maestro.
RODRIGO: What can you bring to get this done?
SILVIO: I will confer with my associates in the streets.
SILVIO: But chances are good that I could procure some Cantarella.
RODRIGO: Yes, and what is that?
SILVIO: It is a most effective form of arsenic, yet difficult to trace.
RODRIGO: Ah, va bene, va bene, then it's decided.
MARCO: Forgive me, Maestro, but is this not perhaps a tad dangerous for you?
Involving yourself so intimately with the minutiae of our plans?
I feel the need to involve myself more directly.
The Pazzi disappointed us in Firenze.
I pray you will not do the same.
Do not worry this time. The Pazzi were a bunch of foolish—
Pazzis were a potent and venerable family,
reduced to rubble by one young Assassin.
Do not underestimate this troublesome foe who now haunts your city.
Or the same fate will befall the Barbarigo.
I want this done promptly.
Bene, I must return to Roma.
RODRIGO: Time is of the essence.
RODRIGO: Do not fail us.
Che idiota sono (What an idiot I am)! I should have kept my eyes on them.
I need to go and see Antonio if I have any hope of salvaging this mess I've made.
Salute, bello mio (Hello beautiful). Come stai (How are you)?
You back to see me, already?
Desolato, mia cara (Sorry, my dear), but I am not here to play.
I must speak with Antonio, it's urgent.
Antonio! Ezio's here!
Ezio, is everything alright?
Carlo Grimaldi and the Barbarigo
are in league with the one they call the Spaniard.
They're going to murder the Doge and replace him with one of their own.
They would have all of Venezia, her entire fleet in their grasp.
And they call me a criminal!
EZIO: Then you'll help me?
You have me on your side, brother, and the support of all my men.
And women.
Grazie, amici.
ANTONIO: But, Ezio, I must warn you.
It's not going to be so easy this time.
Palazzo Ducale is the most heavily guarded building in Venezia.
Nothing is impenetrable.
[laughs] This is why we like you, Ezio.
ANTONIO: Come, let's go take a look, we'll come up with a plan.
ANTONIO: This business with the Doge, terrible.
ANTONIO: Though treachery like this no longer surprises me.
ANTONIO: When I was a child, we were taught that the nobles were just and kind.
ANTONIO: I believed it.
ANTONIO: Though my father was only a cobbler, and my mother a scullery maid,
I aspired to be much more.
ANTONIO: I studied hard, I persevered, but the nobles would never have me.
ANTONIO: If you are not born one of them, acceptance is impossible.
ANTONIO: So I ask you, Ezio, who are the true nobles of Venezia?
ANTONIO: Men like Carlo Grimaldi and Marco Barbarigo? No!
ANTONIO: I say we are, the thieves and mercenari and whores.
ANTONIO: While we work to save this city and its people,
the nobles seek to make it their plaything.
ANTONIO: We need to scout the Palazzo carefully, see it from every angle.
ANTONIO: We just might find a way in.
ANTONIO: I know of a tall campanile behind the palazzo.
ANTONIO: Or we might find a way to climb the back of the basilica.
ANTONIO: Do you have any ideas?
EZIO: I assume the front door is out.
ANTONIO: [laughs] Va bene, we'll try the front door as well, saputello (wise ass).
EZIO: So, what do you think?
ANTONIO: We're not getting in this way.
ANTONIO: They'll have time to murder the Doge
before we're able to get through all these guards.
ANTONIO: Look at that, archers everywhere.
EZIO: And the walls are impossible to climb on this side.
ANTONIO: Bene, we're in luck.
ANTONIO: Looks like there's a perfect path
up the scaffolding to the roof of the basilica.
ANTONIO: Shall we?
ANTONIO: Ezio, look! Isn't that him? Grimaldi?
CARLO: Don't you understand what I'm offering you, Signore?
CARLO: Listen to me, please.
CARLO: Or this will be your last chance.
DOGE: How dare you?
CARLO: I'm sorry, mi dispiace (I'm sorry).
CARLO: I meant nothing by it, I'm only looking out for your safety.
ANTONIO: We're running out of time. There's no way through this fence,
and there are guards everywhere! Diavolo!
It's impossible.
There's no way in or out for men, only birds.
Yes, birds!
ANTONIO: Where are you going now?
EZIO: To see my friend Leonardo!
EZIO: I need your help, Leonardo.
EZIO: Does it work?
LEONARDO: What? What are you asking?